<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Iryna Kheroim &#8211; ThingsBoard&#039;s blog</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 09:59:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/cropped-favicon-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Iryna Kheroim &#8211; ThingsBoard&#039;s blog</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Solving solar power plant problems using advanced analytics</title>
		<link>./../../../solving-solar-power-plant-problems-using-advanced-analytics/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../solving-solar-power-plant-problems-using-advanced-analytics/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Iryna Kheroim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 16:59:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=3314</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Solar energy is becoming increasingly popular as the world looks to resolve the climate emergency and move toward&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Solar energy is becoming increasingly popular as the world looks to resolve the climate emergency and move toward a greener future. However, solar farms face several energy-generating challenges, including operating and maintenance costs, soiling, performance degradation over time, security and intrusion detection, optimizing energy output, and grid integration challenges.</p>



<p>To address these issues, they increasingly rely on advanced analytics to optimize their operations, monitor weather conditions, and raise maintenance processes. Here, we’ll explore the main challenges faced by solar panels, as well as options for solving them with the help of advanced analytics.</p>



<p>Threshold business analytics approaches cannot deal with the complexity of solar power plant data and the problems that arise. Predictive maintenance, forecasting, and anomaly detection will be the main tools for solving challenges. Solar farms adopting such smart analytics tools have already seen benefits like 12-15% gains in annual energy yield, 15-20% drops in cleaning and maintenance costs, and 30% reductions in power output volatility. By leveraging these tools, solar farms can significantly increase their overall efficiency, reduce downtime, and lower their overall cost of operation.</p>



<p>The article aims to educate readers on the problems and the solutions to aid faster industry adoption of analytics. Continued efforts in this direction can help solar power advance strongly towards its promise of a brighter, cleaner energy future.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="solar-farm-structure">Solar Farm Structure</h2>



<p>Solar farms consist of solar panels, wires, inverters, batteries, and a utility meter. Due to the design features, each of these areas must be in constantly changing conditions, which causes many problems that require a quick solution.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="585" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/1-8-1024x585.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3279" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/1-8-1024x585.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/1-8-300x171.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/1-8-768x439.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/1-8-1536x877.png 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/1-8-2048x1170.png 2048w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/1-8-512x292.png 512w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/1-8-920x526.png 920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/1-8-1600x914.png 1600w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/1-8-1920x1097.png 1920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/1-8-1320x754.png 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/1-8.png 2400w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>With the help of IoT technologies, we can take indicators that the analytics system can later store, process, and convert into previously unattainable parameters.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="understanding-the-difficulty-of-solving-challenges">Understanding the difficulty of solving challenges</h2>



<p>Before identifying the main challenges, it is important to understand their complexity and difficulty. We have identified 3 main causes for the decrease in overall efficiency:</p>



<p><strong>The first</strong>&nbsp;is the large number of important metrics that need to be collected for analysis. A solar farm consists of hundreds or even thousands of devices. Each of the devices has a bunch of different parameters that are important for monitoring efficiency. No matter how much we reduce and simplify the system, even a 5 MWh system will have over 10,000 panels. The panels are connected to many inverters and batteries. And they, in turn, are connected by many connections. Accordingly, the system contains a huge amount of data, which is important to operate within a pile.</p>



<p><strong>The second</strong>&nbsp;is the instability of parameters due to changing weather conditions and the sensitivity of solar panels to external factors. This makes it impossible to identify patterns and set simple thresholds. A 15% drop in energy production may be due to a passing cloud rather than a breakdown, soiling, or misconfiguration. With parameters constantly shifting, spotting true problems becomes near impossible for standard threshold-based monitoring tools.</p>



<p><strong>The third</strong>&nbsp;is the inability of humans to process large amounts of data in real-time to take action to improve the situation. But quick action is essential to maximize productivity. So, the system requires machine intervention when it comes to large arrays of constantly changing indicators.</p>



<p>However, a mature advanced analytics system contains built-in instruments that can help us solve the challenges described. Here are a few of them:</p>



<ul>
<li>Automated anomaly detection</li>



<li>Real-time decision engine</li>



<li>Identify hidden patterns and correlations</li>



<li>Predict the future behavior of the system</li>
</ul>



<p>So, advanced analytics can work with large amounts of data, find unusual patterns within it, and make the necessary decisions independently to achieve maximum efficiency.</p>



<p>Now that we understand the complexity of overcoming challenges and the tools that help solve them, we can proceed with a detailed overview of each challenge and possible solutions.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-main-challenges-in-solar-farms">The main challenges in solar farms</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="operational-and-maintenance-costs">Operational and Maintenance Costs</h3>



<p>One of the main challenges solar power plant owners face is the significant operation and maintenance costs associated with maintaining these facilities. The main reasons for high expenses are:</p>



<ul>
<li>Replacement or maintenance of faulty components</li>



<li>Panel cleaning</li>



<li>Equipment wear and tear</li>



<li>Labor costs</li>
</ul>



<p>Solar panels are sensitive to many environmental factors, such as temperature, humidity, dust in the air, and other environmental indicators that accumulate over time. Not only do they reduce energy production efficiency, but they also require frequent maintenance and cleaning, which increases overall operating costs.</p>



<p>Here are the most common issues with solar plants that accumulate over time: Delamination and Internal Corrosion, Electrical Issues, Hot Spots, PID Effect, Snail Trail Contamination, Overheating, Isolation Short-Circuit Fault, Inverter Does Not Restart, and MPPT.</p>



<p>If you want to learn more about this topic, see a full description of the problems and their solutions using anomaly detection, and check out the detailed step-by-step&nbsp;<a href="./../../../optimizing-solar-parks-efficiency-advanced-anomaly-detection-solutions/index.html">guide here</a>.</p>



<p>Expenses such as these can account for up to 15-20% of the total annual cost of solar generation. Traditional maintenance practices often follow a fixed schedule, leading to inefficiencies, unnecessary downtime, and excessive operating costs.</p>



<p>Solar plant managers can use predictive analytics to foresee potential problems before they become costly downtime. This proactive approach minimizes the need for reactive or scheduled maintenance, optimizing the efficiency of the solar plant.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="soiling">Soiling</h3>



<p>The accumulation of dust, dirt, grime, snow, sand deposits, and bird droppings on solar panels blocks incident sunlight to the cells and is a prime source of efficiency losses for solar farms.</p>



<p>Manual cleaning of soiled panels to restore generation is laborious and costly and only offers temporary respite against recurring soiling triggered by environmental or seasonal weather. The high frequency of cleaning needed for farms in specific locales also exponentially increases associated water usage and labor costs. Furthermore, traditional visual inspections for contamination suffer from inaccuracy due to limited manpower and subjective assessments that tend to underestimate early contamination.</p>



<p>Research shows soiling alone can lead to a staggering 7-30% decline in power generation for farms in deserts, near farms, highways, or colder regions. For instance, in some parts of the United States, the soiling rate can range from 0.03 to 0.15% per day, while in desert environments, the soiling loss can be as high as 0.5% per day. These generation gaps for solar farms with tens of thousands of panels placed in arrays covering different geographical regions lead to multimillion-dollar losses.</p>



<p>The way to solve soiling on solar farms with advanced analytics is to use forecasting and comprehensive calculation of the costs of soiling. By finding the perfect balance between the cost of cleaning and the prediction of pollution losses, the system based on real-time data can create a cost-effective cleaning schedule for specific areas.</p>



<p>The system can provide a comprehensive report based on actual data, offering an overview of the solar farm’s condition and details about the optimal time for cleaning the solar panels. Additionally, the system can control the activation and deactivation of the nozzles or any other automated cleaning system at the most suitable time.</p>



<p>If you want to learn more about the topic, check out the detailed step-by-step guide covering the topic of “Soiling” in Solar Farms. To read it,&nbsp;<a previewlistener="true" href="./../../../reducing-costs-of-solar-farms-by-optimizing-the-cleaning-process/index.html">click here</a>.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="performance-degradation-over-time">Performance degradation over time</h3>



<p>Another problem faced by solar power plant owners is the progressive degradation of generating capacity over the lifetime of a plant, which spans decades.</p>



<p>The long-term impact of natural factors, such as solar radiation, moisture, thermal cycles, and mechanical loads, leads to slow wear and tear of components over many years. Delamination, color change, hot spots, and microcracks in the panels lead to an annual drop in conversion efficiency and electrical output of 0.5-1%.</p>



<p>For a 100 MWh solar power plant, over 25 years of operation, this steady degradation leads to a 10-20% net drop in electricity generation, which means millions in lost profits. Owners also face uncertainty in accurately predicting the degradation trajectories of equipment of different ages located at different sites. False estimates lead to revenue losses due to inaccurate power sales contracts.</p>



<p>Moreover, solar panels do not only degrade over time. The connection elements, inverters, batteries, and performance monitoring sensors lose effectiveness over time. It should also be noted that because the equipment is open to unplanned complete failure, solar farms may require short- and medium-term replacements.</p>



<p>However, at the same time, we should keep in mind that electricity generation on solar farms is unstable. Therefore, it is not possible to tell the difference between changes in weather conditions and degradation by setting thresholds or simply looking at the indicators.</p>



<p>Advanced analytics allows us to identify long-term and short-term degradation, thus solving this problem. In addition, understanding when the best time to reinvest in equipment replacement is an advantage that will help you maintain the highest possible return on your investment over time.</p>



<p>The system constantly checks indicators from many parts of the solar power plant, making it possible to track the overall condition and degradation of individual areas. Not only is it possible to calculate, but accurate degradation monitoring will help avoid revenue losses caused by unpredictable degradation.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="security-and-intrusion-detection">Security and Intrusion Detection</h3>



<p>Solar power plants are often located in remote locations and are large installations covering large areas. Therefore, expensive equipment such as inverters and solar panels face significant security and intrusion risks from external intruders. These risks can take many forms, causing huge financial and operational losses.</p>



<p>Theft and vandalism are common, with thieves attempting to steal valuable copper wiring and hackers tampering with energy infrastructure, causing power outages. Natural disasters such as forest fires, storms, and floods also create problems that threaten fencing, cables, and monitoring infrastructure. Additional risks, such as unauthorized access to control rooms or electrical sites through broken gates, also create security risks.</p>



<p>Without reliable monitoring tools, these threats often go undetected for long periods, allowing attackers to cause significant damage. Even traditional legacy security systems, such as motion detectors and surveillance cameras, have blind spots where cunning attackers can bypass detection. Patrolling security also offers inconsistent protection based on a large geography. The lack of real-time context also makes threat response ineffective.</p>



<p>Modern analytics platforms offer comprehensive coverage, analysis, and tools to protect solar power plants better. Sensor data analytics can dynamically monitor multi-factor threats. Algorithms can detect anomalies that indicate potential perimeter breaches. Smart cameras or drones can also detect intruder signals and send alerts to dispatchers faster. The information obtained from the cameras and drones can work in conjunction with other data from the solar farm, giving access to almost complete control over the security of the solar farm. Based on historical data from past interventions, you can build the best strategy to eliminate interference in the future.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="optimizing-energy-output">Optimizing Energy Output</h3>



<p>Solar power plants face the challenge of optimizing energy production due to inconsistent access to their main fuel &#8211; sunlight. The energy output changes during the day depending on the sun’s intensity and between days depending on the changing weather conditions.</p>



<p>Complex factors such as cloud cover, temperature, humidity, dust, and vegetation growth also dynamically affect the irradiance falling on the panels.</p>



<p>Starting with potential fines for under-delivery of electricity under power purchase agreements and ending with the impossibility of profitably participating in spot electricity markets based on the fact that there is too much energy to store in batteries of the available capacity. That is why it is important to use complex calculations and forecasts to find the projected energy production for the coming days.</p>



<p>Advanced analytics allows you to detect generation problems by detecting anomalies or forecast problems by predicting them and triggering preventive, corrective actions to eliminate them. The analytical system can also analyze on a minute-by-minute basis whether it is better to take energy from batteries, solar panels, or the system, thus optimizing electricity bills. Such an automated system can significantly reduce electricity bills for households/factories and maximize profits for solar farms.</p>



<p>If you want to learn more about how to solve non-standard tasks and complex calculations using advanced analytics,&nbsp;<a href="./../../../solving-energy-generation-issues-in-solar-farms-using-advanced-analytics/index.html">click here</a>.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="grid-integration-challenge">Grid Integration Challenge</h3>



<p>The volatility of solar generation, which is dependent on weather conditions, creates significant challenges for grid integration. Solar energy production changes rapidly depending on cloud cover and time of day, causing voltage and frequency fluctuations for utilities if not appropriately handled. For grids with a high penetration of solar facilities, this variable generation, if increased, can challenge the stability and reliability of the grid.</p>



<p>There are 3 types of system connection to the grid: distributed systems (off-grid), centralized energy (on-grid), and hybrid systems.</p>



<ul>
<li>Distributed generation is small solar photovoltaic panels (usually from 5 to 500 kilowatts) installed on residential or commercial properties, and solar panels satisfy the main demand for electricity.</li>



<li>Centralized generation is large centralized solar parks, usually with a capacity of hundreds of megawatts, which are connected to the power grid via high-voltage power lines. The main difference between off-grid and on-grid systems is that in centralized power generation, all the energy produced goes from the panels to an inverter, which is converted into alternating current and sent almost directly to the utility grid. In a distributed generation, the energy is stored in batteries and used by a residential or commercial facility as needed.</li>



<li>Hybrid generation differs because it contains batteries and can power a local building and connect to the utility grid.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="781" height="635" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/2-7.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3280" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/2-7.png 781w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/2-7-300x244.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/2-7-768x624.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/2-7-512x416.png 512w" sizes="(max-width: 781px) 100vw, 781px" /></figure>



<p>Problems such as voltage spikes, protection discoordination, phase distortion, and unexpected voltage drops can occur when solar power exhibits instability and unpredictability.</p>



<p>Without effective climate change adaptation, problems range from nuisances like flickering lights to catastrophic large-scale blackouts due to cascading power line failures. The economic costs of unreliable renewable generation also reduce investor confidence in further expanding solar power to meet decarbonization goals.</p>



<p>Predictive forecasting combined with optimization for unexpected situations provides actionable information about the future variability of solar generation. Grid operators can take proactive steps to redirect generators, limit the capacity of solar power plants, or deploy batteries to smooth out fluctuations. Real-time anomaly detection also continuously monitors any new equipment limitations or stability risks.</p>



<p>Optimized algorithms prescribe ideal storage vs generation decisions hourly when combined with predictive modeling of dynamic electricity spot prices. Over a year, farms have achieved as much as 5-7% upside in annual revenues besides minimizing deviation penalties.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="first-steps-to-solving-problems">First steps to solving problems</h2>



<p>We realized which problems occur in solar panels. We understood how to solve them with the help of advanced analytics. So finally, let’s define an action plan on how to make it happen with the help of the ThingsBoard IoT platform and Trendz for advanced analytics:</p>



<ul>
<li>Collect data from the solar farm site into an IoT platform for processing. Most equipment is capable of&nbsp;<a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/user-guide/integrations/">reporting data using Modbus, MQTT, HTTP protocols</a>, or&nbsp;<a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/iot-gateway/what-is-iot-gateway/">gateway data loggers</a>. We need to collect the following information: 
<ul>
<li>Data from weather stations &#8211; solar irradiance, temperature, humidity, etc</li>



<li>Metrics from Inverters &#8211; input and output voltage, current, frequency, etc.</li>



<li>Metrics from solar panels or Strings &#8211; voltage, operating time, panel temperature, panel orientation, etc.</li>



<li>Metrics from batteries or energy storage systems &#8211; voltage and current, state of charge, temperature, etc.</li>



<li>Information from energy meters and grid &#8211; real-time energy flow, power quality data, grid demand response, etc.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Set up a monitoring dashboard in the IoT platform that will&nbsp;<a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/user-guide/dashboards/">visualize collected data in real-time</a>.</li>



<li><a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/trendz/calculated-fields/">Configure computation of </a><a href="http://10.7.3.196:4000/docs/trendz/calculated-fields/">system-level metrics / KPIs</a>&nbsp;that would describe overall system behavior.</li>



<li><a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/trendz/anomaly/anomaly-detection-overview/">Train anomaly detection model on historical data</a>&nbsp;to identify abnormal component behavior or equipment misconfiguration. Enable real-time anomaly detection for all on-site equipment.</li>



<li><a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/trendz/guide/predict-next-maintenance-date-of-equipment/">Configure predictive maintenance models</a>&nbsp;that would forecast potential issues in the future and compute equipment health scores.</li>



<li><a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/user-guide/alarms/">Set up Alerting and notification rules</a>&nbsp;to trigger automated corrective actions or&nbsp;<a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/user-guide/notifications/">notify staff about discovered incidents</a>.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="conclusions">Conclusions</h2>



<p>Solar farms, due to their design factor, have a large number of challenges that require constant intervention and monitoring of the overall condition of the farm. The main challenges are operating and maintenance costs, soiling, performance degradation over time, security and intrusion detection, optimizing energy output, and grid integration challenges.</p>



<p>Effectively handling these challenges is the basis for the high efficiency of a solar farm.</p>



<p>However, manual reading of indicators or setting thresholds is not enough for power plants with unstable energy production. Using advanced analytics will open up new horizons of efficiency and reliability for your solar farm. The future looks bright for the partnership between solar and advanced analytics!</p>




]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../solving-solar-power-plant-problems-using-advanced-analytics/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Optimizing Solar Parks Efficiency &#8211; Advanced Anomaly Detection Solutions #rewrite</title>
		<link>./../../../optimizing-solar-parks-efficiency-advanced-anomaly-detection-solutions-2/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../optimizing-solar-parks-efficiency-advanced-anomaly-detection-solutions-2/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Iryna Kheroim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 15:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=3316</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Solar power plants face issues due to temperature and environmental factors, which lead to reduced efficiency and potential&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Solar power plants face issues due to temperature and environmental factors, which lead to reduced efficiency and potential major breakdowns if not addressed quickly. The challenge is that monitoring tools like drones, digital multimeters, and infrared cameras are costly, making regular checks infrequent, which does not allow quick responses to problems. This means that if a problem arises after a maintenance check, electricity production efficiency will fall, leading to significant losses.</p>



<p><strong>The ability to quickly respond to problems</strong>&nbsp;is what plants with constant energy production need.</p>



<p>One of the ways to achieve a quick response to problems is through the use of anomaly detection. Using this method provides an opportunity to respond to problems quickly and significantly reduces the spending on third-party equipment.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="533" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-35-1024x533.png" alt="" class="wp-image-2886" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-35-1024x533.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-35-300x156.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-35-768x400.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-35-512x266.png 512w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-35-920x479.png 920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-35.png 1505w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Anomaly detection is a technique to identify patterns or events deviating from the norm. In the context of a solar farm, this can involve monitoring various factors, such as Real-time Energy Output, Power Generation Trends, Solar Irradiance, and Temperature for Solar Panels. Also Output Voltage and Current, Frequency, Efficiency, Temperature for Inverter. By analyzing this data, anomaly detection algorithms can identify unusual patterns or events that may indicate problems before they can do any damage to the solar panel or inverter. In other words, we look for a problem not when we see that energy is produced less than expected for the second day in a row but right at the moment when the problem appeared.</p>



<p>But, unusual patterns are not just deviations of parameters from the norm.</p>



<p>Unusual patterns are combinations of parameters that are not expected but which identify potential problems. They are discovered by analyzing historical data collected from solar panels and inverters. During this analysis, we focus not only on individual parameter values but on a combination of values because it potentially gives more insights into system behavior. Based on this, it is possible to find current problems and predict future ones.</p>



<p>A person cannot cope with the calculations of such data arrays. That is why we need advanced analytics with machine learning capabilities to analyze historical data and find unusual patterns in real-time.</p>



<p>Now, we will show how to configure Trends Analytics for correct anomaly detection. However, before that, let’s consider what types of anomalies occur in Solar Farms.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="overview-of-common-anomalies-in-equipment-of-solar-power-plants">Overview of common anomalies in the equipment of solar power plants</h2>



<p>The most widespread and important problems for us are those with solar panels and inverters since these are the first frontier of obtaining energy. Therefore, we will look for anomalies in these parts of the power plant.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="anomalies-in-photovoltaic-modules">Anomalies in photovoltaic modules</h3>



<p>Below, the most common breakdowns in PV modules and solar panels, which can be quickly and economically solved if they are dealt with immediately, will be described.<br><br>Most of them are formed on separate panels, so a drop in the indicators of one panel in contrast to another will indicate a breakdown. You can find each of them by finding anomalies in the Output Electricity (voltage and current) and Power Production indicators from the solar panel.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Soiling:</strong> Soiling refers to the accumulation of dirt, dust, bird droppings, or other materials on the surface of solar panels. This layer of grime can significantly reduce the panels’ ability to absorb sunlight, leading to decreased electricity production.</li>



<li><strong>Shading:</strong> Shading occurs when an object, such as a tree, building, or another solar panel, casts a shadow on a solar panel. This can lead to a reduction in the panel’s electricity production. Prolonged shadowing can lead to an imbalance in the solar panel system and may cause hot spots or reduce the overall lifespan of the panel.</li>



<li><strong>Delamination and Internal Corrosion:</strong> Moisture can find its way into the panel, causing internal corrosion, if the panels are not keeping out air and water and all the solar panel components are not laminated correctly.</li>



<li>Identifying and Addressing Solar Panel Anomalies Faulty wiring, loose connections, corrosion, and oxidation can interfere with electricity production.</li>



<li><strong>Hot Spots:</strong> Badly-soldered connections can cause low resistance in the part of the panel that receives the power generated by the cell, leading to a hotspot in the soldered points and/or a cell. This phenomenon can ultimately lead to a short circuit, reducing the performance and lifespan of the PV panel.</li>



<li><strong>PID Effect:</strong>&nbsp;Potential-induced degradation (PID) can cause an ongoing reduction in performance and accelerated aging of the PV panel. PID occurs when the voltage potential between the solar cells and the grounded frame of the panel causes a leakage current that can damage the cells.</li>



<li><strong>Snail Trail Contamination:</strong>&nbsp;Snail trail contamination is a phenomenon where a white or grayish residue appears on the surface of the solar panel. This residue can reduce the performance of the panel and is caused by the release of silicone from the panel’s encapsulant material.</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="tackling-anomalies-in-inverters">Tackling Anomalies in Inverters</h3>



<p>Inverters are a very important link of a solar power plant, a breakdown of which can lead to the shutdown of the entire power plant. This can have a critical impact on the total efficiency and profitability of the power plant.</p>



<p>You can observe the operation of the inverter by following the indicators Output Voltage and Current, Frequency, Efficiency, and Temperature.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Overheating:</strong>&nbsp;Inverters are sensitive to temperature, and high temperatures can reduce production and potentially a stoppage altogether if overheating occurs as the maximum operating temperature is reached. To prevent overheating, it is important to keep the switch cabinet and the area where the inverter is located well-ventilated, along with the inclusion of cleaning dust filters that can prevent any issues impeding airflow. You can monitor this problem with the help of indicators Temperature, Output Voltage, and Current.</li>



<li><strong>Isolation Short-Circuit Fault:</strong>&nbsp;If there is too much moisture or damage to the cabling sleeves, then an isolation short-circuit fault can occur, whereby the inverter will report an “isolation alarm”. In this scenario, the solar inverter will either work at the minimum “required” isolation level or stop working altogether. You can monitor this problem with the help of indicators Efficiency, Output Voltage, and Current.</li>



<li><strong>Inverter Does Not Restart:</strong>&nbsp;Inverters sometimes fail to restart after a power outage. Various factors, including a faulty inverter, a tripped circuit breaker, or a blown fuse, can cause this. You can monitor this problem with the help of indicators Frequency, and Efficiency.</li>



<li><strong>Maximum Power Point Tracking (MPPT) Module:</strong>&nbsp;The MPPT module is responsible for tracking the maximum power point of the solar panel array. If the MPPT module fails, the inverter cannot convert the DC electricity generated by the solar panels into AC electricity. You can monitor this problem with the help of indicators Temperature, Output Voltage, and Current.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="summary">Summary</h2>



<p>Efficiency challenges in solar farm operations demand a proactive approach to problem-solving, particularly in the context of scheduled diagnostics and high equipment maintenance costs. Anomaly detection emerges as a cost-effective solution, leveraging historical data to identify deviations in parameters like Real-time Energy Output, Power Generation Trends, and Temperature for Solar Panels, along with Output Voltage, Current, Frequency, and Efficiency for Inverters. This approach helps quickly find current problems and predict future issues, which is important for keeping the energy production going without any interruptions.</p>



<p>An efficient strategy to implement this approach involves:</p>



<ul>
<li>Creating anomaly detection models based on historical telemetry data.</li>



<li>Configuring real-time anomaly detection.</li>



<li>Providing a comprehensive dashboard for the maintenance team.</li>
</ul>



<p>This ensures a streamlined process from anomaly identification to resolution, utilizing Trendz Analytics to enhance solar farm efficiency by minimizing downtime, reducing operational costs, and optimizing long-term performance.</p>



<p>And this is only part of how advanced analytics and machine learning can improve the efficiency of solar farms. With help, you can find solutions to your solar farm problems, including Soiling, Battery Health Diagnostics, and more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../optimizing-solar-parks-efficiency-advanced-anomaly-detection-solutions-2/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reducing costs of Solar Farms by optimizing the cleaning process</title>
		<link>./../../../reducing-costs-of-solar-farms-by-optimizing-the-cleaning-process/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../reducing-costs-of-solar-farms-by-optimizing-the-cleaning-process/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Iryna Kheroim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 15:09:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=2957</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Introduction For solar farms, dirty panels can mean thousands of dollars of lost revenue annually. Panels washed too&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="introduction">Introduction</h2>



<p>For solar farms, dirty panels can mean thousands of dollars of lost revenue annually. Panels washed too early or too late – are costs that make up a serious portion of the power plant’s profitability.</p>



<p>In one of our cases, we worked with a Spanish company, a producer of electricity. They owned a solar power plant with a capacity of 10 MW. They will produce about $260,000 worth of energy per month in ideal conditions. However, the company lost over a fifth of its energy due to soiling problems. In turn, the cost of the cleaning cycle was $50,000. Calculating the losses, it was clear that cleaning on a fixed schedule was showing poor results.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="512" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-39-1024x512.png" alt="" class="wp-image-2958" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-39-1024x512.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-39-300x150.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-39-768x384.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-39-1536x768.png 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-39-512x256.png 512w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-39-920x460.png 920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-39-1320x660.png 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-39.png 1567w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>To get the best possible results, you need to be sure of 3 steps:</p>



<ol>
<li>We have to find the energy losses</li>



<li>We need to know the forecast for electricity losses.</li>



<li>You need to find the best time for the cleaning cycle.</li>
</ol>



<p>The key to solving all these questions is advanced analytics. A correctly configured system, like an expert, automatically decides what to do based on real-time and forecasted data and can manage the entire cleaning cycle, from collecting information to turning on the irrigation system or calling a group of cleaners without outside intervention.</p>



<p>Using IoT sensors to track real-time solar generation data, our solution provides actionable intelligence to optimize your cleaning schedule. Here’s how it works:</p>



<ul>
<li>Sensors are installed to monitor energy production from individual panels. This allows precise tracking of solar output over time.</li>



<li>Advanced analytics calculate expected energy generation based on weather conditions and other variables. The difference between expected and available energy generation is considered energy loss.</li>



<li>Our algorithm evaluates the cost of cleaning against potential energy savings. It forecasts lost revenue accrued each day panels remain dirty.</li>



<li>When the value of regained energy outweighs cleaning expenses, the system automatically alerts owners it’s time to wash or turn off/on the cleaning system.</li>



<li>Targeted cleanings restore generation at the optimal moment. You have the opportunity to adjust the cleaning schedule based on the economic feasibility of your decisions.</li>
</ul>



<p>Customers using our solar IoT solution have increased generation by 5-15% while reducing cleaning costs by up to 40%. Solar assets stay active at peak efficiency by timing cleanings precisely when needed.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="effective-solar-panel-cleaning-how-to-optimize-solar-panel-cleaning-schedule">Effective Solar Panel Cleaning. How to optimize Solar Panel cleaning schedule</h2>



<p>Our approach to solving this problem is based on Soiling cost calculation.</p>



<p>Soiling costs are the losses you will incur if you clean your station on this day. This indicator consists of <strong>the cost of cleaning</strong> for a 10 MW plant, which is approximately $50,000, <strong>the sum of all losses</strong> due to pollution, and all this is divided by the number of <strong>days</strong> since the last cleaning.</p>



<p>The indicator drops – good because our costs are decreasing. The indicator starts to rise – you need to wash the panels because the current costs are at their lowest point and then will constantly grow, and that is exactly the point when cleaning is economically feasible. As we can see in the table, in the dry period, when the loss indicators are only growing, the 5th week is the best time to carry out the cleaning cycle because compared to cleaning in any other week, the price is the lowest.</p>



<p>That is why we need to set up an IoT system with advanced analytics to optimize the cleaning schedule based on the historical data from the solar plant, the production forecast, and the metrics we explained in this section.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="summary">Summary</h2>



<p>Solar power plants have many advantages, but due to their novelty, they also have many disadvantages. One of the most common is overspending based on pollution. This is a problem that cannot be eliminated, so the goal – is to minimize losses. Using IoT technologies and advanced analytics, you can easily monitor and wash solar panels at exactly the point in time when cleaning is economically feasible.</p>



<p>Analytics, IoT, and machine learning provide insights, risk forecasts, and data-driven decisions for better business performance. Embracing these ensures competitiveness and risk mitigation. Also, in the future, we plan to tell you how to improve the efficiency of the power plant by finding anomalies in the solar panels and parts of the power plant, such as the inverter or the battery. In our digital age, advanced analytics are the way to simplify and boost complex problem-solving!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../reducing-costs-of-solar-farms-by-optimizing-the-cleaning-process/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Optimizing Solar Parks Efficiency &#8211; Advanced Anomaly Detection Solutions</title>
		<link>./../../../optimizing-solar-parks-efficiency-advanced-anomaly-detection-solutions/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../optimizing-solar-parks-efficiency-advanced-anomaly-detection-solutions/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Iryna Kheroim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 15:08:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=2884</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Solar power plants face issues due to temperature and environmental factors, which lead to reduced efficiency and potential&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Solar power plants face issues due to temperature and environmental factors, which lead to reduced efficiency and potential major breakdowns if not addressed quickly. The challenge is that monitoring tools like drones, digital multimeters, and infrared cameras are costly, making regular checks infrequent, which does not allow quick responses to problems. This means that if a problem arises after a maintenance check, the efficiency of electricity production will fall, which will lead to significant losses.</p>



<p><strong>The ability to quickly respond to problems</strong>&nbsp;is what plants with constant energy production need.</p>



<p>One of the ways to achieve a quick response to problems is through the use of anomaly detection. Using this method not only provides an opportunity to quickly respond to problems but also significantly reduces the spending on third-party equipment.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="533" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-35-1024x533.png" alt="" class="wp-image-2886" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-35-1024x533.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-35-300x156.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-35-768x400.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-35-512x266.png 512w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-35-920x479.png 920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-35.png 1505w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Anomaly detection is a technique used to identify patterns or events that deviate from the norm. In the context of a solar farm, this can involve monitoring a variety of factors, such as Real-time Energy Output, Power Generation Trends, Solar Irradiance, and Temperature for Solar Panels. Also Output Voltage and Current, Frequency, Efficiency, Temperature for Inverter. By analyzing this data, anomaly detection algorithms can identify unusual patterns or events that may indicate problems before they can do any damage to the solar panel or inverter. In other words, we look for a problem not when we see that energy is produced less than expected for the second day in a row, but right at the moment when the problem appeared.</p>



<p>But, unusual patterns are not just deviations of parameters from the norm.</p>



<p>Unusual patterns are combinations of parameters that are not expected, but which identify potential problems. They are discovered by analyzing historical data collected from solar panels and inverters. During this analysis, we focus not only on individual parameter values but on a combination of values because it potentially gives more insights into system behavior. Based on this, it is possible to find current problems and predict future ones.</p>



<p>A person cannot cope with the calculations of such data arrays. That is why we need advanced analytics with machine learning capabilities that can analyze historical data and find unusual patterns in real-time.</p>



<p>Now we will show how to configure Trends Analytics for correct anomaly detection. However, before that, let’s consider what types of anomalies occur in Solar Farms.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="overview-of-common-anomalies-in-equipment-of-solar-power-plants">Overview of common anomalies in equipment of solar power plants</h2>



<p>The most widespread and important for us are problems with solar panels and inverters since this is the first frontier of obtaining energy. Therefore, we will look for anomalies in these parts of the power plant.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="anomalies-in-photovoltaic-modules">Anomalies in photovoltaic modules</h3>



<p>Below, the most common breakdowns in PV modules and solar panels will be described, which can be quickly and economically solved if they are dealt with immediately.</p>



<p>Most of them are formed on separate panels, so a drop in the indicators of one panel in contrast to another will indicate a breakdown. You can find each of them by finding anomalies in the Output Electricity (voltage and current) and Power Production indicators from the solar panel.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Soiling:</strong>&nbsp;Soiling refers to the accumulation of dirt, dust, bird droppings, or other materials on the surface of solar panels. This layer of grime can significantly reduce the panels’ ability to absorb sunlight, leading to decreased electricity production.</li>



<li><strong>Shading:</strong>&nbsp;Shading occurs when an object, such as a tree, building, or another solar panel, casts a shadow on a solar panel. This can lead to a reduction in the panel’s electricity production. Prolonged shadowing can lead to an imbalance in the solar panel system and may cause hot spots or reduce the overall lifespan of the panel.</li>



<li><strong>Delamination and Internal Corrosion:</strong>&nbsp;Moisture can find its way into the panel, causing internal corrosion, if the panels are not keeping out air and water and all the components of the solar panel are not laminated correctly.</li>



<li>Identifying and Addressing Solar Panel Anomalies Faulty wiring, loose connections, corrosion, and oxidation can interfere with electricity production.</li>



<li><strong>Hot Spots:</strong>&nbsp;Badly-soldered connections can cause low resistance in the part of the panel that receives the power generated by the cell, leading to a hotspot in the soldered points and/or a cell. This phenomenon can ultimately lead to a short circuit, reducing the performance and lifespan of the PV panel.</li>



<li><strong>PID Effect:</strong>&nbsp;Potential-induced degradation (PID) can cause an ongoing reduction in performance and accelerated aging of the PV panel. PID occurs when the voltage potential between the solar cells and the grounded frame of the panel causes a leakage current that can damage the cells.</li>



<li><strong>Snail Trail Contamination:</strong>&nbsp;Snail trail contamination is a phenomenon where a white or grayish residue appears on the surface of the solar panel. This residue can reduce the performance of the panel and is caused by the release of silicone from the panel’s encapsulant material.</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="tackling-anomalies-in-inverters">Tackling Anomalies in Inverters</h3>



<p>Inverters are a very important link of a solar power plant, a breakdown of which can lead to the shutdown of the entire power plant. This can have a critical impact on the total efficiency and profitability of the power plant.</p>



<p>You can observe the operation of the inverter by following the indicators Output Voltage and Current, Frequency, Efficiency, and Temperature.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Overheating:</strong>&nbsp;Inverters are sensitive to temperature, and high temperatures can lead to a reduction in production and potentially a stoppage altogether if overheating occurs as the maximum operating temperature is reached. To prevent overheating, it is important to keep the switch cabinet and the area where the inverter is located well-ventilated, along with the inclusion of cleaning dust filters that can prevent any issues impeding airflow. You can monitor this problem with the help of indicators Temperature, Output Voltage, and Current.</li>



<li><strong>Isolation Short-Circuit Fault:</strong>&nbsp;If there is too much moisture or damage to the cabling sleeves, then an isolation short-circuit fault can occur, whereby the inverter will report an “isolation alarm”. In this scenario, the solar inverter will either work at the minimum “required” isolation level or stop working altogether. You can monitor this problem with the help of indicators Efficiency, Output Voltage, and Current.</li>



<li><strong>Inverter Does Not Restart:</strong>&nbsp;Inverters can sometimes fail to restart after a power outage. This can be caused by a variety of factors, including a faulty inverter, a tripped circuit breaker, or a blown fuse. You can monitor this problem with the help of indicators Frequency, and Efficiency.</li>



<li><strong>Maximum Power Point Tracking (MPPT) Module:</strong>&nbsp;The MPPT module is responsible for tracking the maximum power point of the solar panel array. If the MPPT module fails, the inverter will not be able to convert the DC electricity generated by the solar panels into AC electricity. You can monitor this problem with the help of indicators Temperature, Output Voltage, and Current.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="summary">Summary</h2>



<p>Efficiency challenges in solar farm operations demand a proactive approach to problem-solving, particularly in the context of scheduled diagnostics and high equipment maintenance costs. Anomaly detection emerges as a cost-effective solution, leveraging historical data to identify deviations in parameters like Real-time Energy Output, Power Generation Trends, and Temperature for Solar Panels, along with Output Voltage, Current, Frequency, and Efficiency for Inverters. This approach helps quickly find current problems and predict future issues, which is important for keeping the energy production going without any interruptions.</p>



<p>To implement this approach, an efficient strategy involves creating anomaly detection models based on historical telemetry data, configuring real-time anomaly detection, and providing a comprehensive dashboard for the maintenance team. This ensures a streamlined process from anomaly identification to resolution, utilizing Trendz Analytics to enhance solar farm efficiency by minimizing downtime, reducing operational costs, and optimizing long-term performance.</p>



<p>And this is only part of how advanced analytics and machine learning can improve the efficiency of solar farms. With help, you can find solutions to your solar farm problems, including Soiling, Battery Health Diagnostics, and more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../optimizing-solar-parks-efficiency-advanced-anomaly-detection-solutions/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Solving energy generation issues in Solar Farms using advanced analytics</title>
		<link>./../../../solving-energy-generation-issues-in-solar-farms-using-advanced-analytics/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../solving-energy-generation-issues-in-solar-farms-using-advanced-analytics/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Iryna Kheroim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 15:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=2890</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Description of the problem During work with many cases of our clients, we faced a series of unusual&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h1 class="wp-block-heading">Description of the problem</h1>



<p>During work with many cases of our clients, we faced a series of unusual problems in solar farms. We decided to show you how it can be solved with the help of advanced analytics.</p>



<p>Solar farms are stations with a large working area, the frequent inspection of which is not financially profitable. That’s why companies conduct quarterly technical inspections on a schedule or in case of serious problems that can be noticed with the naked eye.</p>



<p>However, there are many localized problems that can greatly affect efficiency in the long run but cannot be noticed simply by comparing a few indicators. For example, the occurrence of corrosion on a solar panel will reduce the solar panel’s efficiency more and more every day. However, the production rate in this case will never reach 0, so primitive detectors will not report the problem. Based on this, the costs will reach from 10 to 40% of the electricity for each day from the string, until the upcoming quarterly inspection. We talked more about them in the article about finding anomalies in solar power plants.</p>



<p>Knowing what these problems are and where they appear, it is only necessary to build the right search mechanism to answer the question: “In which segment of the solar plants did the error occur?”. In other words, it will tell not only about the problem’s existence but also about its location.</p>



<p>Usually, solar panels are located in approximately the same area, so they are all covered by the same conditions and usually have similar power generation, with a 4-5% difference. The reason for the fluctuation is that solar panels operate in uncontrolled environmental conditions. The power generation of solar panels may vary depending on the temperature, degree of pollution, and humidity, which may be different during the day for each solar panel separately.</p>



<p>Let’s consider the usual structure of solar power plants. Panels were connected to the inverter by strings. Data on energy production was collected from the inverter to which all these strings were connected.</p>



<p>A simple manual review of the data or setting a threshold on indicators will not be enough to diagnose faults. That’s because power generation is non-linear and depends on many factors. That is why we need a tool that can adapt to the task. In our system, such a tool is Calculated Field. This tool allows you to get any useful information from your data, with access to all the necessary parameters and setting up the right logic.</p>



<p>In our task, the desired information is energy underproduction. To find this indicator, we need to:</p>



<ul>
<li>Find how much a properly working line should produce.</li>



<li>Understand what is the permissible level of deviation from the energy production of a properly working indicator that we should set.</li>



<li>A system that can constantly adjust to a non-constant deviation.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="532" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-37-1024x532.png" alt="" class="wp-image-2892" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-37-1024x532.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-37-300x156.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-37-768x399.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-37-512x266.png 512w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-37-920x478.png 920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/image-37.png 1504w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>To find how much energy we lose, we need to find how much a string with properly working panels should produce, that name reference value. Compared to the current string Electricity Production, it will be possible to find the delta, which is the amount of energy underproduced.</p>



<p>Observing the behavior of solar power plants, we concluded that it would be best to take the maximum power output of one string in the inverter like the reference value. The reason is that the strings with panels are located in the same zone and consist of devices of the same generation rate. As a result, the maximum value will deviate only slightly from the other values.</p>



<p>Next, we need to compare the energy production of each string with the reference value for this inverter. If the value has a difference of more than 10% from the reference, then it is considered that the string has problems with the undergeneration of energy.</p>



<p>However, to find delta it is not enough to look at energy production at the moment. A small cloud flying by, or some garbage in the air that temporarily sticks to the panel, can affect the string performance. This would be noted as a problem, although the panels are working properly.</p>



<p>That is why it is important to take the average value of energy production by one string for the entire sunny day.</p>



<p>At the same time, not all the stuff that gets on the solar panel can be removed in one day. For example, sand from a localized gust of wind can hit individual strings, which will be diagnosed as a fault. Until it is washed away by rain or a cleaning system after a while. Calling a technical team to this line will be a waste of money. The way out of the situation is to set up an alert when the energy generation seems to be reduced for 3 days in a row.</p>



<p>By meeting all of these conditions, the system can perform constant recalculations in real-time, based on real data, sort it out, and send it in the form of a convenient report to the responsible person. And, of course, this is not the case with just one inverter, but dozens and hundreds of inverters that are constantly providing new indicators.</p>



<p>The availability of such a tool will not only reduce the cost of full diagnostics but also make it possible to conduct local inspections. It will also provide an opportunity to find and solve problems in a short time, which will increase the overall efficiency of the solar farm.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="summary">Summary</h2>



<p>In conclusion, the use of advanced analytics in solar farms can greatly improve the efficiency of the system by detecting localized problems that cannot be noticed by simple indicators. The proposed solution involves using a flexible tool called Calculated Field, which allows for calculations based on formulas, metrics, and data. By finding the reference value and comparing the energy production of each string with it, the system can identify strings with under-generated energy. It is important to meet 3 conditions:</p>



<ul>
<li>The delta value must exceed 10%.</li>



<li>The indicator should contain the arithmetic mean value for the entire sunny day</li>



<li>The indicator must exceed the specified limit for 3 days in a row.</li>
</ul>



<p>By meeting all of these conditions, the system can perform constant recalculations in real-time, based on real data, sort it out, and send it in the form of a convenient report to the responsible person. The availability of such a tool not only reduces the cost of full diagnostics but also makes it possible to conduct local inspections and solve problems in a short time, which ultimately increases the overall efficiency of the solar farm. With the help of advanced analytics and the Calculated Field tool, any business task can be accomplished given the necessary input data.</p>



<p>In summary, we have explored how an advanced analytics platform can solve non-standard business problems.</p>



<p>Proper use of Calculated Fields, prediction capabilities, and anomaly diagnostics together will provide you with a flexible and very versatile tool that will help you customize most of the business aspects of your business.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../solving-energy-generation-issues-in-solar-farms-using-advanced-analytics/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Increasing equipment utilization KPIs with the help of advanced analytics #Design</title>
		<link>./../../../increasing-equipment-utilization-kpis-with-the-help-of-advanced-analytics-2/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Iryna Kheroim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 11:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=3147</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Introduction&#160; Equipment in production plays an important role in achieving maximum efficiency, quality, and payback. The issues that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Introduction&nbsp;</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">Equipment in production plays an important role in achieving maximum efficiency, quality, and payback. The issues that are key to optimizing the use of equipment are:</p>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px">Underutilization of Equipment</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">Ineffective Production Scheduling</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">Excessive Wear and Tear on Machinery</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">Operational Bottlenecks</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">Suboptimal Maintenance Scheduling</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">Misaligned Capacity Planning</li>
</ul>



<p style="font-size:16px">Solving these problems requires constant monitoring of equipment utilization and performance metrics. As production output increases, manufacturers may need to partially or completely change their equipment maintenance strategies and schedules to maintain efficiency. Unfortunately, these problems cannot be solved once and for all. But it also means that we are able to endlessly improve the optimization process.&nbsp;</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">That is why it is important to have the most up-to-date data when choosing a optimization strategy. Previously, with the help of logging, you could see how the equipment worked at the end of the day or week. With the growth of technology, with the help of IoT devices, we can receive raw data in real-time. With advanced analytics, you can now turn raw data into meaningful reports and predict future equipment behavior using machine learning models.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Equipment Utilization</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">To understand the overall condition of the equipment, you need to operate with a significant number of KPIs. We have divided KPIs by the problems they solve:</p>



<p style="font-size:16px"><em>Underutilization of Equipment and Operational Bottlenecks</em></p>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px">Production Output &#8211; A numerical or quality indicator of the useful action performed by the equipment. The information is collected using counters, scales, or quality sensors transmitted via the network to the ThingsBoard. The data does not require any additional processing.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2409" height="1515" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-production-output-1.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3192" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-production-output-1.png 2409w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-production-output-1-300x189.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-production-output-1-1024x644.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-production-output-1-768x483.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-production-output-1-1536x966.png 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-production-output-1-2048x1288.png 2048w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-production-output-1-512x322.png 512w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-production-output-1-920x579.png 920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-production-output-1-1600x1006.png 1600w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-production-output-1-1920x1207.png 1920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-production-output-1-1320x830.png 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 2409px) 100vw, 2409px" /></figure>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px">Equipment Utilization Rate &#8211; measures the degree to which equipment is utilized over a period compared to its full potential or capacity. Production Output is taken as the current capacity indicator. The maximum capacity is set according to the technical documentation. The indicator is calculated by an analytics system that finds the ratio of Production Output to Maximum Capacity in real time.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="3212" height="1980" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3197" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3.png 3212w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3-300x185.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3-1024x631.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3-768x473.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3-1536x947.png 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3-2048x1262.png 2048w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3-512x316.png 512w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3-920x567.png 920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3-1600x986.png 1600w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3-3200x1973.png 3200w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3-1920x1184.png 1920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3-1320x814.png 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 3212px) 100vw, 3212px" /></figure>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px">Percentage of defects &#8211; The number of defects concerning the Production Output. Defective products are automatically detected using computer vision, ultrasonic or X-ray inspection, or by using manual inspection. The advanced analytics system calculates it in real-time by comparing the number of defective products to the manufactured product.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="638" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Precentage-of-Defects-2-1024x638.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3200" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Precentage-of-Defects-2-1024x638.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Precentage-of-Defects-2-300x187.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Precentage-of-Defects-2-768x478.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Precentage-of-Defects-2-1536x956.png 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Precentage-of-Defects-2-2048x1275.png 2048w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Precentage-of-Defects-2-512x319.png 512w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Precentage-of-Defects-2-920x573.png 920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Precentage-of-Defects-2-1600x996.png 1600w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Precentage-of-Defects-2-1920x1196.png 1920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Precentage-of-Defects-2-1320x822.png 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Precentage-of-Defects-2.png 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px"><em>Ineffective Production Scheduling</em></p>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px">Throughput &#8211; Measuring the rate at which products are produced on a machine, line, plant, or across the entire company. Throughput is calculated from meters installed at the inlet and outlet of each production line. After that, the advanced analytics system converts the raw data of time indicators into a ready-made report of the time it took the equipment to perform a certain action.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2409" height="1791" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Throughput-1.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3206" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Throughput-1.png 2409w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Throughput-1-300x223.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Throughput-1-1024x761.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Throughput-1-768x571.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Throughput-1-1536x1142.png 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Throughput-1-2048x1523.png 2048w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Throughput-1-512x381.png 512w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Throughput-1-920x684.png 920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Throughput-1-1600x1190.png 1600w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Throughput-1-1920x1427.png 1920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Throughput-1-1320x981.png 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 2409px) 100vw, 2409px" /></figure>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px">Time-Based Measurement &#8211; tracks how long the equipment is actively used during a defined period, such as a shift or a day. This measurement is crucial as it reveals the actual usage versus the potential capacity, highlighting whether the equipment is being underutilized or overused. Information is collected through the use of IoT devices or functions built into the equipment. After that, raw time data is translated into a ready-made KPI indicator using advanced analytics.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="641" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Time-Based-Measurement-1024x641.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3207" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Time-Based-Measurement-1024x641.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Time-Based-Measurement-300x188.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Time-Based-Measurement-768x481.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Time-Based-Measurement-1536x962.png 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Time-Based-Measurement-2048x1283.png 2048w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Time-Based-Measurement-512x321.png 512w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Time-Based-Measurement-920x576.png 920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Time-Based-Measurement-1600x1002.png 1600w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Time-Based-Measurement-1920x1203.png 1920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Time-Based-Measurement-1320x827.png 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Time-Based-Measurement.png 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px"><em>Excessive Wear and Tear on Machinery and Suboptimal Maintenance Scheduling</em></p>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px">Downtime and Uptime &#8211;&nbsp; Uptime refers to the duration when the equipment is running and available for use, directly contributing to productivity. Downtime, on the other hand, represents periods when the equipment is non-operational due to maintenance, breakdowns, or other issues. These metrics are crucial for understanding the reliability and efficiency of equipment. Information is collected through the use of IoT devices or functions built into the equipment. The data does not require any additional processing.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">Mean Time To Repair (MTTR) &#8211; This measures the average time it takes to repair equipment after a failure. A lower MTTR helps in reducing downtime and maintaining productivity.&nbsp; This indicator uses the same metrics for calculation as the Downtime and Uptime KPIs. After the data has been collected, the advanced analytics system calculates the average value among the time indicators and provides a ready-made report.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<div class="wp-block-columns is-layout-flex wp-container-core-columns-layout-1 wp-block-columns-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-column is-layout-flow wp-block-column-is-layout-flow" style="flex-basis:100%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="639" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-MTTR-1024x639.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3208" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-MTTR-1024x639.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-MTTR-300x187.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-MTTR-768x479.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-MTTR-1536x958.png 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-MTTR-2048x1278.png 2048w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-MTTR-512x319.png 512w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-MTTR-920x574.png 920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-MTTR-1600x998.png 1600w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-MTTR-1920x1198.png 1920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-MTTR-1320x824.png 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-MTTR.png 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>
</div>
</div>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px">Mean Time Between Failures (MTBF) &#8211; This KPI measures the average time between equipment failures. A higher MTBF indicates more reliable equipment. This indicator uses the same metrics for calculation as the Downtime and Uptime KPIs. After the data has been collected, the advanced analytics system calculates the average value among the time indicators and provides a ready-made report.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<p style="font-size:16px">Based on the indicators that this method helps to track, production has more opportunities to react proactively or react to problems. Thus, the use of advanced analytics gives us access to:</p>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px"><strong>Maximizing Efficiency</strong>: By measuring how much equipment is used compared to its full potential, companies can identify underused resources. This helps in making adjustments to increase efficiency, ensuring that the equipment is not just sitting idle when it could be contributing to production.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px"><strong>Cost Optimization</strong>: Equipment represents a significant investment for any business. Measuring its utilization helps in understanding whether the company is getting the most out of this investment. If equipment isn&#8217;t used effectively, it could lead to unnecessary expenses like paying for machines that aren&#8217;t contributing to revenue generation.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px"><strong>Improving Production Planning</strong>: Equipment utilization data is crucial for effective production scheduling. It helps in aligning the use of machinery with production demands, ensuring that the right equipment is available and operational when needed.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px"><strong>Reducing Wear and Tear</strong>: Overuse of equipment can lead to increased maintenance needs and shorter lifespans for machinery. By monitoring utilization, companies can balance the workload on equipment to prevent excessive wear and tear.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px"><strong>Identifying Bottlenecks</strong>: Low utilization rates can signal bottlenecks where equipment is not being used effectively in the production process. This can lead to insights about process inefficiencies or the need for re-allocation of resources.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px"><strong>Maintenance Scheduling</strong>: Knowing how frequently and intensely equipment is used informs maintenance schedules. Instead of following a rigid maintenance calendar, companies can plan maintenance based on actual usage, reducing downtime and maintenance costs.</li>
</ul>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">The exploration of advanced analytics in equipment utilization underscores a transformative shift in how manufacturing processes are optimized. By integrating real-time data collection through IoT devices with the analytical power of advanced analytics and machine learning, production facilities are equipped to make more informed, proactive decisions. This approach revolutionizes equipment management by providing a deeper and more accurate understanding of various key performance indicators (KPIs) like Equipment Utilization Rate, Throughput, Downtime and Uptime, MTTR, and MTBF.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">The implications of this evolution are far-reaching. Advanced analytics enables a more dynamic approach to addressing challenges like underutilization, inefficient production scheduling, and excessive wear and tear on machinery. It allows for real-time identification of operational bottlenecks and facilitates more strategic maintenance scheduling, thereby extending the lifespan of equipment and optimizing investment returns.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Furthermore, the capacity to predict and preempt equipment failures through these sophisticated analytical tools not only enhances operational efficiency but also significantly reduces costs. This proactive approach to equipment maintenance and optimization ensures that resources are utilized effectively, reducing wastage and downtime.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">In conclusion, the integration of advanced analytics into equipment utilization is not just an enhancement of existing processes; it&#8217;s a fundamental shift towards a more data-driven, efficient, and productive manufacturing environment. As industries continue to evolve, the adoption of these technologies will become a cornerstone for competitive advantage, driving innovation and excellence in manufacturing processes. The future of industrial efficiency and productivity lies in harnessing the power of advanced analytics, and the journey has just begun.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Increasing Equipment Utilization KPIs with the help of advanced analytics</title>
		<link>./../../../increasing-equipment-utilization-kpis-with-the-help-of-advanced-analytics/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Iryna Kheroim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 15:28:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=2354</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Introduction  Equipment in production plays an important role in achieving maximum efficiency, quality, and payback. The issues that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Introduction </h2>



<p>Equipment in production plays an important role in achieving maximum efficiency, quality, and payback. The issues that are key to optimizing the use of equipment are:<br></p>



<ul>
<li>Underutilization of Equipment</li>



<li>Ineffective Production Scheduling</li>



<li>Excessive Wear and Tear on Machinery</li>



<li>Operational Bottlenecks</li>



<li>Suboptimal Maintenance Scheduling</li>



<li>Misaligned Capacity Planning</li>
</ul>



<p>Solving these problems requires constant monitoring of equipment utilization and performance metrics. As production output increases, manufacturers may need to partially or completely change their equipment maintenance strategies and schedules to maintain efficiency. Unfortunately, these problems cannot be solved once and for all. But it also means that we are able to endlessly improve the optimization process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That is why it is important to have the most up-to-date data when choosing a optimization strategy. Previously, with the help of logging, you could see how the equipment worked at the end of the day or week. With the growth of technology, with the help of IoT devices, we can receive raw data in real-time. With advanced analytics, you can now turn raw data into meaningful reports and predict future equipment behavior using machine learning models.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Equipment Utilization</h2>



<p>To understand the overall condition of the equipment, you need to operate with a significant number of KPIs. We have divided KPIs by the problems they solve:<br></p>



<p><em>Underutilization of Equipment and Operational Bottlenecks</em></p>



<ul>
<li>Production Output &#8211; A numerical or quality indicator of the useful action performed by the equipment. The information is collected using counters, scales, or quality sensors transmitted via the network to the ThingsBoard. The data does not require any additional processing.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="603" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/1-1024x603.png" alt="" class="wp-image-2355" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/1-1024x603.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/1-300x177.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/1-768x452.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/1-1536x905.png 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/1-512x302.png 512w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/1-920x542.png 920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/1.png 1545w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<ul>
<li>Equipment Utilization Rate &#8211; measures the degree to which equipment is utilized over a period compared to its full potential or capacity. Production Output is taken as the current capacity indicator. The maximum capacity is set according to the technical documentation. The indicator is calculated by an analytics system that finds the ratio of Production Output to Maximum Capacity in real time.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="586" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/2-1024x586.png" alt="" class="wp-image-2356" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/2-1024x586.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/2-300x172.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/2-768x440.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/2-1536x879.png 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/2-512x293.png 512w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/2-920x527.png 920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/2.png 1548w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<ul>
<li>Percentage of defects &#8211; The number of defects concerning the Production Output. Defective products are automatically detected using computer vision, ultrasonic or X-ray inspection, or by using manual inspection. The advanced analytics system calculates it in real-time by comparing the number of defective products to the manufactured product. </li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="594" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/3-1024x594.png" alt="" class="wp-image-2357" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/3-1024x594.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/3-300x174.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/3-768x446.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/3-1536x891.png 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/3-512x297.png 512w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/3-920x534.png 920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/3.png 1551w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p><em>Ineffective Production Scheduling</em></p>



<ul>
<li>Throughput &#8211; Measuring the rate at which products are produced on a machine, line, plant, or across the entire company. Throughput is calculated from meters installed at the inlet and outlet of each production line. After that, the advanced analytics system converts the raw data of time indicators into a ready-made report of the time it took the equipment to perform a certain action.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="828" height="600" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4.png" alt="" class="wp-image-2358" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4.png 828w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-300x217.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-768x557.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-512x371.png 512w" sizes="(max-width: 828px) 100vw, 828px" /></figure>



<ul>
<li>Time-Based Measurement &#8211; tracks how long the equipment is actively used during a defined period, such as a shift or a day. This measurement is crucial as it reveals the actual usage versus the potential capacity, highlighting whether the equipment is being underutilized or overused. Information is collected through the use of IoT devices or functions built into the equipment. After that, raw time data is translated into a ready-made KPI indicator using advanced analytics.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="599" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/5-1024x599.png" alt="" class="wp-image-2359" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/5-1024x599.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/5-300x175.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/5-768x449.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/5-1536x898.png 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/5-512x299.png 512w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/5-920x538.png 920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/5.png 1541w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p><em>Excessive Wear and Tear on Machinery and Suboptimal Maintenance Scheduling</em></p>



<ul>
<li>Downtime and Uptime &#8211;&nbsp; Uptime refers to the duration when the equipment is running and available for use, directly contributing to productivity. Downtime, on the other hand, represents periods when the equipment is non-operational due to maintenance, breakdowns, or other issues. These metrics are crucial for understanding the reliability and efficiency of equipment. Information is collected through the use of IoT devices or functions built into the equipment. The data does not require any additional processing.</li>



<li>Mean Time To Repair (MTTR) &#8211; This measures the average time it takes to repair equipment after a failure. A lower MTTR helps in reducing downtime and maintaining productivity.  This indicator uses the same metrics for calculation as the Downtime and Uptime KPIs. After the data has been collected, the advanced analytics system calculates the average value among the time indicators and provides a ready-made report. </li>
</ul>



<div class="wp-block-columns is-layout-flex wp-container-core-columns-layout-2 wp-block-columns-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-column is-layout-flow wp-block-column-is-layout-flow" style="flex-basis:100%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="594" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-1-1024x594.png" alt="" class="wp-image-2361" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-1-1024x594.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-1-300x174.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-1-768x445.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-1-1536x890.png 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-1-512x297.png 512w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-1-920x533.png 920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-1.png 1544w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>
</div>
</div>



<ul>
<li>Mean Time Between Failures (MTBF) &#8211; This KPI measures the average time between equipment failures. A higher MTBF indicates more reliable equipment. This indicator uses the same metrics for calculation as the Downtime and Uptime KPIs. After the data has been collected, the advanced analytics system calculates the average value among the time indicators and provides a ready-made report. </li>
</ul>



<p>Based on the indicators that this method helps to track, production has more opportunities to react proactively or react to problems. Thus, the use of advanced analytics gives us access to:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Maximizing Efficiency</strong>: By measuring how much equipment is used compared to its full potential, companies can identify underused resources. This helps in making adjustments to increase efficiency, ensuring that the equipment is not just sitting idle when it could be contributing to production.</li>



<li><strong>Cost Optimization</strong>: Equipment represents a significant investment for any business. Measuring its utilization helps in understanding whether the company is getting the most out of this investment. If equipment isn&#8217;t used effectively, it could lead to unnecessary expenses like paying for machines that aren&#8217;t contributing to revenue generation.</li>



<li><strong>Improving Production Planning</strong>: Equipment utilization data is crucial for effective production scheduling. It helps in aligning the use of machinery with production demands, ensuring that the right equipment is available and operational when needed.</li>



<li><strong>Reducing Wear and Tear</strong>: Overuse of equipment can lead to increased maintenance needs and shorter lifespans for machinery. By monitoring utilization, companies can balance the workload on equipment to prevent excessive wear and tear.</li>



<li><strong>Identifying Bottlenecks</strong>: Low utilization rates can signal bottlenecks where equipment is not being used effectively in the production process. This can lead to insights about process inefficiencies or the need for re-allocation of resources.</li>



<li><strong>Maintenance Scheduling</strong>: Knowing how frequently and intensely equipment is used informs maintenance schedules. Instead of following a rigid maintenance calendar, companies can plan maintenance based on actual usage, reducing downtime and maintenance costs.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h2>



<p>The exploration of advanced analytics in equipment utilization underscores a transformative shift in how manufacturing processes are optimized. By integrating real-time data collection through IoT devices with the analytical power of advanced analytics and machine learning, production facilities are equipped to make more informed, proactive decisions. This approach revolutionizes equipment management by providing a deeper and more accurate understanding of various key performance indicators (KPIs) like Equipment Utilization Rate, Throughput, Downtime and Uptime, MTTR, and MTBF.</p>



<p>The implications of this evolution are far-reaching. Advanced analytics enables a more dynamic approach to addressing challenges like underutilization, inefficient production scheduling, and excessive wear and tear on machinery. It allows for real-time identification of operational bottlenecks and facilitates more strategic maintenance scheduling, thereby extending the lifespan of equipment and optimizing investment returns.</p>



<p>Furthermore, the capacity to predict and preempt equipment failures through these sophisticated analytical tools not only enhances operational efficiency but also significantly reduces costs. This proactive approach to equipment maintenance and optimization ensures that resources are utilized effectively, reducing wastage and downtime.</p>



<p>In conclusion, the integration of advanced analytics into equipment utilization is not just an enhancement of existing processes; it&#8217;s a fundamental shift towards a more data-driven, efficient, and productive manufacturing environment. As industries continue to evolve, the adoption of these technologies will become a cornerstone for competitive advantage, driving innovation and excellence in manufacturing processes. The future of industrial efficiency and productivity lies in harnessing the power of advanced analytics, and the journey has just begun.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
