<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Release &#8211; ThingsBoard&#039;s blog</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 11:34:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/cropped-favicon-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Release &#8211; ThingsBoard&#039;s blog</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>New Release 3.6.3 Announcement</title>
		<link>./../../../new-release-3-6-3-announcement/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../new-release-3-6-3-announcement/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dmytro Andriichenko]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 11:29:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Release]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=3392</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Inspired by the valuable feedback from our dedicated community and users, we are excited to announce the launch&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Inspired by the valuable feedback from our dedicated community and users, we are excited to announce the launch of Thingsboard version 3.6.3. This latest release is packed with innovations and enhancements that promise to enrich your IoT platform experience. Version 3.6.3 introduces new functionalities and focuses on streamlining existing processes, ensuring a seamless, more efficient operation for all ThingsBoard users. Embrace the advancements in IoT management and deployment that Version 3.6.3 brings to your toolkit.</p>



<p>This article will briefly describe the most interesting updates to our new features. You can find the full list of updates here.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Notifications to mobile application</h2>



<p>We are adding support for sending push notifications to mobile applications. This enhancement includes the ability to load Firebase service account credentials, revamp the dialog for creating notification templates and sending notifications, and allow for the customization of the push notification&#8217;s &#8220;subject&#8221; and &#8220;message&#8221;. This update aims to enhance mobile application interaction by directly providing timely and relevant notifications to users&#8217; devices.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Notifications-to-app.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3486"/></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Slider widget</h2>



<p>Added a &#8220;Slider widget&#8221; to ThingsBoard, offering a new UI element that allows for easy adjustment of values through a sliding mechanism. This enhancement is designed to improve user experience by providing a straightforward and intuitive way to input values, making it particularly useful for settings requiring precise control over various options.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Slider-widget.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3464"/></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Toggle button widget</h2>



<p>Added a &#8220;Toggle button widget&#8221; to ThingsBoard. This feature provides a graphical UI element that can be toggled on or off, enhancing user interaction and control within the dashboard. The implementation ensures that the widget is seamlessly integrated into the platform, offering a user-friendly option for managing binary states of devices or parameters. More information about this widget can be read here.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Toggle-button-widget.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3465"/></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Action button widget</h2>



<p>Added the &#8220;Action button widget&#8221; to ThingsBoard, enhancing the platform&#8217;s interactivity with a new user interface element that enables the execution of actions directly from the dashboard. This update aims to improve user engagement and operational efficiency by providing a straightforward mechanism for users to interact with devices or data processes. More information about this widget can be read here.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Action-button-widget.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3466"/></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Power button widget</h2>



<p>Added a &#8220;Power button widget&#8221; to ThingsBoard, further enhancing user interface customization options. This widget allows users to easily control the power states of devices directly from the dashboard, offering a practical and visually appealing method for device management. More information about this widget can be read here.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Power-button-widget.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3467"/></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Command button widget</h2>



<p>Added a &#8220;Command button widget&#8221; to ThingsBoard, which is aimed at enhancing the dashboard&#8217;s functionality by allowing users to execute specific commands directly from the UI. This addition is designed to streamline operations and improve the user experience by providing more interactive and dynamic widget options. More information about this widget can be read here.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Command-button-widget.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3468"/></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Single Switch control widget</h2>



<p>ThingsBoard introduces a Single &#8220;Switch control widget&#8221; designed to enhance user interaction by allowing straightforward control over device functionalities. This widget simplifies the process of toggling device states, offering an intuitive interface for users.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Single-Switch-control-widget.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3469"/></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Bar chart with labels</h2>



<p>We are implementing a new &#8220;Bar chart with labels&#8221; chart widget for ThingsBoard. This addition enriches the visualization options available on the platform, allowing for displaying bar charts accompanied by labels for clearer data presentation and analysis.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Bar-chart-with-labels-1.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3472"/></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../new-release-3-6-3-announcement/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
