<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>ThingsBoard&#039;s blog</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 12:42:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/cropped-favicon-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>ThingsBoard&#039;s blog</title>
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>ThingsBoard unpacked: Community edition, Professional, or Cloud?</title>
		<link>./../thingsboard-unpacked-community-edition-professional-or-cloud/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anastasia Antoniuk]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 12:38:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=3340</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the world of IoT platforms, ThingsBoard stands out with its flexible offerings tailored to various needs and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the world of IoT platforms, ThingsBoard stands out with its flexible offerings tailored to various needs and budgets. Today, we&#8217;re diving into the different flavors of ThingsBoard to help you pick the one that fits your project like a glove. Let&#8217;s break it down, shall we?</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Community Edition (CE)</h3>



<p>Starting with the Community Edition it&#8217;s the open-source hero of the lineup. The CE is totally free and offers a solid foundation with limited features. You&#8217;re looking at basic asset management, real-time dashboards, and customizable goodies. It&#8217;s a DIY enthusiast&#8217;s dream, with system admin access and the freedom to play around with the code. Check out the live demo <a previewlistener="true" href="https://demo.thingsboard.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a> before you dive in.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Professional Edition (PE) Self-Managed</h3>



<p>Next up, the Professional Edition steps it up a notch. It&#8217;s the premium, closed-source variant for those who mean business. Unlimited features? Check. Various integration options out-of-the-box? You got it. This edition is self-managed, meaning you&#8217;re in charge of deployment and management, but with the added perks of advanced rule engine, entity groups, and white-labeling options. For the power users out there, it&#8217;s worth every penny. Check out the pricing options <a href="https://thingsboard.io/pricing/?product=thingsboard-pe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>. </p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Professional Edition Cloud (PE PaaS)</h3>



<p>Last but not least, the PE Cloud version takes the hassle out of hosting. It&#8217;s the same closed-source, feature-packed PE but managed by the ThingsBoard team. You get everything from the self-managed PE plus the convenience of cloud hosting. It&#8217;s subscription-based and covers hosting costs, making it a breeze to get started. Fancy a trial? Sign up <a href="https://thingsboard.cloud/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a> and take it for a spin.</p>



<p>The Professional Editions (both Self-managed and Cloud) come packed with advanced features that set them apart from the Community Edition. Here are some of them:</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/pe/user-guide/white-labeling/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Advanced White-Labeling</strong>:</a> Customize the look and feel of your platform to reflect your brand.</li>



<li><a previewlistener="true" href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/pe/user-guide/rbac/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Advanced RBAC</strong>:</a> Implement sophisticated role-based access control strategies to ensure enhanced security across your IoT ecosystem. </li>



<li><a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/user-guide/integrations/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Platform Integrations</strong>:</a> Seamlessly connect with external systems and services, enabling an interconnected IoT solution. </li>
</ul>



<p>To make things crystal clear, here&#8217;s a nifty chart showing the main differences between each edition:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-6 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1005" height="1024" data-id="3370" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Difference-CE-PE-Cloud-1-1005x1024.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3370" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Difference-CE-PE-Cloud-1-1005x1024.png 1005w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Difference-CE-PE-Cloud-1-294x300.png 294w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Difference-CE-PE-Cloud-1-768x783.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Difference-CE-PE-Cloud-1-1507x1536.png 1507w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Difference-CE-PE-Cloud-1-2010x2048.png 2010w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Difference-CE-PE-Cloud-1-512x522.png 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Difference-CE-PE-Cloud-1-1024x1044.png 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Difference-CE-PE-Cloud-1-920x938.png 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Difference-CE-PE-Cloud-1-1600x1631.png 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Difference-CE-PE-Cloud-1-1920x1957.png 1920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Difference-CE-PE-Cloud-1-1320x1345.png 1320w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Difference-CE-PE-Cloud-1.png 2355w" sizes="(max-width: 1005px) 100vw, 1005px" /></figure>
</figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Kickstarting Projects with Solution Templates <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f680.png" alt="🚀" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></h3>



<p>PE users gain out-of-the-box <a previewlistener="true" href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/pe/solution-templates/overview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">solution templates</a> designed to charge the implementation of common IoT scenarios. These templates provide a structured starting point, significantly reducing development time and effort.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Complementary Open Source Offerings <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f381.png" alt="🎁" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></h3>



<p>Both Community and Professional Edition users can take advantage of mobile applications developed on Flutter that keep you connected to your IoT platform anytime, anywhere. In addition to the core platform editions, ThingsBoard proudly offers other open-source products like the <a previewlistener="true" href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/iot-gateway/what-is-iot-gateway/">IoT Gateway</a> and <a previewlistener="true" href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/mqtt-broker/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">TBMQ</a>, further extending the capabilities of your IoT solutions.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Wrapping Up </h3>



<p>Whether you&#8217;re just dabbling in IoT or running a full-scale operation, ThingsBoard has an edition tailored for you. From the open-source Community Edition to the all-inclusive Professional Editions, the choice is yours. Still unsure? <a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/contact-us/">Reach out</a>, and we&#8217;ll help steer you in the right direction. Let&#8217;s make your IoT projects shine with ThingsBoard! ​</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Solving energy generation issues in solar farms using advanced analytics</title>
		<link>./../solving-energy-generation-issues-in-solar-farms-using-advanced-analytics-2-2/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../solving-energy-generation-issues-in-solar-farms-using-advanced-analytics-2-2/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Iryna Kheroim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 14:10:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=3442</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Description of the problem While working with many cases of our clients, we faced unusual problems in solar&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Description of the problem</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">While working with many cases of our clients, we faced unusual problems in solar farms. We decided to show you how it can be solved with the help of advanced analytics.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Solar farms are stations with a large working area, the frequent inspection of which is not financially profitable. That’s why companies conduct quarterly technical inspections on a schedule or in case of serious problems that can be noticed with the naked eye.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">However, many localized problems can significantly affect efficiency in the long run but cannot be noticed simply by comparing a few indicators. For example, the occurrence of corrosion on a solar panel will reduce the solar panel’s efficiency more and more every day. However, the production rate in this case will never reach 0, so primitive detectors will not report the problem. Based on this, the costs will reach from 10 to 40% of the electricity for each day from the string until the upcoming quarterly inspection. We talked more about them in the article about finding anomalies in solar power plants.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Knowing what these problems are and where they appear, it is only necessary to build the right search mechanism to answer the question: “In which segment of the solar plants did the error occur?”. In other words, it will tell not only about the problem’s existence but also about its location.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Usually, solar panels are located in approximately the same area, so they are all covered by the same conditions and usually have similar power generation, with a 4-5% difference. The reason for the fluctuation is that solar panels operate in uncontrolled environmental conditions. The power generation of solar panels may vary depending on the temperature, degree of pollution, and humidity, which may differ during the day for each solar panel separately.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="596" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Energy-generating-issues-diagnostics-2-1024x596.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3447" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Energy-generating-issues-diagnostics-2-1024x596.png 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Energy-generating-issues-diagnostics-2-300x174.png 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Energy-generating-issues-diagnostics-2-768x447.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Energy-generating-issues-diagnostics-2-1536x893.png 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Energy-generating-issues-diagnostics-2-2048x1191.png 2048w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Energy-generating-issues-diagnostics-2-512x298.png 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Energy-generating-issues-diagnostics-2-920x535.png 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Energy-generating-issues-diagnostics-2-1600x931.png 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Energy-generating-issues-diagnostics-2-1920x1117.png 1920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Energy-generating-issues-diagnostics-2-1320x768.png 1320w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Energy-generating-issues-diagnostics-2.png 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">Let’s consider the usual structure of solar power plants. Panels were connected to the inverter by strings. Data on energy production was collected from the inverter to which all these strings were connected.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">A simple manual review of the data or setting a threshold on indicators will not be enough to diagnose faults. That’s because power generation is non-linear and depends on many factors. That is why we need a tool that can adapt to the task. In our system, such a tool is Calculated Field. This tool allows you to get any useful information from your data, with access to all the necessary parameters and setting up the right logic.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">In our task, the desired information is energy underproduction. To find this indicator, we need to:</p>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px">Find how much a properly working line should produce.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">Understand the permissible deviation level from the energy production of a properly working indicator that we should set.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">A system that can constantly adjust to a non-constant deviation.</li>
</ul>



<p style="font-size:16px">To find how much energy we lose, we need to find how much a string with properly working panels should produce, that name reference value. Compared to the current string Electricity Production, finding the delta, which is the amount of energy underproduced, will be possible.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Observing the behavior of solar power plants, we concluded that it would be best to take the maximum power output of one string in the inverter like the reference value. The reason is that the strings with panels are located in the same zone and consist of devices of the same generation rate. As a result, the maximum value will deviate only slightly from the other values.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-7 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="617" data-id="3448" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Current-vs-Avg-hourly-inverter-1024x617.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3448" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Current-vs-Avg-hourly-inverter-1024x617.png 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Current-vs-Avg-hourly-inverter-300x181.png 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Current-vs-Avg-hourly-inverter-768x463.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Current-vs-Avg-hourly-inverter-1536x926.png 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Current-vs-Avg-hourly-inverter-2048x1234.png 2048w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Current-vs-Avg-hourly-inverter-512x309.png 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Current-vs-Avg-hourly-inverter-920x555.png 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Current-vs-Avg-hourly-inverter-1600x964.png 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Current-vs-Avg-hourly-inverter-1920x1157.png 1920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Current-vs-Avg-hourly-inverter-1320x796.png 1320w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Current-vs-Avg-hourly-inverter.png 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>
</figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">Next, we need to compare the energy production of each string with the reference value for this inverter. If the value has a difference of more than 10% from the reference, then it is considered that the string has problems with the undergeneration of energy.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">However, it is not enough to look at energy production at the moment to find the delta. A small cloud flying by or some garbage in the air that temporarily sticks to the panel can affect the string performance. Although the panels are working properly, this would be noted as a problem.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">That is why it is important to take the average value of energy production by one string for the entire sunny day.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">At the same time, not all the stuff that gets on the solar panel can be removed in one day. For example, sand from a localized gust of wind can hit individual strings, which will be diagnosed as a fault until it is washed away by rain or a cleaning system after a while. Calling a technical team to this line will be a waste of money. The way out of the situation is to set up an alert when the energy generation seems to be reduced for 3 days in a row.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-8 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="574" data-id="3449" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Test-calculation-simple-1024x574.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3449" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Test-calculation-simple-1024x574.png 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Test-calculation-simple-300x168.png 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Test-calculation-simple-768x430.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Test-calculation-simple-1536x861.png 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Test-calculation-simple-2048x1148.png 2048w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Test-calculation-simple-512x287.png 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Test-calculation-simple-920x516.png 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Test-calculation-simple-1600x897.png 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Test-calculation-simple-1920x1076.png 1920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Test-calculation-simple-1320x740.png 1320w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Test-calculation-simple.png 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>
</figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">By meeting all of these conditions, the system can perform constant recalculations in real-time, based on real data, sort it out, and send it in the form of a convenient report to the responsible person. And, of course, this is not the case with just one inverter but dozens and hundreds of inverters that are constantly providing new indicators.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">The availability of such a tool will reduce the cost of full diagnostics and make it possible to conduct local inspections. It will also provide an opportunity to find and solve problems quickly, which will increase the overall efficiency of the solar farm.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="summary">Summary</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">In conclusion, the use of advanced analytics in solar farms can greatly improve the efficiency of the system by detecting localized problems that simple indicators cannot notice. The proposed solution uses a flexible tool called Calculated Field, which allows for calculations based on formulas, metrics, and data. By finding the reference value and comparing the energy production of each string with it, the system can identify strings with under-generated energy. It is important to meet 3 conditions:</p>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px">The delta value must exceed 10%.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">The indicator should contain the arithmetic mean value for the entire sunny day</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">The indicator must exceed the specified limit for 3 days in a row.</li>
</ul>



<p style="font-size:16px">By meeting all of these conditions, the system can perform constant recalculations in real-time, based on real data, sort it out, and send it in the form of a convenient report to the responsible person. The availability of such a tool not only reduces the cost of full diagnostics but also makes it possible to conduct local inspections and solve problems in a short time, ultimately increasing the solar farm&#8217;s overall efficiency. With the help of advanced analytics and the Calculated Field tool, any business task can be accomplished given the necessary input data.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">In summary, we have explored how an advanced analytics platform can solve non-standard business problems.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Proper use of Calculated Fields, prediction capabilities, and anomaly diagnostics together will provide you with a flexible and very versatile tool that will help you customize most of the business aspects of your business.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../solving-energy-generation-issues-in-solar-farms-using-advanced-analytics-2-2/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Release 3.6.3 Announcement</title>
		<link>./../new-release-3-6-3-announcement/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../new-release-3-6-3-announcement/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dmytro Andriichenko]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 11:29:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Release]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=3392</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Inspired by the valuable feedback from our dedicated community and users, we are excited to announce the launch&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Inspired by the valuable feedback from our dedicated community and users, we are excited to announce the launch of Thingsboard version 3.6.3. This latest release is packed with innovations and enhancements that promise to enrich your IoT platform experience. Version 3.6.3 introduces new functionalities and focuses on streamlining existing processes, ensuring a seamless, more efficient operation for all ThingsBoard users. Embrace the advancements in IoT management and deployment that Version 3.6.3 brings to your toolkit.</p>



<p>This article will briefly describe the most interesting updates to our new features. You can find the full list of updates here.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Notifications to mobile application</h2>



<p>We are adding support for sending push notifications to mobile applications. This enhancement includes the ability to load Firebase service account credentials, revamp the dialog for creating notification templates and sending notifications, and allow for the customization of the push notification&#8217;s &#8220;subject&#8221; and &#8220;message&#8221;. This update aims to enhance mobile application interaction by directly providing timely and relevant notifications to users&#8217; devices.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Notifications-to-app.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3486"/></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Slider widget</h2>



<p>Added a &#8220;Slider widget&#8221; to ThingsBoard, offering a new UI element that allows for easy adjustment of values through a sliding mechanism. This enhancement is designed to improve user experience by providing a straightforward and intuitive way to input values, making it particularly useful for settings requiring precise control over various options.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Slider-widget.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3464"/></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Toggle button widget</h2>



<p>Added a &#8220;Toggle button widget&#8221; to ThingsBoard. This feature provides a graphical UI element that can be toggled on or off, enhancing user interaction and control within the dashboard. The implementation ensures that the widget is seamlessly integrated into the platform, offering a user-friendly option for managing binary states of devices or parameters. More information about this widget can be read here.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Toggle-button-widget.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3465"/></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Action button widget</h2>



<p>Added the &#8220;Action button widget&#8221; to ThingsBoard, enhancing the platform&#8217;s interactivity with a new user interface element that enables the execution of actions directly from the dashboard. This update aims to improve user engagement and operational efficiency by providing a straightforward mechanism for users to interact with devices or data processes. More information about this widget can be read here.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Action-button-widget.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3466"/></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Power button widget</h2>



<p>Added a &#8220;Power button widget&#8221; to ThingsBoard, further enhancing user interface customization options. This widget allows users to easily control the power states of devices directly from the dashboard, offering a practical and visually appealing method for device management. More information about this widget can be read here.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Power-button-widget.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3467"/></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Command button widget</h2>



<p>Added a &#8220;Command button widget&#8221; to ThingsBoard, which is aimed at enhancing the dashboard&#8217;s functionality by allowing users to execute specific commands directly from the UI. This addition is designed to streamline operations and improve the user experience by providing more interactive and dynamic widget options. More information about this widget can be read here.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Command-button-widget.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3468"/></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Single Switch control widget</h2>



<p>ThingsBoard introduces a Single &#8220;Switch control widget&#8221; designed to enhance user interaction by allowing straightforward control over device functionalities. This widget simplifies the process of toggling device states, offering an intuitive interface for users.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Single-Switch-control-widget.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3469"/></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Bar chart with labels</h2>



<p>We are implementing a new &#8220;Bar chart with labels&#8221; chart widget for ThingsBoard. This addition enriches the visualization options available on the platform, allowing for displaying bar charts accompanied by labels for clearer data presentation and analysis.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Bar-chart-with-labels-1.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3472"/></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../new-release-3-6-3-announcement/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Solving solar power plant problems using advanced analytics</title>
		<link>./../solving-solar-power-plant-problems-using-advanced-analytics-2/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../solving-solar-power-plant-problems-using-advanced-analytics-2/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Iryna Kheroim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 10:33:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=3387</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Solar energy is becoming increasingly popular as the world looks to resolve the climate emergency and move toward&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="font-size:16px">Solar energy is becoming increasingly popular as the world looks to resolve the climate emergency and move toward a greener future. However, solar farms face several energy-generating challenges, including operating and maintenance costs, soiling, performance degradation over time, security and intrusion detection, optimizing energy output, and grid integration challenges.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">To address these issues, they increasingly rely on advanced analytics to optimize their operations, monitor weather conditions, and raise maintenance processes. Here, we’ll explore the main challenges faced by solar panels, as well as options for solving them with the help of advanced analytics.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Threshold business analytics approaches cannot deal with the complexity of solar power plant data and the problems that arise. Predictive maintenance, forecasting, and anomaly detection will be the main tools for solving challenges. Solar farms adopting such smart analytics tools have already seen benefits like 12-15% gains in annual energy yield, 15-20% drops in cleaning and maintenance costs, and 30% reductions in power output volatility. By leveraging these tools, solar farms can significantly increase their overall efficiency, reduce downtime, and lower their overall cost of operation.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">The article aims to educate readers on the problems and the solutions to aid faster industry adoption of analytics. Continued efforts in this direction can help solar power advance strongly towards its promise of a brighter, cleaner energy future.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="solar-farm-structure">Solar Farm Structure</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">Solar farms consist of solar panels, wires, inverters, batteries, and a utility meter. Due to the design features, each of these areas must be in constantly changing conditions, which causes many problems that require a quick solution.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="574" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Solar-Farm-Structure-2-1024x574.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3389" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Solar-Farm-Structure-2-1024x574.png 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Solar-Farm-Structure-2-300x168.png 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Solar-Farm-Structure-2-768x430.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Solar-Farm-Structure-2-1536x861.png 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Solar-Farm-Structure-2-2048x1148.png 2048w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Solar-Farm-Structure-2-512x287.png 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Solar-Farm-Structure-2-920x516.png 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Solar-Farm-Structure-2-1600x897.png 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Solar-Farm-Structure-2-1920x1076.png 1920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Solar-Farm-Structure-2-1320x740.png 1320w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Solar-Farm-Structure-2.png 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">With the help of IoT technologies, we can take indicators that the analytics system can later store, process, and convert into previously unattainable parameters.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="understanding-the-difficulty-of-solving-challenges">Understanding the difficulty of solving challenges</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">Before identifying the main challenges, it is important to understand their complexity and difficulty. We have identified 3 main causes for the decrease in overall efficiency:</p>



<p style="font-size:16px"><strong>The first</strong>&nbsp;is the large number of important metrics that need to be collected for analysis. A solar farm consists of hundreds or even thousands of devices. Each of the devices has a bunch of different parameters that are important for monitoring efficiency. No matter how much we reduce and simplify the system, even a 5 MWh system will have over 10,000 panels. The panels are connected to many inverters and batteries. And they, in turn, are connected by many connections. Accordingly, the system contains a huge amount of data, which is important to operate within a pile.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px"><strong>The second</strong>&nbsp;is the instability of parameters due to changing weather conditions and the sensitivity of solar panels to external factors. This makes it impossible to identify patterns and set simple thresholds. A 15% drop in energy production may be due to a passing cloud rather than a breakdown, soiling, or misconfiguration. With parameters constantly shifting, spotting true problems becomes near impossible for standard threshold-based monitoring tools.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px"><strong>The third</strong>&nbsp;is the inability of humans to process large amounts of data in real-time to take action to improve the situation. But quick action is essential to maximize productivity. So, the system requires machine intervention when it comes to large arrays of constantly changing indicators.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">However, a mature advanced analytics system contains built-in instruments that can help us solve the challenges described. Here are a few of them:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="561" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/scheme-1-1024x561.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3434" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/scheme-1-1024x561.png 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/scheme-1-300x164.png 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/scheme-1-768x421.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/scheme-1-1536x842.png 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/scheme-1-2048x1122.png 2048w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/scheme-1-512x281.png 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/scheme-1-920x504.png 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/scheme-1-1600x877.png 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/scheme-1-1920x1052.png 1920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/scheme-1-1320x723.png 1320w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/scheme-1.png 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<ul>
<li></li>
</ul>



<p style="font-size:16px">So, advanced analytics can work with large amounts of data, find unusual patterns within it, and make the necessary decisions independently to achieve maximum efficiency.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Now that we understand the complexity of overcoming challenges and the tools that help solve them, we can proceed with a detailed overview of each challenge and possible solutions.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-main-challenges-in-solar-farms">The main challenges in solar farms</h4>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="operational-and-maintenance-costs">Operational and Maintenance Costs</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">One of the main challenges solar power plant owners face is the significant operation and maintenance costs associated with maintaining these facilities. The main reasons for high expenses are:</p>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px">Replacement or maintenance of faulty components</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">Panel cleaning</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">Equipment wear and tear</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">Labor costs</li>
</ul>



<p style="font-size:16px">Solar panels are sensitive to many environmental factors, such as temperature, humidity, dust in the air, and other environmental indicators that accumulate over time. Not only do they reduce energy production efficiency, but they also require frequent maintenance and cleaning, which increases overall operating costs.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Here are the most common issues with solar plants that accumulate over time: Delamination and Internal Corrosion, Electrical Issues, Hot Spots, PID Effect, Snail Trail Contamination, Overheating, Isolation Short-Circuit Fault, Inverter Does Not Restart, and MPPT.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">If you want to learn more about this topic, see a full description of the problems and their solutions using anomaly detection, and check out the detailed step-by-step&nbsp;<a href="./../optimizing-solar-parks-efficiency-advanced-anomaly-detection-solutions/index.html">guide here</a>.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Expenses such as these can account for up to 15-20% of the total annual cost of solar generation. Traditional maintenance practices often follow a fixed schedule, leading to inefficiencies, unnecessary downtime, and excessive operating costs.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Solar plant managers can use predictive analytics to foresee potential problems before they become costly downtime. This proactive approach minimizes the need for reactive or scheduled maintenance, optimizing the efficiency of the solar plant.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="soiling">Soiling</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">The accumulation of dust, dirt, grime, snow, sand deposits, and bird droppings on solar panels blocks incident sunlight to the cells and is a prime source of efficiency losses for solar farms.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Manual cleaning of soiled panels to restore generation is laborious and costly and only offers temporary respite against recurring soiling triggered by environmental or seasonal weather. The high frequency of cleaning needed for farms in specific locales also exponentially increases associated water usage and labor costs. Furthermore, traditional visual inspections for contamination suffer from inaccuracy due to limited manpower and subjective assessments that tend to underestimate early contamination.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Research shows soiling alone can lead to a staggering 7-30% decline in power generation for farms in deserts, near farms, highways, or colder regions. For instance, in some parts of the United States, the soiling rate can range from 0.03 to 0.15% per day, while in desert environments, the soiling loss can be as high as 0.5% per day. These generation gaps for solar farms with tens of thousands of panels placed in arrays covering different geographical regions lead to multimillion-dollar losses.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">The way to solve soiling on solar farms with advanced analytics is to use forecasting and comprehensive calculation of the costs of soiling. By finding the perfect balance between the cost of cleaning and the prediction of pollution losses, the system based on real-time data can create a cost-effective cleaning schedule for specific areas.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="573" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomaly-tasks-1024x573.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3451" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomaly-tasks-1024x573.png 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomaly-tasks-300x168.png 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomaly-tasks-768x429.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomaly-tasks-1536x859.png 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomaly-tasks-2048x1145.png 2048w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomaly-tasks-512x286.png 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomaly-tasks-920x514.png 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomaly-tasks-1600x895.png 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomaly-tasks-1920x1074.png 1920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomaly-tasks-1320x738.png 1320w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomaly-tasks.png 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">The system can provide a comprehensive report based on actual data, offering an overview of the solar farm’s condition and details about the optimal time for cleaning the solar panels. Additionally, the system can control the activation and deactivation of the nozzles or any other automated cleaning system at the most suitable time.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">If you want to learn more about the topic, check out the detailed step-by-step guide covering the topic of “Soiling” in Solar Farms. To read it,&nbsp;<a previewlistener="true" href="./../reducing-costs-of-solar-farms-by-optimizing-the-cleaning-process/index.html">click here</a>.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="performance-degradation-over-time">Performance degradation over time</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">Another problem faced by solar power plant owners is the progressive degradation of generating capacity over the lifetime of a plant, which spans decades.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">The long-term impact of natural factors, such as solar radiation, moisture, thermal cycles, and mechanical loads, leads to slow wear and tear of components over many years. Delamination, color change, hot spots, and microcracks in the panels lead to an annual drop in conversion efficiency and electrical output of 0.5-1%.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">For a 100 MWh solar power plant, over 25 years of operation, this steady degradation leads to a 10-20% net drop in electricity generation, which means millions in lost profits. Owners also face uncertainty in accurately predicting the degradation trajectories of equipment of different ages located at different sites. False estimates lead to revenue losses due to inaccurate power sales contracts.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="643" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Heart-map-1024x643.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3438" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Heart-map-1024x643.png 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Heart-map-300x188.png 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Heart-map-768x482.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Heart-map-1536x964.png 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Heart-map-2048x1285.png 2048w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Heart-map-512x321.png 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Heart-map-920x577.png 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Heart-map-1600x1004.png 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Heart-map-1920x1205.png 1920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Heart-map-1320x828.png 1320w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Heart-map.png 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">Moreover, solar panels do not only degrade over time. The connection elements, inverters, batteries, and performance monitoring sensors lose effectiveness over time. It should also be noted that because the equipment is open to unplanned complete failure, solar farms may require short- and medium-term replacements.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">However, at the same time, we should keep in mind that electricity generation on solar farms is unstable. Therefore, it is not possible to tell the difference between changes in weather conditions and degradation by setting thresholds or simply looking at the indicators.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Advanced analytics allows us to identify long-term and short-term degradation, thus solving this problem. In addition, understanding when the best time to reinvest in equipment replacement is an advantage that will help you maintain the highest possible return on your investment over time.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">The system constantly checks indicators from many parts of the solar power plant, making it possible to track the overall condition and degradation of individual areas. Not only is it possible to calculate, but accurate degradation monitoring will help avoid revenue losses caused by unpredictable degradation.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="security-and-intrusion-detection">Security and Intrusion Detection</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">Solar power plants are often located in remote locations and are large installations covering large areas. Therefore, expensive equipment such as inverters and solar panels face significant security and intrusion risks from external intruders. These risks can take many forms, causing huge financial and operational losses.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Theft and vandalism are common, with thieves attempting to steal valuable copper wiring and hackers tampering with energy infrastructure, causing power outages. Natural disasters such as forest fires, storms, and floods also create problems that threaten fencing, cables, and monitoring infrastructure. Additional risks, such as unauthorized access to control rooms or electrical sites through broken gates, also create security risks.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Without reliable monitoring tools, these threats often go undetected for long periods, allowing attackers to cause significant damage. Even traditional legacy security systems, such as motion detectors and surveillance cameras, have blind spots where cunning attackers can bypass detection. Patrolling security also offers inconsistent protection based on a large geography. The lack of real-time context also makes threat response ineffective.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Modern analytics platforms offer comprehensive coverage, analysis, and tools to protect solar power plants better. Sensor data analytics can dynamically monitor multi-factor threats. Algorithms can detect anomalies that indicate potential perimeter breaches. Smart cameras or drones can also detect intruder signals and send alerts to dispatchers faster. The information obtained from the cameras and drones can work in conjunction with other data from the solar farm, giving access to almost complete control over the security of the solar farm. Based on historical data from past interventions, you can build the best strategy to eliminate interference in the future.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="optimizing-energy-output">Optimizing Energy Output</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">Solar power plants face the challenge of optimizing energy production due to inconsistent access to their main fuel &#8211; sunlight. The energy output changes during the day depending on the sun’s intensity and between days depending on the changing weather conditions.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Complex factors such as cloud cover, temperature, humidity, dust, and vegetation growth also dynamically affect the irradiance falling on the panels.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Starting with potential fines for under-delivery of electricity under power purchase agreements and ending with the impossibility of profitably participating in spot electricity markets based on the fact that there is too much energy to store in batteries of the available capacity. That is why it is important to use complex calculations and forecasts to find the projected energy production for the coming days.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="640" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Consumption-forecast-1-1024x640.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3440" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Consumption-forecast-1-1024x640.png 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Consumption-forecast-1-300x188.png 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Consumption-forecast-1-768x480.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Consumption-forecast-1-1536x960.png 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Consumption-forecast-1-2048x1280.png 2048w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Consumption-forecast-1-512x320.png 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Consumption-forecast-1-920x575.png 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Consumption-forecast-1-1600x1000.png 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Consumption-forecast-1-1920x1200.png 1920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Consumption-forecast-1-1320x825.png 1320w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Consumption-forecast-1.png 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">Advanced analytics allows you to detect generation problems by detecting anomalies or forecast problems by predicting them and triggering preventive, corrective actions to eliminate them. The analytical system can also analyze on a minute-by-minute basis whether it is better to take energy from batteries, solar panels, or the system, thus optimizing electricity bills. Such an automated system can significantly reduce electricity bills for households/factories and maximize profits for solar farms.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">If you want to learn more about how to solve non-standard tasks and complex calculations using advanced analytics,&nbsp;<a href="./../solving-energy-generation-issues-in-solar-farms-using-advanced-analytics/index.html">click here</a>.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="grid-integration-challenge">Grid Integration Challenge</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">The volatility of solar generation, which is dependent on weather conditions, creates significant challenges for grid integration. Solar energy production changes rapidly depending on cloud cover and time of day, causing voltage and frequency fluctuations for utilities if not appropriately handled. For grids with a high penetration of solar facilities, this variable generation, if increased, can challenge the stability and reliability of the grid.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">There are 3 types of system connection to the grid: distributed systems (off-grid), centralized energy (on-grid), and hybrid systems.</p>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px">Distributed generation is small solar photovoltaic panels (usually from 5 to 500 kilowatts) installed on residential or commercial properties, and solar panels satisfy the main demand for electricity.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">Centralized generation is large centralized solar parks, usually with a capacity of hundreds of megawatts, which are connected to the power grid via high-voltage power lines. The main difference between off-grid and on-grid systems is that in centralized power generation, all the energy produced goes from the panels to an inverter, which is converted into alternating current and sent almost directly to the utility grid. In a distributed generation, the energy is stored in batteries and used by a residential or commercial facility as needed.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">Hybrid generation differs because it contains batteries and can power a local building and connect to the utility grid.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2409" height="1704" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/On-Grid-Off-Grid-and-Hybrid-Solar-Systems.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3390" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/On-Grid-Off-Grid-and-Hybrid-Solar-Systems.png 2409w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/On-Grid-Off-Grid-and-Hybrid-Solar-Systems-300x212.png 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/On-Grid-Off-Grid-and-Hybrid-Solar-Systems-1024x724.png 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/On-Grid-Off-Grid-and-Hybrid-Solar-Systems-768x543.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/On-Grid-Off-Grid-and-Hybrid-Solar-Systems-1536x1086.png 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/On-Grid-Off-Grid-and-Hybrid-Solar-Systems-2048x1449.png 2048w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/On-Grid-Off-Grid-and-Hybrid-Solar-Systems-512x362.png 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/On-Grid-Off-Grid-and-Hybrid-Solar-Systems-920x651.png 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/On-Grid-Off-Grid-and-Hybrid-Solar-Systems-1600x1132.png 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/On-Grid-Off-Grid-and-Hybrid-Solar-Systems-1920x1358.png 1920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/On-Grid-Off-Grid-and-Hybrid-Solar-Systems-1320x934.png 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 2409px) 100vw, 2409px" /></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">Problems such as voltage spikes, protection discoordination, phase distortion, and unexpected voltage drops can occur when solar power exhibits instability and unpredictability.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Without effective climate change adaptation, problems range from nuisances like flickering lights to catastrophic large-scale blackouts due to cascading power line failures. The economic costs of unreliable renewable generation also reduce investor confidence in further expanding solar power to meet decarbonization goals.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Predictive forecasting combined with optimization for unexpected situations provides actionable information about the future variability of solar generation. Grid operators can take proactive steps to redirect generators, limit the capacity of solar power plants, or deploy batteries to smooth out fluctuations. Real-time anomaly detection also continuously monitors any new equipment limitations or stability risks.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Optimized algorithms prescribe ideal storage vs generation decisions hourly when combined with predictive modeling of dynamic electricity spot prices. Over a year, farms have achieved as much as 5-7% upside in annual revenues besides minimizing deviation penalties.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="first-steps-to-solving-problems">First steps to solving problems</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">We realized which problems occur in solar panels. We understood how to solve them with the help of advanced analytics. So finally, let’s define an action plan on how to make it happen with the help of the ThingsBoard IoT platform and Trendz for advanced analytics:</p>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px">Collect data from the solar farm site into an IoT platform for processing. Most equipment is capable of&nbsp;<a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/user-guide/integrations/">reporting data using Modbus, MQTT, HTTP protocols</a>, or&nbsp;<a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/iot-gateway/what-is-iot-gateway/">gateway data loggers</a>. We need to collect the following information: 
<ul>
<li>Data from weather stations &#8211; solar irradiance, temperature, humidity, etc</li>



<li>Metrics from Inverters &#8211; input and output voltage, current, frequency, etc.</li>



<li>Metrics from solar panels or Strings &#8211; voltage, operating time, panel temperature, panel orientation, etc.</li>



<li>Metrics from batteries or energy storage systems &#8211; voltage and current, state of charge, temperature, etc.</li>



<li>Information from energy meters and grid &#8211; real-time energy flow, power quality data, grid demand response, etc.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">Set up a monitoring dashboard in the IoT platform that will&nbsp;<a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/user-guide/dashboards/">visualize collected data in real-time</a>.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px"><a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/trendz/calculated-fields/">Configure computation of </a><a href="http://10.7.3.196:4000/docs/trendz/calculated-fields/">system-level metrics / KPIs</a>&nbsp;that would describe overall system behavior.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px"><a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/trendz/anomaly/anomaly-detection-overview/">Train anomaly detection model on historical data</a>&nbsp;to identify abnormal component behavior or equipment misconfiguration. Enable real-time anomaly detection for all on-site equipment.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px"><a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/trendz/guide/predict-next-maintenance-date-of-equipment/">Configure predictive maintenance models</a>&nbsp;that would forecast potential issues in the future and compute equipment health scores.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px"><a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/user-guide/alarms/">Set up Alerting and notification rules</a>&nbsp;to trigger automated corrective actions or&nbsp;<a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/user-guide/notifications/">notify staff about discovered incidents</a>.</li>
</ul>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="conclusions">Conclusions</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">Solar farms, due to their design factor, have a large number of challenges that require constant intervention and monitoring of the overall condition of the farm. The main challenges are operating and maintenance costs, soiling, performance degradation over time, security and intrusion detection, optimizing energy output, and grid integration challenges.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Effectively handling these challenges is the basis for the high efficiency of a solar farm.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">However, manual reading of indicators or setting thresholds is not enough for power plants with unstable energy production. Using advanced analytics will open up new horizons of efficiency and reliability for your solar farm. The future looks bright for the partnership between solar and advanced analytics!</p>




]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../solving-solar-power-plant-problems-using-advanced-analytics-2/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Optimizing solar parks efficiency &#8211; advanced anomaly detection solutions</title>
		<link>./../optimizing-solar-parks-efficiency-advanced-anomaly-detection-solutions-2/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../optimizing-solar-parks-efficiency-advanced-anomaly-detection-solutions-2/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Iryna Kheroim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 15:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=3316</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Solar power plants face issues due to temperature and environmental factors, which lead to reduced efficiency and potential&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="font-size:16px">Solar power plants face issues due to temperature and environmental factors, which lead to reduced efficiency and potential major breakdowns if not addressed quickly. The challenge is that monitoring tools like drones, digital multimeters, and infrared cameras are costly, making regular checks infrequent, which does not allow quick responses to problems. This means that if a problem arises after a maintenance check, electricity production efficiency will fall, leading to significant losses.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px"><strong>The ability to quickly respond to problems</strong>&nbsp;is what plants with constant energy production need.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">One of the ways to achieve a quick response to problems is through the use of anomaly detection. Using this method provides an opportunity to respond to problems quickly and significantly reduces the spending on third-party equipment.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="574" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/The-ability-to-quickly-respond-to-problems-1024x574.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3367" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/The-ability-to-quickly-respond-to-problems-1024x574.png 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/The-ability-to-quickly-respond-to-problems-300x168.png 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/The-ability-to-quickly-respond-to-problems-768x430.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/The-ability-to-quickly-respond-to-problems-1536x861.png 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/The-ability-to-quickly-respond-to-problems-2048x1148.png 2048w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/The-ability-to-quickly-respond-to-problems-512x287.png 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/The-ability-to-quickly-respond-to-problems-920x516.png 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/The-ability-to-quickly-respond-to-problems-1600x897.png 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/The-ability-to-quickly-respond-to-problems-1920x1076.png 1920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/The-ability-to-quickly-respond-to-problems-1320x740.png 1320w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/The-ability-to-quickly-respond-to-problems.png 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">Anomaly detection is a technique to identify patterns or events deviating from the norm. In the context of a solar farm, this can involve monitoring various factors, such as Real-time Energy Output, Power Generation Trends, Solar Irradiance, and Temperature for Solar Panels. Also Output Voltage and Current, Frequency, Efficiency, Temperature for Inverter. By analyzing this data, anomaly detection algorithms can identify unusual patterns or events that may indicate problems before they can do any damage to the solar panel or inverter. In other words, we look for a problem not when we see that energy is produced less than expected for the second day in a row but right at the moment when the problem appeared.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">But, unusual patterns are not just deviations of parameters from the norm.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Unusual patterns are combinations of parameters that are not expected but which identify potential problems. They are discovered by analyzing historical data collected from solar panels and inverters. During this analysis, we focus not only on individual parameter values but on a combination of values because it potentially gives more insights into system behavior. Based on this, it is possible to find current problems and predict future ones.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">A person cannot cope with the calculations of such data arrays. That is why we need advanced analytics with machine learning capabilities to analyze historical data and find unusual patterns in real-time.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Now, we will show how to configure Trends Analytics for correct anomaly detection. However, before that, let’s consider what types of anomalies occur in Solar Farms.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="overview-of-common-anomalies-in-equipment-of-solar-power-plants">Overview of common anomalies in the equipment of solar power plants</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">The most widespread and important problems for us are those with solar panels and inverters since these are the first frontier of obtaining energy. Therefore, we will look for anomalies in these parts of the power plant.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="anomalies-in-photovoltaic-modules">Anomalies in photovoltaic modules</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">Below, the most common breakdowns in PV modules and solar panels, which can be quickly and economically solved if they are dealt with immediately, will be described.<br><br>Most of them are formed on separate panels, so a drop in the indicators of one panel in contrast to another will indicate a breakdown. You can find each of them by finding anomalies in the Output Electricity (voltage and current) and Power Production indicators from the solar panel.</p>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px"><strong>Soiling:</strong> Soiling refers to the accumulation of dirt, dust, bird droppings, or other materials on the surface of solar panels. This layer of grime can significantly reduce the panels’ ability to absorb sunlight, leading to decreased electricity production.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px"><strong>Shading:</strong>&nbsp;Shading occurs when an object, such as a tree, building, or another solar panel, casts a shadow on a solar panel. This can lead to a reduction in the panel’s electricity production. Prolonged shadowing can lead to an imbalance in the solar panel system and may cause hot spots or reduce the overall lifespan of the panel.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px"><strong>Delamination and Internal Corrosion:</strong>&nbsp;Moisture can find its way into the panel, causing internal corrosion, if the panels are not keeping out air and water and all the solar panel components are not laminated correctly.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">Identifying and Addressing Solar Panel Anomalies Faulty wiring, loose connections, corrosion, and oxidation can interfere with electricity production.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px"><strong>Hot Spots:</strong>&nbsp;Badly-soldered connections can cause low resistance in the part of the panel that receives the power generated by the cell, leading to a hotspot in the soldered points and/or a cell. This phenomenon can ultimately lead to a short circuit, reducing the performance and lifespan of the PV panel.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px"><strong>PID Effect:</strong>&nbsp;Potential-induced degradation (PID) can cause an ongoing reduction in performance and accelerated aging of the PV panel. PID occurs when the voltage potential between the solar cells and the grounded frame of the panel causes a leakage current that can damage the cells.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px"><strong>Snail Trail Contamination:</strong>&nbsp;Snail trail contamination is a phenomenon where a white or grayish residue appears on the surface of the solar panel. This residue can reduce the performance of the panel and is caused by the release of silicone from the panel’s encapsulant material.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="1024" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-photovoltaic-modules-1024x1024.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3404" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-photovoltaic-modules-1024x1024.png 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-photovoltaic-modules-300x300.png 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-photovoltaic-modules-150x150.png 150w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-photovoltaic-modules-768x768.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-photovoltaic-modules-1536x1536.png 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-photovoltaic-modules-2048x2048.png 2048w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-photovoltaic-modules-148x148.png 148w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-photovoltaic-modules-296x296.png 296w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-photovoltaic-modules-512x512.png 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-photovoltaic-modules-920x920.png 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-photovoltaic-modules-1600x1600.png 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-photovoltaic-modules-1920x1920.png 1920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-photovoltaic-modules-1320x1320.png 1320w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-photovoltaic-modules.png 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="tackling-anomalies-in-inverters">Tackling Anomalies in Inverters</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">Inverters are a very important link of a solar power plant, a breakdown of which can lead to the shutdown of the entire power plant. This can have a critical impact on the total efficiency and profitability of the power plant.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">You can observe the operation of the inverter by following the indicators Output Voltage and Current, Frequency, Efficiency, and Temperature.</p>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px"><strong>Overheating:</strong>&nbsp;Inverters are sensitive to temperature, and high temperatures can reduce production and potentially a stoppage altogether if overheating occurs as the maximum operating temperature is reached. To prevent overheating, it is important to keep the switch cabinet and the area where the inverter is located well-ventilated, along with the inclusion of cleaning dust filters that can prevent any issues impeding airflow. You can monitor this problem with the help of indicators Temperature, Output Voltage, and Current.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px"><strong>Isolation Short-Circuit Fault:</strong>&nbsp;If there is too much moisture or damage to the cabling sleeves, then an isolation short-circuit fault can occur, whereby the inverter will report an “isolation alarm”. In this scenario, the solar inverter will either work at the minimum “required” isolation level or stop working altogether. You can monitor this problem with the help of indicators Efficiency, Output Voltage, and Current.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px"><strong>Inverter Does Not Restart:</strong>&nbsp;Inverters sometimes fail to restart after a power outage. Various factors, including a faulty inverter, a tripped circuit breaker, or a blown fuse, can cause this. You can monitor this problem with the help of indicators Frequency, and Efficiency.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px"><strong>Maximum Power Point Tracking (MPPT) Module:</strong>&nbsp;The MPPT module is responsible for tracking the maximum power point of the solar panel array. If the MPPT module fails, the inverter cannot convert the DC electricity generated by the solar panels into AC electricity. You can monitor this problem with the help of indicators Temperature, Output Voltage, and Current.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="561" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-Inverters-1-1024x561.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3412" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-Inverters-1-1024x561.png 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-Inverters-1-300x164.png 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-Inverters-1-768x421.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-Inverters-1-1536x842.png 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-Inverters-1-2048x1122.png 2048w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-Inverters-1-512x281.png 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-Inverters-1-920x504.png 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-Inverters-1-1600x877.png 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-Inverters-1-1920x1052.png 1920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-Inverters-1-1320x723.png 1320w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Anomalies-in-Inverters-1.png 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="summary">Summary</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">Efficiency challenges in solar farm operations demand a proactive approach to problem-solving, particularly in the context of scheduled diagnostics and high equipment maintenance costs. Anomaly detection emerges as a cost-effective solution, leveraging historical data to identify deviations in parameters like Real-time Energy Output, Power Generation Trends, and Temperature for Solar Panels, along with Output Voltage, Current, Frequency, and Efficiency for Inverters. This approach helps quickly find current problems and predict future issues, which is important for keeping the energy production going without any interruptions.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">To implement this approach, an efficient strategy involves creating anomaly detection models based on historical telemetry data, configuring real-time anomaly detection, and providing a comprehensive dashboard for the maintenance team. This ensures a streamlined process from anomaly identification to resolution, utilizing Trendz Analytics to enhance solar farm efficiency by minimizing downtime, reducing operational costs, and optimizing long-term performance.</p>



<ul>
<li></li>
</ul>



<p style="font-size:16px">And this is only part of how advanced analytics and machine learning can improve the efficiency of solar farms. With help, you can find solutions to your solar farm problems, including Soiling, Battery Health Diagnostics, and more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../optimizing-solar-parks-efficiency-advanced-anomaly-detection-solutions-2/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reducing costs of solar farms by optimizing the cleaning process</title>
		<link>./../reducing-costs-of-solar-farms-by-optimizing-the-cleaning-process/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../reducing-costs-of-solar-farms-by-optimizing-the-cleaning-process/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Iryna Kheroim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 15:09:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=2957</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Introduction For solar farms, dirty panels can mean thousands of dollars of lost revenue annually. Panels washed too&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="introduction">Introduction</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">For solar farms, dirty panels can mean thousands of dollars of lost revenue annually. Panels washed too early or too late – are costs that make up a serious portion of the power plant’s profitability.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">In one of our cases, we worked with a Spanish company, a producer of electricity. They owned a solar power plant with a capacity of 10 MW. They will produce about $260,000 worth of energy per month in ideal conditions. However, the company lost over a fifth of its energy due to soiling problems. In turn, the cost of the cleaning cycle was $50,000. Calculating the losses, it was clear that cleaning on a fixed schedule was showing poor results.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="574" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Reducing-costs-of-Solar-Farms-2-1024x574.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3420" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Reducing-costs-of-Solar-Farms-2-1024x574.png 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Reducing-costs-of-Solar-Farms-2-300x168.png 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Reducing-costs-of-Solar-Farms-2-768x430.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Reducing-costs-of-Solar-Farms-2-1536x861.png 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Reducing-costs-of-Solar-Farms-2-2048x1148.png 2048w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Reducing-costs-of-Solar-Farms-2-512x287.png 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Reducing-costs-of-Solar-Farms-2-920x516.png 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Reducing-costs-of-Solar-Farms-2-1600x897.png 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Reducing-costs-of-Solar-Farms-2-1920x1076.png 1920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Reducing-costs-of-Solar-Farms-2-1320x740.png 1320w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Reducing-costs-of-Solar-Farms-2.png 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">To get the best possible results, you need to be sure of 3 steps:</p>



<ol>
<li style="font-size:16px">We have to find the energy losses</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">We need to know the forecast for electricity losses.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">You need to find the best time for the cleaning cycle.</li>
</ol>



<p style="font-size:16px">The key to solving all these questions is advanced analytics. A correctly configured system, like an expert, automatically decides what to do based on real-time and forecasted data and can manage the entire cleaning cycle, from collecting information to turning on the irrigation system or calling a group of cleaners without outside intervention.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Using IoT sensors to track real-time solar generation data, our solution provides actionable intelligence to optimize your cleaning schedule. Here’s how it works:</p>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px">Sensors are installed to monitor energy production from individual panels. This allows precise tracking of solar output over time.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">Advanced analytics calculate expected energy generation based on weather conditions and other variables. The difference between expected and available energy generation is considered energy loss.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">Our algorithm evaluates the cost of cleaning against potential energy savings. It forecasts lost revenue accrued each day panels remain dirty.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">When the value of regained energy outweighs cleaning expenses, the system automatically alerts owners it’s time to wash or turn off/on the cleaning system.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">Targeted cleanings restore generation at the optimal moment. You have the opportunity to adjust the cleaning schedule based on the economic feasibility of your decisions.</li>
</ul>



<p style="font-size:16px">Customers using our solar IoT solution have increased generation by 5-15% while reducing cleaning costs by up to 40%. Solar assets stay active at peak efficiency by timing cleanings precisely when needed.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="effective-solar-panel-cleaning-how-to-optimize-solar-panel-cleaning-schedule">Effective Solar Panel Cleaning. How to optimize Solar Panel cleaning schedule</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">Our approach to solving this problem is based on Soiling cost calculation.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Soiling costs are the losses you will incur if you clean your station on this day. This indicator consists of&nbsp;<strong>the cost of cleaning</strong> for a 10 MW plant, which is approximately $50,000,&nbsp;<strong>the sum of all losses</strong>&nbsp;due to pollution, and all this is divided by the number of&nbsp;<strong>days</strong>&nbsp;since the last cleaning.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">The indicator drops – good because our costs are decreasing. The indicator starts to rise – you need to wash the panels because the current costs are at their lowest point and then will constantly grow, and that is exactly the point when cleaning is economically feasible. As we can see in the table, in the dry period, when the loss indicators are only growing, the 5th week is the best time to carry out the cleaning cycle because compared to cleaning in any other week, the price is the lowest.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-9 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="669" data-id="3423" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Soiling-cost-calculation-1024x669.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3423" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Soiling-cost-calculation-1024x669.png 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Soiling-cost-calculation-300x196.png 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Soiling-cost-calculation-768x502.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Soiling-cost-calculation-1536x1004.png 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Soiling-cost-calculation-2048x1339.png 2048w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Soiling-cost-calculation-512x335.png 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Soiling-cost-calculation-920x601.png 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Soiling-cost-calculation-1600x1046.png 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Soiling-cost-calculation-1920x1255.png 1920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Soiling-cost-calculation-1320x863.png 1320w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Soiling-cost-calculation.png 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>
</figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">That is why we need to set up an IoT system with advanced analytics to optimize the cleaning schedule based on the historical data from the solar plant, the production forecast, and the metrics we explained in this section.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="summary">Summary</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">Solar power plants have many advantages, but due to their novelty, they also have many disadvantages. One of the most common is overspending based on pollution. This is a problem that cannot be eliminated, so the goal – is to minimize losses. Using IoT technologies and advanced analytics, you can easily monitor and wash solar panels at exactly the point in time when cleaning is economically feasible.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Analytics, IoT, and machine learning provide insights, risk forecasts, and data-driven decisions for better business performance. Embracing these ensures competitiveness and risk mitigation. Also, in the future, we plan to tell you how to improve the efficiency of the power plant by finding anomalies in the solar panels and parts of the power plant, such as the inverter or the battery. In our digital age, advanced analytics are the way to simplify and boost complex problem-solving!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../reducing-costs-of-solar-farms-by-optimizing-the-cleaning-process/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reliable T&#038;H monitoring with WhereView &#038; ThingsBoard</title>
		<link>./../reliable-th-monitoring-with-whereview-thingsboard-2/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../reliable-th-monitoring-with-whereview-thingsboard-2/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Doan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 12:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=3188</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Reliable and high-quality control of temperature and humidity with constant access to monitoring data is an important condition for the storage of thermosensitive drugs and raw materials for medicines. The ThingsBoard partner — Vypin together with our team has implemented a solution for a global pharmaceutical company. The IoT application has helped to optimize processes and costs.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="font-size:16px">Reliable and high-quality control of temperature and humidity with constant access to monitoring data is an important condition for the storage of thermosensitive drugs and raw materials for medicines. The ThingsBoard partner — <a href="http://vypin.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Vypin</a>, together with our team, has implemented a solution for a global pharmaceutical company. The IoT application has helped to optimize processes and costs.</p>



<div style="height:16px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/5.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3225"/></figure>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">The problem</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">The FDA (The Food &amp; Drug Administration) has strict requirements and recommendations for pharmaceutical manufacturers, particularly regarding storage conditions and the control system to comply with these conditions (more about regulation can be found here). The customer asked  Vypin to replace the current system. The previous one didn’t meet the FDA standards, which was the reason for the fines and the potential risk of drug or component damage.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">As they say in the medical field, the patient had specific complaints. First of all, data loss. Existing devices could go offline for various reasons (from network outages to power loss), but the transmission or recording of telemetry did not take place. But the client couldn’t find out about these or those losses, which was the second complaint. The current system does not provide a notification mechanism. In addition, monitoring data was not available remotely.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p class="is-style-cs-about" style="font-size:16px">Round-the-clock rotation of operators to control the temperature and humidity in the warehouse indeed is not the best solution. Therefore, in the regular automatic reports related to the storage environment state there were gaps in the tables and graphs. The FDA fines for such violations.</p>
<cite>Customer officer says</cite></blockquote>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-left">Solution</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">To solve the problem, the Vypin team proposed an integrated Vypin-Whereview system (powered by ThingsBoard). The company built a wireless network, installed sensors and gateways</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">If we mention one of the first problems (data loss), the new sensors now had a memory module and could record telemetry locally. When the gateway connection was lost, data loss (!) didn’t and doesn’t occur. When the online gateway returns, it picks up the accumulated telemetry and sends it to Whereview.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2409" height="1353" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3223" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8.png 2409w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-300x168.png 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-1024x575.png 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-768x431.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-1536x863.png 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-2048x1150.png 2048w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-512x288.png 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-920x517.png 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-1600x899.png 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-1920x1078.png 1920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-1320x741.png 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 2409px) 100vw, 2409px" /></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">The application, built on TB, solved the rest of the customer&#8217;s problems. First, the client&#8217;s responsible employee gets access to the monitoring data at any time. Managers also received access.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="587" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-1024x587.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3228" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-1024x587.png 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-300x172.png 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-768x440.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-1536x880.png 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-2048x1173.png 2048w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-512x293.png 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-920x527.png 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-1600x917.png 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-1920x1100.png 1920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-1320x756.png 1320w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6.png 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">To see the Dashboard with graphs and tables, it is enough to open the corresponding tab in your own browser and log in.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">It makes sense to highlight that based on the rule engine and device profiles, Vypin set up a notification system. In case of violations of the specified conditions (for example, exceeding the temperature thresholds), notifications are received by those who should be aware of this recorded violation. This allows you to respond instantly and even take preventive measures.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-left">Result </h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">Everyone understands that it is better (easier, cheaper, less time-consuming) to prevent a disease than to treat it. With the new warehouse monitoring system, the client (patient) has the opportunity for prevention.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../reliable-th-monitoring-with-whereview-thingsboard-2/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Increasing equipment utilization KPIs with the help of advanced analytics</title>
		<link>./../increasing-equipment-utilization-kpis-with-the-help-of-advanced-analytics-2/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Iryna Kheroim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 11:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=3147</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Introduction&#160; Equipment in production plays an important role in achieving maximum efficiency, quality, and payback. The issues that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Introduction&nbsp;</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">Equipment in production plays an important role in achieving maximum efficiency, quality, and payback. The issues that are key to optimizing the use of equipment are:</p>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px">Underutilization of Equipment</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">Ineffective Production Scheduling</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">Excessive Wear and Tear on Machinery</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">Operational Bottlenecks</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">Suboptimal Maintenance Scheduling</li>



<li style="font-size:16px">Misaligned Capacity Planning</li>
</ul>



<p style="font-size:16px">Solving these problems requires constant monitoring of equipment utilization and performance metrics. As production output increases, manufacturers may need to partially or completely change their equipment maintenance strategies and schedules to maintain efficiency. Unfortunately, these problems cannot be solved once and for all. But it also means that we can endlessly improve the optimization process.&nbsp;</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">That is why having the most up-to-date data is important when choosing an optimization strategy. Previously, with the help of logging, you could see how the equipment worked at the end of the day or week. With the growth of technology and the help of IoT devices, we can receive raw data in real-time. With advanced analytics, you can turn raw data into meaningful reports and predict future equipment behavior using machine learning models.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Equipment Utilization</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">To understand the overall condition of the equipment, you need to operate with a significant number of KPIs. We have divided KPIs by the problems they solve:</p>



<p style="font-size:16px"><em>Underutilization of Equipment and Operational Bottlenecks</em></p>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px">Production Output &#8211; A numerical or quality indicator of the useful action performed by the equipment. The information is collected using counters, scales, or quality sensors transmitted via the network to the ThingsBoard. The data does not require any additional processing.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2409" height="1515" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-production-output-1.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3192" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-production-output-1.png 2409w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-production-output-1-300x189.png 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-production-output-1-1024x644.png 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-production-output-1-768x483.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-production-output-1-1536x966.png 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-production-output-1-2048x1288.png 2048w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-production-output-1-512x322.png 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-production-output-1-920x579.png 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-production-output-1-1600x1006.png 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-production-output-1-1920x1207.png 1920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-production-output-1-1320x830.png 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 2409px) 100vw, 2409px" /></figure>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px">Equipment Utilization Rate &#8211; measures the degree to which equipment is utilized over a period compared to its full potential or capacity. Production Output is taken as the current capacity indicator. The maximum capacity is set according to the technical documentation. The indicator is calculated by an analytics system that finds the ratio of Production Output to Maximum Capacity in real-time.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="3212" height="1980" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3197" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3.png 3212w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3-300x185.png 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3-1024x631.png 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3-768x473.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3-1536x947.png 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3-2048x1262.png 2048w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3-512x316.png 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3-920x567.png 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3-1600x986.png 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3-3200x1973.png 3200w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3-1920x1184.png 1920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Equipment-Utilization-Rate-3-1320x814.png 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 3212px) 100vw, 3212px" /></figure>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px">Percentage of defects &#8211; The number of defects concerning the Production Output. Defective products are automatically detected using computer vision, ultrasonic or X-ray inspection, or by using manual inspection. The advanced analytics system calculates it in real-time by comparing the number of defective products to the manufactured product.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="638" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Precentage-of-Defects-2-1024x638.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3200" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Precentage-of-Defects-2-1024x638.png 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Precentage-of-Defects-2-300x187.png 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Precentage-of-Defects-2-768x478.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Precentage-of-Defects-2-1536x956.png 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Precentage-of-Defects-2-2048x1275.png 2048w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Precentage-of-Defects-2-512x319.png 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Precentage-of-Defects-2-920x573.png 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Precentage-of-Defects-2-1600x996.png 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Precentage-of-Defects-2-1920x1196.png 1920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Precentage-of-Defects-2-1320x822.png 1320w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Precentage-of-Defects-2.png 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px"><em>Ineffective Production Scheduling</em></p>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px">Throughput &#8211; Measuring the rate at which products are produced on a machine, line, plant, or across the entire company. Throughput is calculated from meters installed at the inlet and outlet of each production line. After that, the advanced analytics system converts the raw data of time indicators into a ready-made report of the time it took the equipment to perform a certain action.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2409" height="1791" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Throughput-1.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3206" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Throughput-1.png 2409w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Throughput-1-300x223.png 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Throughput-1-1024x761.png 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Throughput-1-768x571.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Throughput-1-1536x1142.png 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Throughput-1-2048x1523.png 2048w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Throughput-1-512x381.png 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Throughput-1-920x684.png 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Throughput-1-1600x1190.png 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Throughput-1-1920x1427.png 1920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Throughput-1-1320x981.png 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 2409px) 100vw, 2409px" /></figure>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px">Time-Based Measurement &#8211; tracks how long the equipment is actively used during a defined period, such as a shift or a day. This measurement is crucial as it reveals the actual usage versus the potential capacity, highlighting whether the equipment is being underutilized or overused. Information is collected using IoT devices or functions built into the equipment. After that, raw time data is translated into a ready-made KPI indicator using advanced analytics.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="641" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Time-Based-Measurement-1024x641.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3207" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Time-Based-Measurement-1024x641.png 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Time-Based-Measurement-300x188.png 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Time-Based-Measurement-768x481.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Time-Based-Measurement-1536x962.png 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Time-Based-Measurement-2048x1283.png 2048w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Time-Based-Measurement-512x321.png 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Time-Based-Measurement-920x576.png 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Time-Based-Measurement-1600x1002.png 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Time-Based-Measurement-1920x1203.png 1920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Time-Based-Measurement-1320x827.png 1320w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-Time-Based-Measurement.png 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px"><em>Excessive Wear and Tear on Machinery and Suboptimal Maintenance Scheduling</em></p>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px"><strong>Downtime and Uptime </strong>&#8211;&nbsp; Uptime refers to the duration when the equipment is running and available for use, directly contributing to productivity. Downtime, on the other hand, represents periods when the equipment is non-operational due to maintenance, breakdowns, or other issues. These metrics are crucial for understanding the reliability and efficiency of equipment. Information is collected using IoT devices or functions built into the equipment. The data does not require any additional processing.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px"><strong>Mean Time To Repair (MTTR)</strong> &#8211; This measures the average time it takes to repair equipment after a failure. A lower MTTR helps in reducing downtime and maintaining productivity.&nbsp; This indicator uses the same metrics for calculation as the Downtime and Uptime KPIs. After collecting the data, the advanced analytics system calculates the average value among the time indicators and provides a ready-made report.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<div class="wp-block-columns is-layout-flex wp-container-core-columns-layout-1 wp-block-columns-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-column is-layout-flow wp-block-column-is-layout-flow" style="flex-basis:100%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="639" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-MTTR-1024x639.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3208" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-MTTR-1024x639.png 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-MTTR-300x187.png 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-MTTR-768x479.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-MTTR-1536x958.png 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-MTTR-2048x1278.png 2048w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-MTTR-512x319.png 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-MTTR-920x574.png 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-MTTR-1600x998.png 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-MTTR-1920x1198.png 1920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-MTTR-1320x824.png 1320w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Eu-MTTR.png 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>
</div>
</div>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px">Mean Time Between Failures (MTBF) &#8211; This KPI measures the average time between equipment failures. A higher MTBF indicates more reliable equipment. This indicator uses the same metrics for calculation as the Downtime and Uptime KPIs. After collecting the data, the advanced analytics system calculates the average value among the time indicators and provides a ready-made report.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<p style="font-size:16px">Based on the indicators, this method helps to track production and has more opportunities to react proactively or to problems. Thus, the use of advanced analytics gives us access to:</p>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px"><strong>Maximizing Efficiency:</strong> Companies can identify underused resources by measuring how much equipment is used compared to its full potential. This helps make adjustments to increase efficiency, ensuring that the equipment is not just sitting idle when it could contribute to production.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px"><strong>Cost Optimization:</strong> Equipment represents a significant investment for any business. Measuring its utilization helps understand whether the company is getting the most out of this investment. If equipment isn&#8217;t used effectively, it could lead to unnecessary expenses like paying for machines that aren&#8217;t contributing to revenue generation.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px"><strong>Improving Production Planning:</strong> Equipment utilization data is crucial for effective production scheduling. It helps align the use of machinery with production demands, ensuring that the right equipment is available and operational when needed.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px"><strong>Reducing Wear and Tear:</strong> Overuse of equipment can lead to increased maintenance needs and shorter lifespans for machinery. By monitoring utilization, companies can balance the workload on equipment to prevent excessive wear and tear.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px"><strong>Identifying Bottlenecks:</strong> Low utilization rates can signal bottlenecks where equipment is not used effectively in production. This can lead to insights about process inefficiencies or the need to reallocate resources.</li>



<li style="font-size:16px"><strong>Maintenance Scheduling:</strong> Knowing how frequently and intensely equipment is used informs maintenance schedules. Instead of following a rigid maintenance calendar, companies can plan maintenance based on actual usage, reducing downtime and maintenance costs.</li>
</ul>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">The exploration of advanced analytics in equipment utilization underscores a transformative shift in optimizing manufacturing processes. By integrating real-time data collection through IoT devices with the analytical power of advanced analytics and machine learning, production facilities are equipped to make more informed, proactive decisions. This approach revolutionizes equipment management by providing a deeper and more accurate understanding of various key performance indicators (KPIs) like Equipment Utilization Rate, Throughput, Downtime and Uptime, MTTR, and MTBF.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">The implications of this evolution are far-reaching. Advanced analytics enables a more dynamic approach to addressing challenges like underutilization, inefficient production scheduling, and excessive wear and tear on machinery. It allows for real-time identification of operational bottlenecks and facilitates more strategic maintenance scheduling, thereby extending the lifespan of equipment and optimizing investment returns.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Furthermore, the capacity to predict and preempt equipment failures through these sophisticated analytical tools enhances operational efficiency and significantly reduces costs. This proactive equipment maintenance and optimization approach ensures that resources are utilized effectively, reducing wastage and downtime.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">In conclusion, integrating advanced analytics into equipment utilization is not just an enhancement of existing processes; it&#8217;s a fundamental shift towards a more data-driven, efficient, and productive manufacturing environment. Adopting these technologies will become a cornerstone for competitive advantage as industries evolve, driving innovation and excellence in manufacturing processes. The future of industrial efficiency and productivity lies in harnessing the power of advanced analytics, and the journey has just begun.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>IoT Widgets for enhanced dashboards: introducing the  action, command, toggle, and power buttons</title>
		<link>./../iot-widgets-for-enhanced-dashboards-introducing-the-action-command-toggle-and-power-buttons-2-2/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../iot-widgets-for-enhanced-dashboards-introducing-the-action-command-toggle-and-power-buttons-2-2/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Shvaika]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 11:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Engineering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New features]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=2970</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to the latest update from the ThingsBoard team! Our ongoing mission to improve the platform&#8217;s functionality and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="font-size:16px">Welcome to the latest update from the ThingsBoard team! Our ongoing mission to improve the platform&#8217;s functionality and user experience brings us to the introduction of four innovative IoT widgets: the &#8220;Action button,&#8221; &#8220;Command button,&#8221; &#8220;Toggle button,&#8221; and &#8220;Power button.&#8221; Designed with a focus on usability, these new buttons are tailored for the most common IoT use cases, offering users enhanced control and flexibility in managing their IoT devices and dashboards. Let&#8217;s dive into their capabilities.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Action button widget</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">This button facilitates single-click navigation to other dashboards, states, or custom actions. You may choose one of the common <a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/user-guide/ui/widget-actions">widget actions</a> to be triggered when the user clicks the button. You may also choose whether the button is in default, activated, or disabled state. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Buttons.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3106"/></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">More importantly, the button may dynamically change its state based on the value of the attribute or time-series subscription. You may find an example of the button that changes its state when the user attribute is updated below: </p>



<div class="wp-block-file"><a id="wp-block-file--media-2b8b2412-a70d-486d-bfd5-d21e65230e9a" href="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/tb-dynamic_button_states.json">tb_dynamic_button_states.json</a><a href="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/tb-dynamic_button_states.json" class="wp-block-file__button wp-element-button" download aria-describedby="wp-block-file--media-2b8b2412-a70d-486d-bfd5-d21e65230e9a">Download</a></div>



<p style="font-size:16px">The behavior configuration is available in the basic widget settings:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Add-widget-2.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3126"/></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">The button appearance is highly customizable. You may choose one of four available layouts, configure icons, and label appearance. The colors of the buttons are configured via main and background color palettes. By default, the button uses a palette configured in the <a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/pe/user-guide/white-labeling/">white-labeling settings</a>.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Appearance-3.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3108"/></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">Although the button supports all common <a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/user-guide/ui/widget-actions">widget actions</a>, we will highlight only the most popular in this article. To demonstrate them, we have prepared the dashboard that you may <a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/user-guide/dashboards/#import-dashboard">import</a> to your platform instance.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Button-use-cases.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3109"/></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">You may find the sample dashboard JSON below: </p>



<div class="wp-block-file"><a id="wp-block-file--media-fd741ad2-e692-4a03-9a23-812a9f191991" href="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/button_use_cases.json">button_use_cases.json</a></div>



<p style="font-size:16px">The dashboard has two states: &#8220;default&#8221; and &#8220;other&#8221;. The default state contains 5 showcase buttons. The &#8220;other&#8221; state contains a line chart widget with random data. Let&#8217;s review each button below:</p>



<p style="font-size:16px"><strong>•</strong> <strong>Open dialog</strong> button uses &#8220;Navigate to new dashboard state&#8221; with the &#8220;Open in separate dialog&#8221; display option. So, the user will see the line chart opened in a modal window.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-10 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1666" height="856" data-id="3048" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Open-dialog-1.gif" alt="" class="wp-image-3048"/></figure>
</figure>



<p style="font-size:16px"><strong>•</strong> <strong>Open popup</strong> button is similar, but the &#8220;Open in popover&#8221; display option is used. You may also explore various options for the &#8220;Preferred popover placement&#8221; option. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="565" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Open-popup-1024x565.gif" alt="" class="wp-image-3062" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Open-popup-1024x565.gif 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Open-popup-300x165.gif 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Open-popup-768x424.gif 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Open-popup-1536x847.gif 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Open-popup-512x282.gif 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Open-popup-920x507.gif 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Open-popup-1600x882.gif 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Open-popup-1320x728.gif 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px"><strong>•</strong> <strong>Change state</strong> button simply update the current dashboard state to the new one. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1666" height="860" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Change-state.gif" alt="" class="wp-image-3063"/></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px"><strong>•</strong> <strong>Drill down</strong> button is similar, but instead of changing the dashboard state, it leaves the old one in the stack. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1670" height="860" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Drill-Down.gif" alt="" class="wp-image-3064"/></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px"><strong>•</strong> <strong>Open URL</strong> provides the ability to open external or relative URLs in the same or separate browser tab. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="527" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Open-URL-1024x527.gif" alt="" class="wp-image-3066" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Open-URL-1024x527.gif 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Open-URL-300x154.gif 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Open-URL-768x395.gif 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Open-URL-1536x791.gif 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Open-URL-512x264.gif 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Open-URL-920x474.gif 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Open-URL-1600x824.gif 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Open-URL-1320x680.gif 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Command button widget</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">The Command button widget is designed to perform three key actions: sending <a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/user-guide/rpc/">commands</a> to devices, updating <a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/user-guide/attributes/">attributes</a>, or appending <a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/user-guide/telemetry/">time-series</a> data. </p>



<p style="font-size:16px">You can specify a single device to carry out your chosen action, such as receiving a command. For those familiar with the platform, there&#8217;s an option to use <a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/user-guide/ui/aliases/">entity aliases</a> for targeting. This means you&#8217;re not limited to devices; you can target assets, users, or other entities capable of supporting attribute updates or time-series data additions. </p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Behavior settings enable the definition of the on-click action and condition when the button is disabled. More importantly, the button may dynamically become enabled or disabled based on attribute or time-series subscription. </p>



<p style="font-size:16px"><strong>Execute RPC action</strong> allows you to send the command to the device. You may configure the command (method) name and parameters of the command. The parameter value may be configured as a constant or result of function execution. You may send the command without parameters by choosing the &#8220;None&#8221; option.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Execute-RPC-action-7.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3110"/></figure></div>


<p style="font-size:16px">By default, we use an un-persisted command with 5 seconds timeout. You may change the command parameters in the advanced settings of the action.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px"><strong>Set attribute action</strong> allows you to set or update the value of the particular entity attribute. The action configuration form allows you to configure the scope, key, and value of the attribute. The attribute value may be configured as a constant or result of function execution. Please note that only devices support &#8220;shared&#8221; attribute scope. You must choose the &#8220;server&#8221; scope for all other entities. </p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Set-attribute-action-8.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3111"/></figure></div>


<p style="font-size:16px"><strong>Add time-series action</strong> allows you to add the new time-series value for the particular entity. The action configuration form allows you to configure the time-series data key and value. The value may be configured as a constant or result of function execution. </p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Add-time-series-action-9.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3112"/></figure></div>


<p style="font-size:16px">You may dynamically disable the button based on certain values of the attribute or time-series key. For example, the dashboard attached below contains two buttons that switch the state of the user&#8217;s attribute &#8220;state&#8221;. When the user presses button A, it becomes disabled, and vice versa.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Disabled-state-10.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3113" style="width:822px;height:auto"/></figure></div>


<p style="font-size:16px">You may find the sample dashboard JSON below: </p>



<div class="wp-block-file"><a id="wp-block-file--media-8508d6eb-4fb5-4e33-b266-136f058048ae" href="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/command_buttons.json">command_buttons.json</a><a href="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/command_buttons.json" class="wp-block-file__button wp-element-button" download aria-describedby="wp-block-file--media-8508d6eb-4fb5-4e33-b266-136f058048ae">Download</a></div>



<p style="font-size:16px">Alternatively, you may disable the button that sends the command to the device, if the device is offline. For this purpose, you may just use the value of the &#8220;active&#8221; attribute or time-series key. </p>



<p style="font-size:16px">The appearance settings for the Command button are identical to those of the Action button. The primary applications of the Command button are straightforward, focusing on managing devices and assets. This involves either issuing commands or updating attributes to control their operation.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Toggle button widget</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">The Toggle button widget shares many similarities with the Command button widget, but with a crucial distinction: it features two distinct states, &#8220;checked&#8221; and &#8220;unchecked&#8221;. This design allows it to perform two specific actions, &#8220;Check&#8221; and &#8220;Uncheck&#8221;, depending on its state. Users have the flexibility to fully customize the appearance of the button for both states, enhancing its visual and functional integration into their dashboards.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Toggle-button-widget-1.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3115"/></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">The default behavior will change the state of the device using the &#8220;setState&#8221; command:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Behavior-1.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3121"/></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">You may easily change this button to operate with the &#8220;state&#8221; attribute instead of sending commands to devices:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Behavior123-1.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3122"/></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">The Toggle button shares appearance settings with the Command button but allows separate configurations for its &#8220;Checked&#8221; and &#8220;Unchecked&#8221; states:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Button-appearance-1.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3123"/></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">Adjusting the border radius, background colors, and other appearance settings can significantly alter the button&#8217;s style:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="803" height="208" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Buttons123.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3120" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Buttons123.png 803w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Buttons123-300x78.png 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Buttons123-768x199.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Buttons123-512x133.png 512w" sizes="(max-width: 803px) 100vw, 803px" /></figure>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Power button widget</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">The Power button widget, similar to the Toggle button, differs in appearance and has three states: &#8216;On&#8217;, &#8216;Off&#8217; and disabled, with six customizable layouts:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Power-button-widget.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3124"/></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">The appearance settings are simplified compared to the Command button. Basically, you are able to configure main and background colors for every state.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Button-appearance-2.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3125"/></figure></div>


<p style="font-size:16px">The Power button widget enables remote control of devices across sectors: turning smart home appliances on/off, managing industrial equipment, controlling servers, adjusting energy sources, operating irrigation systems, managing healthcare devices, retail displays, and public lighting, showcasing its versatility in simplifying power management in IoT applications.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Summary</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">In our overview of the newest widgets for the ThingsBoard IoT Platform—Action button, Command button, Toggle button, and Power button—we&#8217;ve highlighted how these tools enhance IoT dashboard interaction and device management. Each widget offers specific functionalities to improve the user experience, from executing commands to providing clear status indicators.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">We encourage you to explore these widgets&#8217; capabilities within your projects. If you have ideas for improvements or additional features, we welcome you to submit feature requests on <a href="https://github.com/thingsboard/thingsboard">GitHub</a>. For any other feedback, please leave your comments below. Your feedback is essential for us to keep improving and growing the platform.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../iot-widgets-for-enhanced-dashboards-introducing-the-action-command-toggle-and-power-buttons-2-2/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Optimizing dashboard performance with enhanced image management</title>
		<link>./../optimizing-dashboard-performance-with-enhanced-image-management-3/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../optimizing-dashboard-performance-with-enhanced-image-management-3/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Shvaika]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 11:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=2971</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At ThingsBoard, we&#8217;ve always been committed to enhancing user experience and system performance. Our latest update, version 3.6.2,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="font-size:16px">At ThingsBoard, we&#8217;ve always been committed to enhancing user experience and system performance. Our latest update, version <a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/reference/releases/#v362">3.6.2</a>, introduces significant improvements in how images are managed within dashboards, widgets, and more. This update is a key enhancement designed to tackle inefficiencies identified as our user base expanded.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">The challenge with large images</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">Since the earliest releases, our platform has permitted the embedding of images in dashboards and widgets via external links or Base64 encoded data URLs. While flexible, this approach presented a significant challenge. Users occasionally embedded images up to 50MB in size directly into dashboards. Editing or exporting these dashboards meant transferring massive JSON files to and from the server, a highly inefficient process. This not only affected loading times but also the responsiveness of the dashboard editing experience.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">The solution</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">To address this issue, we&#8217;ve introduced a major update in how images are handled within the platform. A central aspect of this update is the introduction of the <a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/user-guide/image-gallery/">Image Gallery</a>. By moving dashboards to a separate entity and utilizing our internal, relative links for storing image references, we&#8217;ve significantly improved efficiency. This change minimizes the size of dashboard JSON files, streamlining both loading and editing processes. The Image Gallery simplifies the process of uploading, organizing, and selecting images.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1604" height="902" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Image-gallery.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3348" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Image-gallery.png 1604w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Image-gallery-300x169.png 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Image-gallery-1024x576.png 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Image-gallery-768x432.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Image-gallery-1536x864.png 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Image-gallery-512x288.png 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Image-gallery-920x517.png 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Image-gallery-1600x900.png 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Image-gallery-1320x742.png 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1604px) 100vw, 1604px" /></figure>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Backward compatibility</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">The platform&#8217;s upgrade script automatically converts all existing dashboards to the new format. Users can still upload dashboards in the old format to a new platform instance. These dashboards will automatically be converted to the new format during the upload process.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">For example, consider a “Sensors” dashboard with its background image stored in the old format:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code has-black-color has-text-color has-link-color wp-elements-240688aa6d231c0cb4116ec18afee3f6"><code lang="" class="">{
...
"backgroundImageUrl": "data:image/webp;base64,iVBORw...JRU5ErkJggg=="
...
}</code></pre>



<p style="font-size:16px">After the upgrade, a new image will be created in the image gallery:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1604" height="902" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Edit-image.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3345" srcset="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Edit-image.png 1604w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Edit-image-300x169.png 300w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Edit-image-1024x576.png 1024w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Edit-image-768x432.png 768w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Edit-image-1536x864.png 1536w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Edit-image-512x288.png 512w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Edit-image-920x517.png 920w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Edit-image-1600x900.png 1600w, ./../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Edit-image-1320x742.png 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1604px) 100vw, 1604px" /></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">The image name is auto-generated based on the dashboard name and the dashboard element where the image is used. This same behavior applies to images used in widget configuration: markers, backgrounds, etc. The dashboard now references the image using the following link:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code"><code lang="json" class="language-json">{
...
"backgroundImageUrl": "/api/images/tenant/sensors_dashboard_default_background.webp"
...
}</code></pre>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Private and public image links</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">Images can be provisioned at the system and tenant levels. System-level widgets are accessible to all platform users, while tenant images are available to authorized users of specific tenants.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">To embed an image into an Angular HTML template, such as the Markdown widget, HTML section in the widget editor, custom actions, etc., use the following code snippet:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code"><code class="">&lt;img [src]="'/api/images/tenant/sensors_dashboard_default_background.webp' | image | async" /&gt;</code></pre>



<p style="font-size:16px">The <code>image</code> pipe automatically adds the necessary authentication headers to the image request, allowing the same relative image URL to return different content for users from different tenants.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">However, custom widgets or static HTML blocks that do not support Angular HTML syntax cannot add authentication headers to requests. Therefore, every platform image also has a unique URL for downloading the image without authentication. Using the following code snippet, you may embed an image into the components based on the plain HTML. Such components include HTML card widgets, cell content functions, etc.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code"><code class="">&lt;img src="/api/images/public/ZA4biARtpnl970l0j8MMolRKM56fbpK1" alt="&amp;quot;Sensors&amp;quot; dashboard default background" /&gt;</code></pre>



<p style="font-size:16px">Each code snippet is unique to its image, and you can find the corresponding snippets in the Embed image window.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Embed-image.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3132"/></figure>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Caching</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">Our image API now utilizes ETags to optimize caching, ensuring that images are only re-downloaded when they have changed. This approach significantly saves bandwidth and improves load times. While we don&#8217;t apply Cache-Control headers by default, users have the flexibility to customize caching behavior through environment variables, including settings for image ETags cache TTL, maximum cache size, and browser cache TTL for both system and tenant images. These settings are crucial for balancing between reducing server load and ensuring content freshness.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/ThingsBoard.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3133"/></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">The platform offers environment variables to control caching behavior:</p>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px">CACHE_SPECS_IMAGE_ETAGS_TTL<strong>:</strong> Controls the cache TTL for image ETags. The default is set to 44640 minutes (31 days), after which the cache is cleared.<br></li>



<li style="font-size:16px">CACHE_SPECS_IMAGE_ETAGS_MAX_SIZE<strong>:</strong> Determines the maximum ETags cache size on the server. The default is 10000. Setting this to 0 disables the cache. <br></li>



<li style="font-size:16px">CACHE_SPECS_IMAGE_SYSTEM_BROWSER_TTL and CACHE_SPECS_IMAGE_TENANT_BROWSER_TTL<strong>:</strong> These settings manage the browser cache TTL for system and tenant images, respectively, with a default of 0 minutes, meaning caching is disabled by default.</li>
</ul>



<p style="font-size:16px">These settings allow administrators to adjust the balance between performance and content freshness as needed.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Improvement Summary</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">By tackling the challenge of image management within dashboards, we aim to offer a more efficient, robust, and user-friendly platform. Following the upgrade of <a href="https://thingsboard.cloud/">thingsboard.cloud</a>, we&#8217;ve observed an 86% reduction in the size of the dashboards, and some dashboards now load more than twice as fast.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-11 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex"></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-12 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex"></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../optimizing-dashboard-performance-with-enhanced-image-management-3/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
