<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Community &#8211; ThingsBoard&#039;s blog</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 11:39:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/cropped-favicon-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Community &#8211; ThingsBoard&#039;s blog</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Invitation to the online event: discover the latest updates from ThingsBoard platform!</title>
		<link>./../../../andrews-blog-post-test/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Shvaika]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 16:07:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Company]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=30</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Greetings, dear users! We are excited to announce an upcoming online event where we will provide a detailed&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Greetings, dear users!</p>



<p>We are excited to announce an upcoming online event where we will provide a detailed overview of all the exciting innovations and updates on our ThingsBoard platform. This event will be a unique opportunity for you to be the first to learn about the enhancements awaiting you in your favorite IoT project management tool.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-6 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="2560" height="1486" data-id="2460" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/2201_w037_n003_155b_p1_155-3-scaled.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2460" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/2201_w037_n003_155b_p1_155-3-scaled.jpg 2560w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/2201_w037_n003_155b_p1_155-3-300x174.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></figure>
</figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Date and Time</h2>



<p>Date: 12 of March<br>Time: 16:00 <br>Location: Online (Event link will be provided after registration)</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What to Expect</h2>



<ul>
<li><strong>New features overview:</strong> Learn about the latest platform updates and how they can enhance your experience working with ThingsBoard.</li>



<li><strong>Process demonstrations:</strong> See live examples of how to use the new features and capabilities to manage your projects more effectively.</li>



<li><strong>Questions and answers:</strong> Ask your questions to our experts directly during the event and receive real-time answers.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Registration</h2>



<p>To participate in this exciting event, please register using the following link: [Registration Link]</p>



<p>Don&#8217;t miss the chance to be the first to learn about all the new features and improvements on our platform! Join us at our online event and stay updated on all the changes.</p>



<p>We look forward to meeting you!</p>



<p>Best regards, The ThingsBoard Team</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hello world! How to get started with ThingsBoard</title>
		<link>./../../../hello-world/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yevheniia Havrysh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 14:42:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://127.0.0.1/?p=1</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Getting started with ThingsBoard cloud: a comprehensive IoT guide In the rapidly evolving world of Internet of Things&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Getting started with ThingsBoard cloud: a comprehensive IoT guide</h3>



<p>In the rapidly evolving world of Internet of Things (IoT), ThingsBoard Cloud emerges as a beacon for those embarking on IoT projects. This tutorial is your comprehensive guide to navigating the robust features of ThingsBoard Cloud, aimed at demystifying the process from device connection to dashboard creation and beyond. Whether you&#8217;re a seasoned IoT professional or a newcomer, this guide serves as your roadmap to leveraging ThingsBoard Cloud for your IoT solutions.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Introduction to ThingsBoard cloud</h3>



<p>ThingsBoard Cloud is a cutting-edge platform designed to streamline the integration, management, and analysis of IoT devices. It offers a suite of tools to connect devices, process device data, and present this data in real-time dashboards, enabling users to make informed decisions based on live data feeds. The platform supports a variety of use cases, from smart buildings to industrial monitoring, making it a versatile choice for IoT projects.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Prerequisites for using ThingsBoard cloud</h3>



<p>Before diving into the practical steps, ensure you have access to ThingsBoard Professional Edition. The most straightforward method is to utilize the ThingsBoard Cloud server, although you can also opt for a local installation following the provided Installation Guide.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Step 1: Device provisioning</h3>



<p>The journey begins with adding a device to the ThingsBoard platform. This device will serve as your data source, transmitting key metrics like temperature readings to the platform. Adding a new device involves navigating to the &#8220;Entities&#8221; section, selecting &#8220;Devices,&#8221; and using the intuitive UI to create your device instance, named for example, &#8220;My New Device.&#8221;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Step 2: Establishing device connectivity</h3>



<p>Once your device is provisioned, the next critical step is to verify its connectivity to ThingsBoard. This is achieved through the &#8220;Check connectivity&#8221; feature, which allows you to publish telemetry data on behalf of your device. Successful data publication marks your device as active, a vital step in ensuring reliable data flow to the platform.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Step 3: Dashboard creation and widget configuration</h3>



<p>With your device connected, the focus shifts to data visualization. ThingsBoard dashboards offer a dynamic canvas to monitor and analyze IoT data. The process involves creating a new dashboard and populating it with widgets, each tailored to display specific data types, such as temperature readings or alarm signals. This section will guide you through creating an empty dashboard, adding an &#8220;Entities table&#8221; widget, and further enhancing your dashboard with chart widgets and alarms tables, providing a holistic view of your IoT ecosystem.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Step 4: Alarm rules configuration</h3>



<p>An integral part of managing IoT devices is monitoring for specific conditions and triggering alarms. This tutorial will walk you through setting up alarm rules that, for instance, raise an alert when temperature readings exceed a defined threshold. This proactive monitoring is crucial for maintaining the integrity and performance of your IoT devices.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Step 5: Alarm generation and notification</h3>



<p>Following the configuration of alarm rules, this section delves into generating alarms based on real-time data. It also covers the notification process within ThingsBoard, ensuring that users are promptly alerted to any issues detected by the alarm rules.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Step 6: Notification setup</h3>



<p>Timely notifications are key to an effective IoT system. ThingsBoard&#8217;s Notification center facilitates this, allowing for customizable notifications through various channels such as email and SMS. This tutorial provides insights into setting up and managing notifications, ensuring that you stay informed of critical events within your IoT infrastructure.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Step 7: Sharing dashboards and managing access</h3>



<p>A unique aspect of ThingsBoard is its ability to share dashboards with different users or customer groups, ensuring that relevant stakeholders have access to the necessary data. This section covers the creation of customers and customer users, assigning device ownership, and sharing dashboards, providing a comprehensive overview of managing access to IoT data within ThingsBoard.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h3>



<p>This guide is designed to empower you to leverage the full potential of ThingsBoard Cloud for your IoT projects. From device provisioning to dashboard sharing, each step is meticulously detailed to provide a clear path to successful IoT implementation. Whether you&#8217;re monitoring a single device or managing a complex network of IoT sensors, ThingsBoard Cloud offers the tools and flexibility needed to achieve your objectives.</p>



<p>As you embark on your IoT journey with ThingsBoard Cloud, remember that this guide is just the beginning. The platform&#8217;s extensive features and customization options open up a world of possibilities for IoT innovation and efficiency. Happy exploring!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Enhancing IoT solutions with edge computing</title>
		<link>./../../../road-tripping-across-new-zealand-a-guide-to-the-islands-best-kept-secrets/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../road-tripping-across-new-zealand-a-guide-to-the-islands-best-kept-secrets/index.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Shvaika]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 06:24:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://swyft.codesupply.co/lifestyle/?p=2094</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Leveraging technology in daily routines and work, individuals can now experience a seamless blend of business, work, and leisure.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Hey IoT enthusiasts!</p>



<p>Are you looking to take your IoT projects to the next level? If so, you&#8217;ve come to the right place. Today, we&#8217;re diving deep into the world of edge computing and exploring how it can revolutionize the way we approach IoT solutions.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.wikipedia.com.ua/">What</a> is Edge Computing?</h3>



<p>Edge computing is a distributed computing paradigm that brings computation and data storage closer to the location where it is needed, improving response times and saving bandwidth. In the context of IoT, edge computing enables devices to process data locally, reducing latency and ensuring real-time decision-making capabilities.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Benefits of Edge Computing in IoT:</h3>



<ol>
<li><strong>Reduced Latency</strong>: By processing data closer to its source, edge computing minimizes the time it takes for data to travel from devices to the cloud and back, resulting in lower latency and faster response times.</li>



<li><strong>Improved Reliability</strong>: Edge computing reduces reliance on cloud connectivity, making IoT solutions more resilient to network outages and ensuring continuous operation even in remote or offline environments.</li>



<li><strong>Enhanced Security</strong>: Edge computing enables data to be processed and analyzed locally, reducing the risk of data breaches and ensuring sensitive information remains secure.</li>



<li><strong>Scalability</strong>: Edge computing allows for distributed processing of data across a network of edge devices, enabling IoT solutions to scale more effectively to accommodate growing data volumes and device deployments.</li>
</ol>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Real-World Applications:</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Smart Manufacturing</strong>: Edge computing enables predictive maintenance, real-time monitoring, and process optimization in manufacturing environments, improving efficiency and reducing downtime.</li>



<li><strong>Smart Cities</strong>: Edge computing supports real-time analysis of data from sensors deployed throughout the city, enabling faster response to emergencies, optimized traffic management, and improved public services.</li>



<li><strong>Healthcare</strong>: Edge computing facilitates remote patient monitoring, real-time analysis of medical data, and personalized healthcare delivery, improving patient outcomes and reducing healthcare costs.</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Getting Started with Edge Computing:</h3>



<p>Ready to harness the power of edge computing for your IoT projects? Check out our comprehensive guide on getting started with edge computing on the ThingsBoard platform, where we&#8217;ll walk you through the process of setting up edge devices, deploying edge analytics, and integrating with cloud services.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion:</h3>



<p>Edge computing is revolutionizing the way we approach IoT solutions, enabling faster response times, improved reliability, and enhanced security. By leveraging the power of edge computing, you can unlock new possibilities for your IoT projects and take them to new heights.</p>



<p>Stay tuned for more insights, tutorials, and case studies on edge computing and IoT from ThingsBoard!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../road-tripping-across-new-zealand-a-guide-to-the-islands-best-kept-secrets/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
