<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Business &#8211; ThingsBoard&#039;s blog</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 10:41:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/cropped-favicon-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Business &#8211; ThingsBoard&#039;s blog</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Reliable T&#038;H monitoring with WhereView &#038; ThingsBoard</title>
		<link>./../../../reliable-th-monitoring-with-whereview-thingsboard-2/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../reliable-th-monitoring-with-whereview-thingsboard-2/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Doan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 12:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=3188</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Reliable and high-quality control of temperature and humidity with constant access to monitoring data is an important condition for the storage of thermosensitive drugs and raw materials for medicines. The ThingsBoard partner — Vypin together with our team has implemented a solution for a global pharmaceutical company. The IoT application has helped to optimize processes and costs.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="font-size:16px">Reliable and high-quality control of temperature and humidity with constant access to monitoring data is an important condition for the storage of thermosensitive drugs and raw materials for medicines. The ThingsBoard partner — <a href="http://vypin.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Vypin</a>, together with our team, has implemented a solution for a global pharmaceutical company. The IoT application has helped to optimize processes and costs.</p>



<div style="height:16px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/5.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3225"/></figure>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">The problem</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">The FDA (The Food &amp; Drug Administration) has strict requirements and recommendations for pharmaceutical manufacturers, particularly regarding storage conditions and the control system to comply with these conditions (more about regulation can be found here). The customer asked  Vypin to replace the current system. The previous one didn’t meet the FDA standards, which was the reason for the fines and the potential risk of drug or component damage.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">As they say in the medical field, the patient had specific complaints. First of all, data loss. Existing devices could go offline for various reasons (from network outages to power loss), but the transmission or recording of telemetry did not take place. But the client couldn’t find out about these or those losses, which was the second complaint. The current system does not provide a notification mechanism. In addition, monitoring data was not available remotely.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p class="is-style-cs-about" style="font-size:16px">Round-the-clock rotation of operators to control the temperature and humidity in the warehouse indeed is not the best solution. Therefore, in the regular automatic reports related to the storage environment state there were gaps in the tables and graphs. The FDA fines for such violations.</p>
<cite>Customer officer says</cite></blockquote>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-left">Solution</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">To solve the problem, the Vypin team proposed an integrated Vypin-Whereview system (powered by ThingsBoard). The company built a wireless network, installed sensors and gateways</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">If we mention one of the first problems (data loss), the new sensors now had a memory module and could record telemetry locally. When the gateway connection was lost, data loss (!) didn’t and doesn’t occur. When the online gateway returns, it picks up the accumulated telemetry and sends it to Whereview.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="2409" height="1353" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3223" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8.png 2409w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-300x168.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-1024x575.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-768x431.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-1536x863.png 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-2048x1150.png 2048w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-512x288.png 512w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-920x517.png 920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-1600x899.png 1600w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-1920x1078.png 1920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-1320x741.png 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 2409px) 100vw, 2409px" /></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">The application, built on TB, solved the rest of the customer&#8217;s problems. First, the client&#8217;s responsible employee gets access to the monitoring data at any time. Managers also received access.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="587" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-1024x587.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3228" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-1024x587.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-300x172.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-768x440.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-1536x880.png 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-2048x1173.png 2048w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-512x293.png 512w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-920x527.png 920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-1600x917.png 1600w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-1920x1100.png 1920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-1320x756.png 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6.png 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">To see the Dashboard with graphs and tables, it is enough to open the corresponding tab in your own browser and log in.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">It makes sense to highlight that based on the rule engine and device profiles, Vypin set up a notification system. In case of violations of the specified conditions (for example, exceeding the temperature thresholds), notifications are received by those who should be aware of this recorded violation. This allows you to respond instantly and even take preventive measures.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-left">Result </h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">Everyone understands that it is better (easier, cheaper, less time-consuming) to prevent a disease than to treat it. With the new warehouse monitoring system, the client (patient) has the opportunity for prevention.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../reliable-th-monitoring-with-whereview-thingsboard-2/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
