<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Business - Thingsboard's blog</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/category/business/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 12:12:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Empowering IoT Solutions: X-TELIA&#8217;s Success Story with ThingsBoard</title>
		<link>/blog/empowering-iot-solutions-x-telias-success-story-with-thingsboard/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=empowering-iot-solutions-x-telias-success-story-with-thingsboard</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 12:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solutions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/blog/?p=4428</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>X-TELIA, a leading innovator in IoT solutions based in Montreal, Canada, has found its winning formula with ThingsBoard.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/empowering-iot-solutions-x-telias-success-story-with-thingsboard/">Empowering IoT Solutions: X-TELIA’s Success Story with ThingsBoard</a> first appeared on <a href="/blog/">Thingsboard's blog</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the fast-paced world of IoT, choosing the right platform can make or break a project&#8217;s success. X-TELIA, a leading innovator in IoT solutions based in Montreal, Canada, has found its winning formula with ThingsBoard. As an open-source IoT platform renowned for its versatility and reliability, ThingsBoard has become the cornerstone of X-TELIA&#8217;s operations, enabling it to deliver cutting-edge solutions across various sectors.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Unleashing the Power of ThingsBoard</h4>



<p>X-TELIA&#8217;s journey with ThingsBoard began several years ago when they adopted the Professional Edition of the platform. From the outset, they were impressed by its comprehensive features tailored specifically for data collection, processing, visualization, and device management. With a diverse clientele spanning municipal, agricultural, and commercial markets, X-TELIA found that ThingsBoard offered the flexibility and scalability needed to effectively address a wide range of use cases.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Harnessing the Potential of LoRaWAN Technology</h4>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="689" src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/x-tella-1024x689.webp" alt="" class="wp-image-4479" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/x-tella-1024x689.webp 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/x-tella-300x202.webp 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/x-tella-768x516.webp 768w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/x-tella-1536x1033.webp 1536w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/x-tella-2048x1377.webp 2048w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/x-tella-512x344.webp 512w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/x-tella-920x619.webp 920w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/x-tella-1600x1076.webp 1600w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/x-tella-1920x1291.webp 1920w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/x-tella.webp 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>At the heart of X-TELIA&#8217;s operations lies its public LoRa Network, a critical component for collecting sensor data. Leveraging ThingsBoard&#8217;s seamless integration capabilities, X-TELIA effortlessly channels LoRaWAN sensor data into the platform, laying the foundation for actionable insights and intelligent decision-making. Whether it&#8217;s monitoring environmental conditions, optimizing agricultural processes, or enhancing operational efficiency in commercial settings, ThingsBoard provides the robust infrastructure needed to transform raw data into valuable insights.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Custom Solutions, Endless Possibilities</h4>



<p>One of the key strengths of ThingsBoard lies in its ability to accommodate diverse requirements, from simple use cases to complex projects. X-TELIA leverages this flexibility to offer bespoke solutions tailored to each client&#8217;s unique needs. Whether it&#8217;s developing custom dashboards, implementing specialized algorithms, or integrating third-party services, ThingsBoard&#8217;s customizable nature empowers X-TELIA to deliver tailored solutions that exceed client expectations.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="655" src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/x-tella2-1024x655.webp" alt="" class="wp-image-4481" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/x-tella2-1024x655.webp 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/x-tella2-300x192.webp 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/x-tella2-768x492.webp 768w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/x-tella2-1536x983.webp 1536w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/x-tella2-2048x1311.webp 2048w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/x-tella2-512x328.webp 512w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/x-tella2-920x589.webp 920w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/x-tella2-1600x1024.webp 1600w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/x-tella2-1920x1229.webp 1920w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/x-tella2.webp 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Security, Scalability, and Customization: The Triple Threat</h4>



<p>Security is paramount in the IoT landscape, and X-TELIA trusts ThingsBoard&#8217;s robust security protocols to safeguard sensitive data and ensure compliance with industry standards. </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>With scalability built into its core architecture, ThingsBoard seamlessly accommodates X-TELIA&#8217;s growing infrastructure demands, ensuring optimal performance even as its client base expands. Finally, the ability to customize the platform using custom code enables X-TELIA to confidently tackle even the most complex projects, knowing that ThingsBoard provides the foundation for innovation and growth.</p>
<cite>Eric Bourbeau<br>CEO, X-TELIA</cite></blockquote>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">A Cloud-Based Success Story</h4>



<p>Operating on the cloud adds another layer of agility and accessibility to X-TELIA&#8217;s operations. By running their own instance of ThingsBoard PE on AWS, X-TELIA enjoys the benefits of cloud computing, including enhanced flexibility, scalability, and reliability. This cloud-native approach ensures seamless integration with existing infrastructure while future-proofing X-TELIA&#8217;s IoT ecosystem for continued success.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h4>



<p>In the competitive landscape of IoT solutions, X-TELIA stands out as a beacon of innovation and excellence, powered by the unparalleled capabilities of ThingsBoard. With its robust features, seamless integrations, and unwavering commitment to security and scalability, ThingsBoard has become the backbone of X-TELIA&#8217;s operations, enabling them to deliver tailored solutions that drive real-world impact across municipal, agricultural, and commercial sectors. As X-TELIA continues to push the boundaries of IoT innovation, ThingsBoard remains their trusted partner on the journey towards a smarter, more connected future.</p>



<p>You can try creating your account and explore the possibilities of the service here: <a href="https://thingsboard.io/products/paas/" title="Thingsboard">ThingsBoard Cloud</a></p><p>The post <a href="/blog/empowering-iot-solutions-x-telias-success-story-with-thingsboard/">Empowering IoT Solutions: X-TELIA’s Success Story with ThingsBoard</a> first appeared on <a href="/blog/">Thingsboard's blog</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Milesight and ThingsBoard announced a technical partnership to provide more integrated IoT solutions</title>
		<link>/blog/milesight-and-thingsboard-inc-announced-a-technical-partnership-to-provide-more-integrated-iot-solutions/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=milesight-and-thingsboard-inc-announced-a-technical-partnership-to-provide-more-integrated-iot-solutions</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 16:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/blog/?p=3913</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Xiamen, China, and New York, United States —&#160;Milesight, an innovative IoT products provider, and&#160;ThingsBoard, Inc., an IoT-related software&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/milesight-and-thingsboard-inc-announced-a-technical-partnership-to-provide-more-integrated-iot-solutions/">Milesight and ThingsBoard announced a technical partnership to provide more integrated IoT solutions</a> first appeared on <a href="/blog/">Thingsboard's blog</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="535" src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Milesight-1-1024x535.webp" alt="" class="wp-image-3915" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Milesight-1-1024x535.webp 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Milesight-1-300x157.webp 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Milesight-1-768x401.webp 768w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Milesight-1-1536x803.webp 1536w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Milesight-1-2048x1070.webp 2048w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Milesight-1-512x268.webp 512w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Milesight-1-920x481.webp 920w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Milesight-1-1600x836.webp 1600w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Milesight-1-1920x1003.webp 1920w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Milesight-1.webp 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Xiamen, China, and New York, United States —&nbsp;<a href="https://www.milesight.com/">Milesight</a>, an innovative IoT products provider, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thingsboard.io/">ThingsBoard</a><a href="https://www.thingsboard.io/">, Inc.</a>, an IoT-related software product vendor, particularly an open-source IoT platform provider, have announced a technical partnership. This collaboration aims to deliver highly integrated IoT solutions to customers. Both companies aim to provide comprehensive and seamless solutions for diverse IoT applications by combining their expertise and technologies.</p>



<p>Milesight, a pioneer in future-oriented IoT technologies encompassing sensing, LoRaWAN®, AI, and 5G, has established itself as a leader by introducing a wide range of cutting-edge products, including highly reliable gateways, indoor air quality sensors, occupancy and people counting sensors, water leak detectors, and many more. Through continuous innovation, Milesight reaffirms its commitment to delivering state-of-the-art products that cater to the evolving needs of the IoT landscape.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><em>As customers often come to us with a request to recommend hardware vendors, we want to provide them with reliable vendors we vouch for, like Milesight. This partnership reflects the joint dedication of both sides to provide reliable IoT solutions. We are committed to a long-term collaboration that will bring lasting benefits to our customers.</em></p>
<cite>Anrdii Shvaika,&nbsp;CEO and co-founder of ThingsBoard Inc.</cite></blockquote>



<p>ThingsBoard is an IoT platform for data collection, processing, visualization, and device management. The platform enables device connectivity via industry-standard IoT protocols or stream data from devices connected to existing IoT Platforms. The platform supports both cloud and on-premises deployments, combining scalability, fault tolerance, and performance so that the users&#8217; data remains safe.</p>



<p>In collaboration with ThingsBoard, Milesight has established seamless integration of its gateways and devices with the robust ThingsBoard IoT platform. This partnership aims to provide customers with more integrated IoT solutions that leverage the combined strengths of both companies. By combining Milesight&#8217;s innovative gateways and devices with the powerful capabilities of the ThingsBoard IoT platform, users can achieve enhanced connectivity, streamlined device management, and advanced data analytics.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><em>This partnership shows that Milesight and ThingsBoard are committed to empowering businesses with complete and dependable IoT solutions. By combining both of our technologies, we aim to spark digital transformation, boost operational efficiency, and open up new possibilities in the world of IoT applications.</em></p>
<cite>Leon Jiang, VP at Milesight</cite></blockquote>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">About&nbsp;<a href="https://thingsboard.io/">ThingsBoard</a></h4>



<p>Established in 2016, ThingsBoard, Inc. specializes in developing IoT software products under the ThingsBoard<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> umbrella. Our flagship IoT platform is the most popular open-source project in its class. ThingsBoard&#8217;s freeware and licensed software is widely utilized by IoT enthusiasts designing and prototyping smart solutions in their garages and industrial customers with diverse requirements for device management, data processing, security, privacy, analysis, etc.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">About&nbsp;<a href="https://www.milesight.com/">Milesight</a></h4>



<p>Milesight is a fast-growing high-tech company delivering smart IoT and video surveillance products with a focus on IoT technologies, including Artificial Intelligence, 5G, and LoRaWAN®, since 2011. With improved sensing capability and advanced IoT insights, we help customers worldwide optimize their business operations in a more efficient and sustainable way. In collaboration with a global network of distributors and system integrators, we are committed to building open ecosystems and accelerating IoT strategies to the next level.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Your feedback</h4>



<p>If you found this article interesting, please leave your feedback in the comments section, post questions or feature requests on the&nbsp;<strong><a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/thingsboard">forum</a></strong>&nbsp;and “star” our project on the&nbsp;<strong><a href="https://github.com/thingsboard/thingsboard">github</a></strong>&nbsp;in order to stay tuned for new releases and tutorials.</p><p>The post <a href="/blog/milesight-and-thingsboard-inc-announced-a-technical-partnership-to-provide-more-integrated-iot-solutions/">Milesight and ThingsBoard announced a technical partnership to provide more integrated IoT solutions</a> first appeared on <a href="/blog/">Thingsboard's blog</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
