<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>PR team - Thingsboard's blog</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/author/alex-doan/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 14:27:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>TOP SUPPLIER RETAIL 2024: ThingsBoard and Schwarz Group&#8217;s Award-Winning Partnership</title>
		<link>/blog/top-supplier-retail-2024-2/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=top-supplier-retail-2024-2</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 10:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solutions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Use cases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://tbblog.xyz/?p=3972</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A new achievement and what does it mean to all</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/top-supplier-retail-2024-2/">TOP SUPPLIER RETAIL 2024: ThingsBoard and Schwarz Group’s Award-Winning Partnership</a> first appeared on <a href="/blog/">Thingsboard's blog</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The retail technology landscape is evolving rapidly, driven by the transformative power of the Internet of Things (IoT). In this innovative arena, the partnership between ThingsBoard and Schwarz IT shines brightly. This collaboration has secured ThingsBoard the prestigious &#8220;TOP SUPPLIER RETAIL 2024&#8221; award from the EHI Retail Institute, confirming our leadership in IoT solutions for retail.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-vimeo wp-block-embed-vimeo wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Schwarz IT" src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/914373784?dnt=1&amp;app_id=122963" width="1200" height="675" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture; clipboard-write"></iframe>
</div></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Revolutionizing Retail Operations with IoT</h3>



<p>The Schwarz Group, known for its <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lidl" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Lidl</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kaufland" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kaufland</a> supermarket brands, operates over 13,000 stores in 32 countries. Facing the challenge of managing diverse technical equipment across its vast network, <a href="https://it.schwarz/en" data-type="link" data-id="https://it.schwarz/en">Schwarz IT</a> turned to the proven capabilities of the ThingsBoard platform. This strategic choice has been transformative, standardizing technologies and use cases across all supermarkets and ensuring customized, secure access to data for each store.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Technical Innovations and Operational Excellence</h3>



<p>At the heart of our partnership with the Schwarz Group is the innovative use of the ThingsBoard IoT platform, which excels in integrating a vast array of devices across the entire network of supermarkets. This platform addresses the challenge of connecting devices utilizing a wide variety of communication protocols, including LoRaWAN, SigFox, MQTT gateways, and more. Such versatility ensures that regardless of the specific technology used by each device, seamless integration, and data consolidation is achieved.</p>



<p>Each store enjoys secure access to its data, enhancing the operational efficiency and responsiveness of the retail environment. Moreover, the IoT portal acts as a crucial visualization layer, presenting all relevant data from the connected devices in an accessible format. This enables staff to quickly analyze and rectify faults, thereby minimizing impact and enhancing customer experience.</p>



<p>This approach not only connects over 500,000 individual devices across the Schwarz Group&#8217;s network, reducing operating costs significantly, but also provides the freedom to select the most suitable device providers and suppliers. The strategic use of the ThingsBoard platform accelerates the digitization process by streamlining the interaction between data consumers and devices, demonstrating the platform&#8217;s agility and future-proof design. It facilitates the rapid deployment of new use cases in a standardized way, simplifying maintenance throughout the lifecycle and significantly contributing to the digital transformation of the retail space.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Acknowledgment and Looking Forward<br></h3>



<p>The recognition of Schwarz IT as the &#8220;Best Enterprise Retail Solution 2024&#8221; and ThingsBoard as the &#8220;TOP SUPPLIER RETAIL 2024&#8221; by the EHI Retail Institute highlights the transformative impact of our platform on the Schwarz Group&#8217;s retail operations. This reward underscores our commitment to excellence and innovation in the retail sector.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>The partnership between Schwarz Group and ThingsBoard stands as a beacon of innovation. As we look toward the future, the Schwarz + ThingsBoard alliance continues to shape the retail landscape with unparalleled solutions and a commitment to excellence.</p>
<cite>Alex Doan, EVP at ThingsBoard </cite></blockquote>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Join Us in Shaping the Future of Retail</h3>



<p>We invite you to explore the potential of ThingsBoard in revolutionizing your retail operations. Our award-winning IoT solutions are designed to empower businesses like yours to navigate digital transformation with confidence. Discover how we can help transform your business by visiting our <a href="https://thingsboard.io/">website</a> or <a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/contact-us/">contacting</a> our sales team. Let&#8217;s innovate together and lead the way in retail technology.</p><p>The post <a href="/blog/top-supplier-retail-2024-2/">TOP SUPPLIER RETAIL 2024: ThingsBoard and Schwarz Group’s Award-Winning Partnership</a> first appeared on <a href="/blog/">Thingsboard's blog</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Warehouse monitoring with ThingsBoard</title>
		<link>/blog/warehouse-monitoring-with-thingsboard/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=warehouse-monitoring-with-thingsboard</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 12:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Solutions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/blog/?p=3188</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Reliable and high-quality control of temperature and humidity with constant access to monitoring data is an important condition for the storage of thermosensitive drugs and raw materials for medicines. The ThingsBoard partner — Vypin together with our team has implemented a solution for a global pharmaceutical company. The IoT application has helped to optimize processes and costs.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/warehouse-monitoring-with-thingsboard/">Warehouse monitoring with ThingsBoard</a> first appeared on <a href="/blog/">Thingsboard's blog</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="font-size:16px">Ensuring reliable and consistent monitoring of temperature and humidity is crucial for the proper storage of temperature-sensitive medications and perishable food products. Our partner, <a href="https://www.vypin.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Vypin</a>, has successfully deployed WhereView, a solution powered by ThingsBoard, for a leading global pharmaceutical corporation. This IoT application has significantly enhanced operational efficiency and cost-effectiveness.</p>



<div style="height:16px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="803" height="451" src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/5.webp" alt="Working conditions on the left side and device on the right side" class="wp-image-3797" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/5.webp 803w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/5-300x168.webp 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/5-768x431.webp 768w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/5-512x288.webp 512w" sizes="(max-width: 803px) 100vw, 803px" /></figure>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">The challenge</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) imposes stringent guidelines on pharmaceutical manufacturers concerning storage conditions and the regulatory compliance of control systems. The client approached Vypin with a request to overhaul their existing system, which failed to meet FDA standards, leading to penalties and the potential for product or ingredient spoilage.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">The client&#8217;s primary concerns revolved around data loss. The then-existing devices were prone to disconnections due to various issues, such as network or power failures, leading to lapses in telemetry transmission or recording. Furthermore, the system lacked a mechanism for notifying the client about these disruptions. Additionally, there was no provision for remote access to monitoring data.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p class="is-style-cs-about" style="font-size:16px">Round-the-clock rotation of operators to control the temperature and humidity in the warehouse indeed is not the best solution. Therefore, in the regular automatic reports related to the storage environment state there were gaps in the tables and graphs. The FDA fines for such violations.</p>
<cite>Customer officer says</cite></blockquote>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-left">The solution</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">In response, Vypin proposed the Vypin-WhereView system, leveraging ThingsBoard&#8217;s capabilities. The solution involved establishing a wireless network, along with the installation of sensors and gateways.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Addressing the initial concern of data loss, the newly installed sensors were equipped with memory modules to store telemetry data locally. Thus, even in the event of a gateway disconnection, data integrity was maintained. Upon restoration of the gateway&#8217;s online status, it would retrieve and transmit the stored telemetry to WhereView.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="893" height="407" src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/temp_hum_dashboard210923.webp" alt="Screen with opened dashboard and devices in front" class="wp-image-3800" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/temp_hum_dashboard210923.webp 893w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/temp_hum_dashboard210923-300x137.webp 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/temp_hum_dashboard210923-768x350.webp 768w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/temp_hum_dashboard210923-512x233.webp 512w" sizes="(max-width: 893px) 100vw, 893px" /></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">The WareView application, powered by ThingsBoard, resolved the outstanding concerns of reliable data processing and storage and enabled differentiated access levels. Designated personnel were granted comprehensive access, allowing them to monitor data from all warehouses at any time and location. In contrast, warehouse managers were provided with tailored access rights, enabling them to oversee only their specific warehouses.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="803" height="460" src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/6.webp" alt="Two windows with alarms information  and dashboard" class="wp-image-3799" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/6.webp 803w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/6-300x172.webp 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/6-768x440.webp 768w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/6-512x293.webp 512w" sizes="(max-width: 803px) 100vw, 803px" /></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">Accessing the dashboard, which displays various graphs and tables, simply requires logging into the system from a web browser.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">A noteworthy feature is the customized notification system, established through ThingsBoard&#8217;s rule engine and device profiles. This system alerts the relevant individuals in case of deviations from preset conditions, such as temperature threshold breaches. This feature facilitates immediate response and the implementation of preventive measures.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-left">The outcome</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">Prevention is universally acknowledged as more efficient, cost-effective, and less time-consuming than cure. With the newly installed warehouse monitoring system, the client now has the capability to proactively prevent issues before they arise, ensuring the safety and integrity of their sensitive products.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">This case study exemplifies the power of IoT in enhancing regulatory compliance and operational efficiency in critical industries such as pharmaceuticals. The Vypin-WhereView solution, backed by ThingsBoard, demonstrates our commitment to delivering innovative and reliable monitoring solutions.</p><p>The post <a href="/blog/warehouse-monitoring-with-thingsboard/">Warehouse monitoring with ThingsBoard</a> first appeared on <a href="/blog/">Thingsboard's blog</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Milesight and ThingsBoard announced a technical partnership to provide more integrated IoT solutions</title>
		<link>/blog/milesight-and-thingsboard-inc-announced-a-technical-partnership-to-provide-more-integrated-iot-solutions/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=milesight-and-thingsboard-inc-announced-a-technical-partnership-to-provide-more-integrated-iot-solutions</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 16:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/blog/?p=3913</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Xiamen, China, and New York, United States —&#160;Milesight, an innovative IoT products provider, and&#160;ThingsBoard, Inc., an IoT-related software&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/milesight-and-thingsboard-inc-announced-a-technical-partnership-to-provide-more-integrated-iot-solutions/">Milesight and ThingsBoard announced a technical partnership to provide more integrated IoT solutions</a> first appeared on <a href="/blog/">Thingsboard's blog</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="535" src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Milesight-1-1024x535.webp" alt="" class="wp-image-3915" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Milesight-1-1024x535.webp 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Milesight-1-300x157.webp 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Milesight-1-768x401.webp 768w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Milesight-1-1536x803.webp 1536w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Milesight-1-2048x1070.webp 2048w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Milesight-1-512x268.webp 512w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Milesight-1-920x481.webp 920w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Milesight-1-1600x836.webp 1600w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Milesight-1-1920x1003.webp 1920w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Milesight-1.webp 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Xiamen, China, and New York, United States —&nbsp;<a href="https://www.milesight.com/">Milesight</a>, an innovative IoT products provider, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thingsboard.io/">ThingsBoard</a><a href="https://www.thingsboard.io/">, Inc.</a>, an IoT-related software product vendor, particularly an open-source IoT platform provider, have announced a technical partnership. This collaboration aims to deliver highly integrated IoT solutions to customers. Both companies aim to provide comprehensive and seamless solutions for diverse IoT applications by combining their expertise and technologies.</p>



<p>Milesight, a pioneer in future-oriented IoT technologies encompassing sensing, LoRaWAN®, AI, and 5G, has established itself as a leader by introducing a wide range of cutting-edge products, including highly reliable gateways, indoor air quality sensors, occupancy and people counting sensors, water leak detectors, and many more. Through continuous innovation, Milesight reaffirms its commitment to delivering state-of-the-art products that cater to the evolving needs of the IoT landscape.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><em>As customers often come to us with a request to recommend hardware vendors, we want to provide them with reliable vendors we vouch for, like Milesight. This partnership reflects the joint dedication of both sides to provide reliable IoT solutions. We are committed to a long-term collaboration that will bring lasting benefits to our customers.</em></p>
<cite>Anrdii Shvaika,&nbsp;CEO and co-founder of ThingsBoard Inc.</cite></blockquote>



<p>ThingsBoard is an IoT platform for data collection, processing, visualization, and device management. The platform enables device connectivity via industry-standard IoT protocols or stream data from devices connected to existing IoT Platforms. The platform supports both cloud and on-premises deployments, combining scalability, fault tolerance, and performance so that the users&#8217; data remains safe.</p>



<p>In collaboration with ThingsBoard, Milesight has established seamless integration of its gateways and devices with the robust ThingsBoard IoT platform. This partnership aims to provide customers with more integrated IoT solutions that leverage the combined strengths of both companies. By combining Milesight&#8217;s innovative gateways and devices with the powerful capabilities of the ThingsBoard IoT platform, users can achieve enhanced connectivity, streamlined device management, and advanced data analytics.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><em>This partnership shows that Milesight and ThingsBoard are committed to empowering businesses with complete and dependable IoT solutions. By combining both of our technologies, we aim to spark digital transformation, boost operational efficiency, and open up new possibilities in the world of IoT applications.</em></p>
<cite>Leon Jiang, VP at Milesight</cite></blockquote>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">About&nbsp;<a href="https://thingsboard.io/">ThingsBoard</a></h4>



<p>Established in 2016, ThingsBoard, Inc. specializes in developing IoT software products under the ThingsBoard<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> umbrella. Our flagship IoT platform is the most popular open-source project in its class. ThingsBoard&#8217;s freeware and licensed software is widely utilized by IoT enthusiasts designing and prototyping smart solutions in their garages and industrial customers with diverse requirements for device management, data processing, security, privacy, analysis, etc.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">About&nbsp;<a href="https://www.milesight.com/">Milesight</a></h4>



<p>Milesight is a fast-growing high-tech company delivering smart IoT and video surveillance products with a focus on IoT technologies, including Artificial Intelligence, 5G, and LoRaWAN®, since 2011. With improved sensing capability and advanced IoT insights, we help customers worldwide optimize their business operations in a more efficient and sustainable way. In collaboration with a global network of distributors and system integrators, we are committed to building open ecosystems and accelerating IoT strategies to the next level.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Your feedback</h4>



<p>If you found this article interesting, please leave your feedback in the comments section, post questions or feature requests on the&nbsp;<strong><a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/thingsboard">forum</a></strong>&nbsp;and “star” our project on the&nbsp;<strong><a href="https://github.com/thingsboard/thingsboard">github</a></strong>&nbsp;in order to stay tuned for new releases and tutorials.</p><p>The post <a href="/blog/milesight-and-thingsboard-inc-announced-a-technical-partnership-to-provide-more-integrated-iot-solutions/">Milesight and ThingsBoard announced a technical partnership to provide more integrated IoT solutions</a> first appeared on <a href="/blog/">Thingsboard's blog</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
