<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Solutions &#8211; ThingsBoard&#039;s blog</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 17:24:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/cropped-favicon-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Solutions &#8211; ThingsBoard&#039;s blog</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Warehouse monitoring with ThingsBoard</title>
		<link>./../../../warehouse-monitoring-with-thingsboard/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../warehouse-monitoring-with-thingsboard/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Doan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 12:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Solutions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wp.thingsboard.io/?p=3188</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Reliable and high-quality control of temperature and humidity with constant access to monitoring data is an important condition for the storage of thermosensitive drugs and raw materials for medicines. The ThingsBoard partner — Vypin together with our team has implemented a solution for a global pharmaceutical company. The IoT application has helped to optimize processes and costs.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="font-size:16px">Ensuring reliable and consistent monitoring of temperature and humidity is crucial for the proper storage of temperature-sensitive medications and perishable food products. Our partner, <a href="https://www.vypin.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Vypin</a>, has successfully deployed WhereView, a solution powered by ThingsBoard, for a leading global pharmaceutical corporation. This IoT application has significantly enhanced operational efficiency and cost-effectiveness.</p>



<div style="height:16px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/5.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3225"/></figure>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">The challenge</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) imposes stringent guidelines on pharmaceutical manufacturers concerning storage conditions and the regulatory compliance of control systems. The client approached Vypin with a request to overhaul their existing system, which failed to meet FDA standards, leading to penalties and the potential for product or ingredient spoilage.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">The client&#8217;s primary concerns revolved around data loss. The then-existing devices were prone to disconnections due to various issues, such as network or power failures, leading to lapses in telemetry transmission or recording. Furthermore, the system lacked a mechanism for notifying the client about these disruptions. Additionally, there was no provision for remote access to monitoring data.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p class="is-style-cs-about" style="font-size:16px">Round-the-clock rotation of operators to control the temperature and humidity in the warehouse indeed is not the best solution. Therefore, in the regular automatic reports related to the storage environment state there were gaps in the tables and graphs. The FDA fines for such violations.</p>
<cite>Customer officer says</cite></blockquote>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-left">The solution</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">In response, Vypin proposed the Vypin-WhereView system, leveraging ThingsBoard&#8217;s capabilities. The solution involved establishing a wireless network, along with the installation of sensors and gateways.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Addressing the initial concern of data loss, the newly installed sensors were equipped with memory modules to store telemetry data locally. Thus, even in the event of a gateway disconnection, data integrity was maintained. Upon restoration of the gateway&#8217;s online status, it would retrieve and transmit the stored telemetry to WhereView.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="2409" height="1353" src="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3223" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8.png 2409w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-300x168.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-1024x575.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-768x431.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-1536x863.png 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-2048x1150.png 2048w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-512x288.png 512w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-920x517.png 920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-1600x899.png 1600w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-1920x1078.png 1920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/4-8-1320x741.png 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 2409px) 100vw, 2409px" /></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">The WareView application, powered by ThingsBoard, resolved the outstanding concerns of reliable data processing and storage and enabled differentiated access levels. Designated personnel were granted comprehensive access, allowing them to monitor data from all warehouses at any time and location. In contrast, warehouse managers were provided with tailored access rights, enabling them to oversee only their specific warehouses.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="587" src="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-1024x587.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3228" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-1024x587.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-300x172.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-768x440.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-1536x880.png 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-2048x1173.png 2048w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-512x293.png 512w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-920x527.png 920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-1600x917.png 1600w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-1920x1100.png 1920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6-1320x756.png 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/6-6.png 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">Accessing the dashboard, which displays various graphs and tables, simply requires logging into the system from a web browser.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">A noteworthy feature is the customized notification system, established through ThingsBoard&#8217;s rule engine and device profiles. This system alerts the relevant individuals in case of deviations from preset conditions, such as temperature threshold breaches. This feature facilitates immediate response and the implementation of preventive measures.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-left">The outcome</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">Prevention is universally acknowledged as more efficient, cost-effective, and less time-consuming than cure. With the newly installed warehouse monitoring system, the client now has the capability to proactively prevent issues before they arise, ensuring the safety and integrity of their sensitive products.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">This case study exemplifies the power of IoT in enhancing regulatory compliance and operational efficiency in critical industries such as pharmaceuticals. The Vypin-WhereView solution, backed by ThingsBoard, demonstrates our commitment to delivering innovative and reliable monitoring solutions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../warehouse-monitoring-with-thingsboard/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>IoT Widgets for enhanced dashboards: introducing the  action, command, toggle, and power buttons</title>
		<link>./../../../iot-widgets-for-enhanced-dashboards-introducing-the-action-command-toggle-and-power-buttons/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../iot-widgets-for-enhanced-dashboards-introducing-the-action-command-toggle-and-power-buttons/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Shvaika]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 11:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Solutions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wp.thingsboard.io/?p=2970</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to the latest update from the ThingsBoard team! Our ongoing mission to improve the platform&#8217;s functionality and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="font-size:16px">Welcome to the latest update from the ThingsBoard team! Our ongoing mission to improve the platform&#8217;s functionality and user experience brings us to the introduction of four innovative IoT widgets: the &#8220;Action button,&#8221; &#8220;Command button,&#8221; &#8220;Toggle button,&#8221; and &#8220;Power button.&#8221; Designed with a focus on usability, these new buttons are tailored for the most common IoT use cases, offering users enhanced control and flexibility in managing their IoT devices and dashboards. Let&#8217;s dive into their capabilities.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Action button widget</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">This button facilitates single-click navigation to other dashboards, states, or custom actions. You may choose one of the common <a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/user-guide/ui/widget-actions">widget actions</a> to be triggered when the user clicks the button. You may also choose whether the button is in default, activated, or disabled state. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Buttons.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3106"/></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">More importantly, the button may dynamically change its state based on the value of the attribute or time-series subscription. You may find an example of the button that changes its state when the user attribute is updated below: </p>



<div class="wp-block-file"><a id="wp-block-file--media-2b8b2412-a70d-486d-bfd5-d21e65230e9a" href="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/tb-dynamic_button_states.json">tb_dynamic_button_states.json</a><a href="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/tb-dynamic_button_states.json" class="wp-block-file__button wp-element-button" download aria-describedby="wp-block-file--media-2b8b2412-a70d-486d-bfd5-d21e65230e9a">Download</a></div>



<p style="font-size:16px">The behavior configuration is available in the basic widget settings:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Add-widget-2.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3126"/></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">The button appearance is highly customizable. You may choose one of four available layouts, configure icons, and label appearance. The colors of the buttons are configured via main and background color palettes. By default, the button uses a palette configured in the <a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/pe/user-guide/white-labeling/">white-labeling settings</a>.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Appearance-3.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3108"/></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">Although the button supports all common <a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/user-guide/ui/widget-actions">widget actions</a>, we will highlight only the most popular in this article. To demonstrate them, we have prepared the dashboard that you may <a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/user-guide/dashboards/#import-dashboard">import</a> to your platform instance.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Button-use-cases.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3109"/></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">You may find the sample dashboard JSON below: </p>



<div class="wp-block-file"><a id="wp-block-file--media-fd741ad2-e692-4a03-9a23-812a9f191991" href="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/button_use_cases.json">button_use_cases.json</a></div>



<p style="font-size:16px">The dashboard has two states: &#8220;default&#8221; and &#8220;other&#8221;. The default state contains 5 showcase buttons. The &#8220;other&#8221; state contains a line chart widget with random data. Let&#8217;s review each button below:</p>



<p style="font-size:16px"><strong>•</strong> <strong>Open dialog</strong> button uses &#8220;Navigate to new dashboard state&#8221; with the &#8220;Open in separate dialog&#8221; display option. So, the user will see the line chart opened in a modal window.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-6 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="722" height="372" data-id="3566" src="https://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Open_dialog-2.gif" alt="" class="wp-image-3566"/></figure>
</figure>



<p style="font-size:16px"><strong>•</strong> <strong>Open popup</strong> button is similar, but the &#8220;Open in popover&#8221; display option is used. You may also explore various options for the &#8220;Preferred popover placement&#8221; option. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="720" height="372" src="https://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Open_pop-up-1.gif" alt="" class="wp-image-3567" style="width:802px;height:auto"/></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px"><strong>•</strong> <strong>Change state</strong> button simply update the current dashboard state to the new one. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="722" height="372" src="https://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Change_state.gif" alt="" class="wp-image-3570"/></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px"><strong>•</strong> <strong>Drill down</strong> button is similar, but instead of changing the dashboard state, it leaves the old one in the stack. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="722" height="372" src="https://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Drill_down.gif" alt="" class="wp-image-3571"/></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px"><strong>•</strong> <strong>Open URL</strong> provides the ability to open external or relative URLs in the same or separate browser tab. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="722" height="372" src="https://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Open_url.gif" alt="" class="wp-image-3572"/></figure>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Command button widget</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">The Command button widget is designed to perform three key actions: sending <a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/user-guide/rpc/">commands</a> to devices, updating <a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/user-guide/attributes/">attributes</a>, or appending <a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/user-guide/telemetry/">time-series</a> data. </p>



<p style="font-size:16px">You can specify a single device to carry out your chosen action, such as receiving a command. For those familiar with the platform, there&#8217;s an option to use <a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/user-guide/ui/aliases/">entity aliases</a> for targeting. This means you&#8217;re not limited to devices; you can target assets, users, or other entities capable of supporting attribute updates or time-series data additions. </p>



<p style="font-size:16px">Behavior settings enable the definition of the on-click action and condition when the button is disabled. More importantly, the button may dynamically become enabled or disabled based on attribute or time-series subscription. </p>



<p style="font-size:16px"><strong>Execute RPC action</strong> allows you to send the command to the device. You may configure the command (method) name and parameters of the command. The parameter value may be configured as a constant or result of function execution. You may send the command without parameters by choosing the &#8220;None&#8221; option.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" src="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Execute-RPC-action-7.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3110"/></figure></div>


<p style="font-size:16px">By default, we use an un-persisted command with 5 seconds timeout. You may change the command parameters in the advanced settings of the action.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px"><strong>Set attribute action</strong> allows you to set or update the value of the particular entity attribute. The action configuration form allows you to configure the scope, key, and value of the attribute. The attribute value may be configured as a constant or result of function execution. Please note that only devices support &#8220;shared&#8221; attribute scope. You must choose the &#8220;server&#8221; scope for all other entities. </p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" src="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Set-attribute-action-8.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3111"/></figure></div>


<p style="font-size:16px"><strong>Add time-series action</strong> allows you to add the new time-series value for the particular entity. The action configuration form allows you to configure the time-series data key and value. The value may be configured as a constant or result of function execution. </p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" src="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Add-time-series-action-9.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3112"/></figure></div>


<p style="font-size:16px">You may dynamically disable the button based on certain values of the attribute or time-series key. For example, the dashboard attached below contains two buttons that switch the state of the user&#8217;s attribute &#8220;state&#8221;. When the user presses button A, it becomes disabled, and vice versa.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Disabled-state-10.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3113" style="width:822px;height:auto"/></figure></div>


<p style="font-size:16px">You may find the sample dashboard JSON below: </p>



<div class="wp-block-file"><a id="wp-block-file--media-8508d6eb-4fb5-4e33-b266-136f058048ae" href="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/command_buttons.json">command_buttons.json</a><a href="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/command_buttons.json" class="wp-block-file__button wp-element-button" download aria-describedby="wp-block-file--media-8508d6eb-4fb5-4e33-b266-136f058048ae">Download</a></div>



<p style="font-size:16px">Alternatively, you may disable the button that sends the command to the device, if the device is offline. For this purpose, you may just use the value of the &#8220;active&#8221; attribute or time-series key. </p>



<p style="font-size:16px">The appearance settings for the Command button are identical to those of the Action button. The primary applications of the Command button are straightforward, focusing on managing devices and assets. This involves either issuing commands or updating attributes to control their operation.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Toggle button widget</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">The Toggle button widget shares many similarities with the Command button widget, but with a crucial distinction: it features two distinct states, &#8220;checked&#8221; and &#8220;unchecked&#8221;. This design allows it to perform two specific actions, &#8220;Check&#8221; and &#8220;Uncheck&#8221;, depending on its state. Users have the flexibility to fully customize the appearance of the button for both states, enhancing its visual and functional integration into their dashboards.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Toggle-button-widget-1.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3115"/></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">The default behavior will change the state of the device using the &#8220;setState&#8221; command:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Behavior-1.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3121"/></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">You may easily change this button to operate with the &#8220;state&#8221; attribute instead of sending commands to devices:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Behavior123-1.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3122"/></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">The Toggle button shares appearance settings with the Command button but allows separate configurations for its &#8220;Checked&#8221; and &#8220;Unchecked&#8221; states:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Button-appearance-1.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3123"/></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">Adjusting the border radius, background colors, and other appearance settings can significantly alter the button&#8217;s style:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="803" height="208" src="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Buttons123.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3120" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Buttons123.png 803w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Buttons123-300x78.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Buttons123-768x199.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Buttons123-512x133.png 512w" sizes="(max-width: 803px) 100vw, 803px" /></figure>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Power button widget</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">The Power button widget, similar to the Toggle button, differs in appearance and has three states: &#8216;On&#8217;, &#8216;Off&#8217; and disabled, with six customizable layouts:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Power-button-widget.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3124"/></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">The appearance settings are simplified compared to the Command button. Basically, you are able to configure main and background colors for every state.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" src="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Button-appearance-2.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3125"/></figure></div>


<p style="font-size:16px">The Power button widget enables remote control of devices across sectors: turning smart home appliances on/off, managing industrial equipment, controlling servers, adjusting energy sources, operating irrigation systems, managing healthcare devices, retail displays, and public lighting, showcasing its versatility in simplifying power management in IoT applications.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Summary</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">In our overview of the newest widgets for the ThingsBoard IoT Platform—Action button, Command button, Toggle button, and Power button—we&#8217;ve highlighted how these tools enhance IoT dashboard interaction and device management. Each widget offers specific functionalities to improve the user experience, from executing commands to providing clear status indicators.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">We encourage you to explore these widgets&#8217; capabilities within your projects. If you have ideas for improvements or additional features, we welcome you to submit feature requests on <a href="https://github.com/thingsboard/thingsboard">GitHub</a>. For any other feedback, please leave your comments below. Your feedback is essential for us to keep improving and growing the platform.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../iot-widgets-for-enhanced-dashboards-introducing-the-action-command-toggle-and-power-buttons/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Optimizing dashboard performance with enhanced image management</title>
		<link>./../../../optimizing-dashboard-performance-with-enhanced-image-management/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../optimizing-dashboard-performance-with-enhanced-image-management/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Shvaika]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 11:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Solutions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wp.thingsboard.io/?p=2971</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At ThingsBoard, we&#8217;ve always been committed to enhancing user experience and system performance. Our latest update, version 3.6.2,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="font-size:16px">At ThingsBoard, we&#8217;ve always been committed to enhancing user experience and system performance. Our latest update, version <a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/reference/releases/#v362">3.6.2</a>, introduces significant improvements in how images are managed within dashboards, widgets, and more. This update is a key enhancement designed to tackle inefficiencies identified as our user base expanded.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">The challenge with large images</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">Since the earliest releases, our platform has permitted the embedding of images in dashboards and widgets via external links or Base64 encoded data URLs. While flexible, this approach presented a significant challenge. Users occasionally embedded images up to 50MB in size directly into dashboards. Editing or exporting these dashboards meant transferring massive JSON files to and from the server, a highly inefficient process. This not only affected loading times but also the responsiveness of the dashboard editing experience.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">The solution</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">To address this issue, we&#8217;ve introduced a major update in how images are handled within the platform. A central aspect of this update is the introduction of the <a href="https://thingsboard.io/docs/user-guide/image-gallery/">Image Gallery</a>. By moving dashboards to a separate entity and utilizing our internal, relative links for storing image references, we&#8217;ve significantly improved efficiency. This change minimizes the size of dashboard JSON files, streamlining both loading and editing processes. The Image Gallery simplifies the process of uploading, organizing, and selecting images.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1604" height="902" src="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Image-gallery.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3348" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Image-gallery.png 1604w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Image-gallery-300x169.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Image-gallery-1024x576.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Image-gallery-768x432.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Image-gallery-1536x864.png 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Image-gallery-512x288.png 512w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Image-gallery-920x517.png 920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Image-gallery-1600x900.png 1600w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Image-gallery-1320x742.png 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1604px) 100vw, 1604px" /></figure>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Backward compatibility</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">The platform&#8217;s upgrade script automatically converts all existing dashboards to the new format. Users can still upload dashboards in the old format to a new platform instance. These dashboards will automatically be converted to the new format during the upload process.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">For example, consider a “Sensors” dashboard with its background image stored in the old format:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code has-black-color has-text-color has-link-color wp-elements-240688aa6d231c0cb4116ec18afee3f6"><code lang="" class="">{
...
"backgroundImageUrl": "data:image/webp;base64,iVBORw...JRU5ErkJggg=="
...
}</code></pre>



<p style="font-size:16px">After the upgrade, a new image will be created in the image gallery:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1604" height="902" src="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Edit-image.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3345" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Edit-image.png 1604w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Edit-image-300x169.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Edit-image-1024x576.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Edit-image-768x432.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Edit-image-1536x864.png 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Edit-image-512x288.png 512w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Edit-image-920x517.png 920w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Edit-image-1600x900.png 1600w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Edit-image-1320x742.png 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1604px) 100vw, 1604px" /></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">The image name is auto-generated based on the dashboard name and the dashboard element where the image is used. This same behavior applies to images used in widget configuration: markers, backgrounds, etc. The dashboard now references the image using the following link:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code"><code lang="json" class="language-json">{
...
"backgroundImageUrl": "/api/images/tenant/sensors_dashboard_default_background.webp"
...
}</code></pre>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Private and public image links</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">Images can be provisioned at the system and tenant levels. System-level widgets are accessible to all platform users, while tenant images are available to authorized users of specific tenants.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">To embed an image into an Angular HTML template, such as the Markdown widget, HTML section in the widget editor, custom actions, etc., use the following code snippet:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code"><code class="">&lt;img [src]="'/api/images/tenant/sensors_dashboard_default_background.webp' | image | async" /&gt;</code></pre>



<p style="font-size:16px">The <code>image</code> pipe automatically adds the necessary authentication headers to the image request, allowing the same relative image URL to return different content for users from different tenants.</p>



<p style="font-size:16px">However, custom widgets or static HTML blocks that do not support Angular HTML syntax cannot add authentication headers to requests. Therefore, every platform image also has a unique URL for downloading the image without authentication. Using the following code snippet, you may embed an image into the components based on the plain HTML. Such components include HTML card widgets, cell content functions, etc.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-code"><code class="">&lt;img src="/api/images/public/ZA4biARtpnl970l0j8MMolRKM56fbpK1" alt="&amp;quot;Sensors&amp;quot; dashboard default background" /&gt;</code></pre>



<p style="font-size:16px">Each code snippet is unique to its image, and you can find the corresponding snippets in the Embed image window.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Embed-image.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3132"/></figure>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Caching</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">Our image API now utilizes ETags to optimize caching, ensuring that images are only re-downloaded when they have changed. This approach significantly saves bandwidth and improves load times. While we don&#8217;t apply Cache-Control headers by default, users have the flexibility to customize caching behavior through environment variables, including settings for image ETags cache TTL, maximum cache size, and browser cache TTL for both system and tenant images. These settings are crucial for balancing between reducing server load and ensuring content freshness.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="http://wp.thingsboard.io/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/ThingsBoard.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-3133"/></figure>



<p style="font-size:16px">The platform offers environment variables to control caching behavior:</p>



<ul>
<li style="font-size:16px">CACHE_SPECS_IMAGE_ETAGS_TTL<strong>:</strong> Controls the cache TTL for image ETags. The default is set to 44640 minutes (31 days), after which the cache is cleared.<br></li>



<li style="font-size:16px">CACHE_SPECS_IMAGE_ETAGS_MAX_SIZE<strong>:</strong> Determines the maximum ETags cache size on the server. The default is 10000. Setting this to 0 disables the cache. <br></li>



<li style="font-size:16px">CACHE_SPECS_IMAGE_SYSTEM_BROWSER_TTL and CACHE_SPECS_IMAGE_TENANT_BROWSER_TTL<strong>:</strong> These settings manage the browser cache TTL for system and tenant images, respectively, with a default of 0 minutes, meaning caching is disabled by default.</li>
</ul>



<p style="font-size:16px">These settings allow administrators to adjust the balance between performance and content freshness as needed.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Improvement Summary</h4>



<p style="font-size:16px">By tackling the challenge of image management within dashboards, we aim to offer a more efficient, robust, and user-friendly platform. Following the upgrade of <a href="https://thingsboard.cloud/">thingsboard.cloud</a>, we&#8217;ve observed an 86% reduction in the size of the dashboards, and some dashboards now load more than twice as fast.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../optimizing-dashboard-performance-with-enhanced-image-management/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
